[古典音乐]
[CLASSICAL MUSIC]
大卫·J·马兰：好的 这是CS50的S介绍
DAVID J. MALAN: All right, this is CS50's Introduction
到使用Python语言编程
to Programming with Python.
我的名字是David Malan 这是我们的面向对象编程周
My name is David Malan, and this is our week on object-oriented programming,
或者OOP
or OOP.
事实证明 在编程的世界里
It turns out that, in the world of programming,
编程语言有不同的范例
there's different paradigms of programming languages.
有不同的方法来解决代码问题
There's different ways of solving problems with code,
一开始很难看到这一点
and it's a little hard to see this at first
如果你只学过一门语言
if you've only learned one language.
但随着时间的推移 如果你学习了除Python之外的其他语言
But over time, if and when you learn other languages besides Python,
您将开始注意到某些模式和某些功能
you'll start to notice certain patterns and certain capabilities
一些语言 而不是另一种语言
of some languages but not another.
到目前为止 在Python的世界里 你和我
Thus far, within the world of Python, you and I
在很大程度上是在编写本质上是程序性的代码 因此我们
have largely been writing code that's procedural in nature, whereby we're
编写过程；我们正在编写函数；
writing procedures; we're writing functions;
我们从头到尾都在做事情
and we're doing things top to bottom.
一切都是循序渐进的 就像你会做的那样
Everything is step by step by step, as you would
一般说来 对算法的期望
expect in general from an algorithm.
但在这一过程中 我们实际上涉足了
But along the way, we've actually dabbled
在另一种称为使用Python的函数式编程的范例中 我们已经
in another paradigm known as functional programming with Python whereby we've
能够传递函数
been able to pass functions around.
几周前我们甚至有一个匿名功能
We even had an anonymous function some weeks ago.
这是函数式编程语言特点的证据
And that's evidence of features of a functional programming language,
尽管我们只是触及了它的皮毛
even though we've just scratched the surface thereof.
今天我们关注的是另一种模式 这个模式更加详细--
Today we focus on another paradigm, and this one in more detail--
即面向对象编程
namely object-oriented programming.
现在 虽然你们中的一些人可能有过编程经验
And now, while some of you might have prior programming experience
并且已经学习了像Java这样的语言 根据设计 这些语言基本上
and have learned languages like Java, which are, by design, fundamentally
面向对象的 Python确实允许您具有一定的灵活性
object-oriented, Python indeed allows you a bit of flexibility
当谈到如何用代码解决问题时
when it comes to how you solve problems with code.
但事实证明 面向对象编程
But it turns out object-oriented programming
是一个非常令人信服的问题解决方案
is a pretty compelling solution to problems
当你的程序变得更长 更大
that you invariably encounter as your programs get longer, larger,
而且更复杂
and more complicated.
因此 事实上 对于我们的目的 OOP将
So indeed, OOP, for our purposes, is going
成为一个建立在过去许多教训基础上的问题的解决方案
to be a solution to a problem that builds on so many of the lessons past.
所以让我们继续做这件事
So let's go ahead and do this.
让我们从非常程序化地编写程序开始
Let's start by writing a program very procedurally
在这里打开VS代码
by opening up VS Code here.
我将继续创建一个名为Student.py的程序
I'm going to go ahead and create a program called student.py.
在这个节目中 我想做一些相对简单的事情
And in this program, I want to do something relatively simple
最初 就像我们几周前可能做的那样 我只是
initially, as we might have done some weeks ago now, where I just
向用户询问他们的名字 也许是在《哈利波特》的上下文中
ask a user for their name and, maybe in the context of the Harry Potter
宇宙 他们的房子 然后打印出那个学生来自哪里
universe, their house, and just print out where that student is from.
让我们通过向它添加越来越多的功能来逐步增强这个程序
And let's gradually enhance this program by adding more and more features to it
看看我们是否会偶然发现一些问题 到目前为止
and see if we don't stumble upon problems that, up until now,
我们可能没有非常优雅、精心设计的解决方案来解决
we might not have had very elegant, well-designed solutions to.
但是如果我们明确地引入面向对象编程
But if we introduce, explicitly, object-oriented programming
作为一种编程技术 我打赌我们可以清理我们的代码
as a programming technique, I bet we can clean up our code
并为编写更复杂、更长的程序奠定了基础
and set the stage for writing even more sophisticated programs, longer programs
顺着路线走下去
down the line.
因此 在Student.py中 让我继续做一个名称变量
So in student.py, let me go ahead and do a name variable,
将其设置为等于输入的返回值
setting it equal to the return value of input,
只需提示用户输入他们的名字 如下所示
and just prompt the user for their name like this.
然后让我们继续对house变量执行相同的操作
And then let me go ahead and do the same for a house variable
并提示用户输入他们的房子 如下所示
and prompt the user for their house, using input like this.
现在让我们做一些非常简单的事情
And let's do something super simple now.
让我们继续打印一个f字符串
Let's just go ahead and print out an f string
上面写着房子里的名字
that says something like name from house,
这样我就可以确认这些变量的内容
just so that I can confirm that the contents of these variables
确实如我所料
are indeed as I expect.
我不会执行任何错误检查或修剪
I'm not going to do any error checking or trimming
或任何类似的东西 目前
or anything like that for now.
我真的要把用户刚输入的内容吐出来
I'm really just going to spit back out whatever the user just typed in.
好的 让我继续运行PYTHON of Student.py
All right, let me go ahead and run Python of student.py.
让我们使用我们的首选 就像《哈利·波特》中的《格兰芬多》
Let's use our go-to, like Harry, as in Harry Potter, from Gryffindor.
当我按回车键时 现在让我们看看我是否看到来自格兰芬多的哈里
And when I hit Enter, now let's see if I see that Harry from Gryffindor
确实是这样
is indeed the case.
好的 我想我们现在有一个工作计划 但让我们
All right, so I think we have a working program at this point, but let's
现在介绍一下从零周开始学到的一些经验教训
now introduce some of those lessons learned way back from week zero
在那里我们开始编写自己的函数
where we started writing our own functions,
不一定是因为它更正确地解决了问题--
not necessarily because it solves the problem more correctly--
我敢说这是正确的
I daresay this is correct as is.
但它开始为我们提供我们可以扩展的构建块
But it begins to give us building blocks that we can extend so
至于解决更复杂的程序
as to solve more complicated programs.
所以让我回到Student.py 让我们现在继续做这件事
So let me go back up to student.py, and let's go ahead now and do this.
让我们将我刚刚编写的整个逻辑放在我们的典型方法中
Let's put the entire logic I just wrote inside of our typical method
名为main 让我缩进这三行 这样至少它们是
called main, and let me indent those three lines so that at least they're
现在结合成一个主要的方法
now combined into one main method.
但是不是使用线路2上的输入与线路3上的输入
But instead of using input on line 2 an input on line 3,
我们现在是不是应该假设
don't we go ahead and assume, for the moment,
我们在世界上有一个名为get_name的函数
that we've got some function called get_name in the world,
让我们继续并假设我们有另一个类似Get_house的函数
and let's go ahead and assume we've got another function like get_house
世界上不需要参数的人
in the world that don't take parameters.
但他们的生活目标 在他们的名字里
But their purpose in life is, by their name,
将分别获得用户的名称和他们的用户的房子
going to be to get the user's name and to get their users house, respectively.
然后我将打印出和之前完全相同的f字符串
And then I'm going to print out the exact same f string as before.
当然 我现在需要实现这些功能
I, of course, need to implement these functions now.
因此 让我在文件的下面定义一个名为GET_NAME的函数
So let me go lower in my file and define a function called get_name.
这些括号里什么都没有 因为它不会接受参数
Nothing in these parentheses because it's not going to take a parameter.
我将继续做一些类似于名称等于输入的操作
And I'm going to go ahead and do something like name equals input
(“name”) 就像以前一样 然后我将继续并返回name
("Name"), just like before, and then I'm going to go ahead and return name.
所以这是一个超级简单的函数 但它是一个抽象的
So it's a super simple function, but it's an abstraction.
我现在有一个名为get_name的函数 它的实现细节
I now have a function called get_name whose implementation details
我再也不需要关心了
I don't have to care about anymore.
我只知道这个功能是存在的
I just know that the function exists.
事实上 我可以加强这一点
And I can tighten this up, in fact, .
在第8行中并不真正需要名称变量
Don't really need a name variable on line 8
如果我要立即在第9行返回相同名称的变量
if I'm immediately going to return that same name variable on line 9.
所以让我把这个绷紧一点
So let me just tighten this up a little bit
即使它不会改变功能
even though it doesn't change the functionality
并且只需立即返回此处INPUTS函数调用的返回值
and just immediately return the return value of the inputs function call here.
现在让我们为Get_house做一些非常类似的事情
Let's do something very similar now for get_house,
同样 这也不会有任何争论
which will similarly take no arguments.
我要继续并退回退款
I'm going to go ahead and return the return
输入值 这一次提示用户选择他们的房子
value of input, this time prompting the user for their house.
我还需要最后一个细节
And I need one final detail.
在最下面 让我们继续我们的习惯 如果此文件的名称
At the very bottom, let's continue our habit of doing if the name of this file
等于 等于 引号 不引号 主键 然后让我们继续
equals, equals, quote, unquote, main, then let's go ahead
然后实际呼叫Main并回想一下我们已经准备好了
and actually call main and recall that we have that in place
所以 如果这最终成为一个模块的一部分 一个各种各样的库
so that, if this eventually becomes part of a module, a library of sorts,
我不会不小心盲目地给Main打电话
I don't accidentally call main blindly.
只有当我打算从该文件的命令行运行main时 我才会这样做
I only do it if I mean to run main from the command line on this file.
好的 如果我没有犯任何错误 让我继续
All right, so if I didn't make any mistakes here, let me go ahead
然后 在我的终端窗口中 再次运行Student.py的Python 输入
and, in my terminal window, again, run Python of student.py, Enter.
让我们输入哈里 回车
Let's type in Harry, Enter.
让我们输入格兰芬多 回车
Let's type in Gryffindor, Enter.
我们已经准备好了
And we're set.
来自格兰芬多的哈里似乎还在工作
Harry from Gryffindor seems to still be working.
所以我们并没有真正正确地解决这个问题
So we haven't really solved the problem any more correctly,
但我已经奠定了基础 也许现在就可以
but I've laid the foundation to maybe now do
一些更有趣的事情 因为我已经
some more interesting things because I've
把这些积木放在适当的位置
had these building blocks in place.
但让我提议 我们可以用一点不同的方式来做这件事
But let me propose that we could be doing this a little bit differently.
GET_NAME GET_HOUSE很好
get_name, get_house is fine.
但归根结底 我真的是想从用户那里得到一个学生
But at the end of the day, I'm really trying to get a student from the user.
我要他们的名字和他们的房子 而不只是其中之一
I want their name and their house, not just one or the other.
所以也许它会更干净一点
So maybe it would be a little cleaner still
定义一个名为Get_Student的函数并让
to define a function called get_student and let
Get_Student为我们做所有这些工作
get_student do all of this work for us.
现在 理论上 get学生可以调用get_name 也可以调用get_house
Now, theoretically, get_student could call get_name and could call get_house.
但由于这些函数太短了
But because these functions are so short,
我想我可以只定义一个名为Get_Student的函数
I think I'm OK with just defining one function, called get_student,
同样 这也不需要任何论据
that similarly won't take any arguments.
但它会做两件事
But it's going to do two things.
它将通过像以前一样提示他们输入 来获得学生的名字
It's going to get the students name, by prompting them with input as before.
它会夺走学生的房子
And it's going to get the student's house,
通过也像以前一样提示他们
by also prompting them as before.
现在 嗯
Now, hmm.
我想把学生还回去 但我觉得
I want to return the student, but I think
我可能把自己逼到了墙角
I might have painted myself into a corner
因为我现在有两个变量--name和house
here because I now have two variables-- name and house.
然而 到目前为止 我们基本上只退还了其中的一种
And yet, up until now, we've pretty much returned one or the other.
我们返回了一个值
We've returned one value.
所以有没有什么建议可以让我们
So any suggestions for how we can perhaps
解决我刚刚为自己创造的这个问题 借此我想返回
solve this problem that I just created for myself, whereby I want to return,
真的 我是个学生 但我现在有一个名字变量和一个房子变量
really, a student, but I currently have a name variable and a house variable.
我至少想把这两件都退货
I'd minimally like to return both of those.
听众：我相信 我们可以归还一本词典
AUDIENCE: I believe that, we can return a dictionary,
包括名字和房子
includes the name and the house.
大卫·J·马兰：是的 所以我们绝对可以
DAVID J. MALAN: Yeah, so we absolutely could
返回一个字典--Python中的Dict对象 其中可能有一个键是name；
return a dictionary-- a dict object in Python, whereby maybe one key is name;
一把钥匙是房子 它的价值恰好是
one key is house; and the values thereof are exactly
这些变量的值
the values of these variables.
所以我们完全可以这么做
So we could totally do that.
我担心这可能会变得有点复杂
I worry that that might be getting a little complicated.
我想知道有没有更简单的方法来代替
I wonder if there's a simpler way instead.
还有其他本能吗--即使你不确定它会奏效吗？
Any other instincts-- even if you're not sure it would work?
观众：名字和房子都要还吗？
AUDIENCE: Return both name and house?
大卫·J·马兰：把名字和房子都还回来
DAVID J. MALAN: Return both name and house.
我喜欢听你这么说
I like the sound of that.
这听起来很简单
It sounds simple.
我不需要考虑字典会是什么样子的
I don't have to figure out what a dictionary is going to look like.
事实上 这也是一种有效的方法
And in fact, this, too, would be a valid approach,
即使你以前没见过这个
even if you've not seen this before.
事实证明 在Python中 您可以返回多个值
It turns out, in Python, that you can return multiple values,
但这是一个善意的谎言
but that's a bit of a white lie.
或者我们可以采用穆罕默德的方法 实际上归还一本词典
Or we could take Muhammad's approach of actually returning a dictionary
并在其中放置多个钥匙
and putting multiple keys therein.
所以在这里 我们又有了另一个例子
So here, again, we have yet another example
你如何至少用两种方式解决同样的问题
of how you can solve the same problem in at least two ways,
我敢说 我们即将看到更多
and I daresay we're about to see even more.
因此 解决这个问题的一种方法是
So one way you could solve this problem, whereby
如果想要返回多个值 可以这样做
you want to return multiple values, would be to do something like this.
我可以按字面意思返回 不只是名字 还可以加一个逗号
I could go ahead and literally return not just name, but I could put a comma
也要把房子还回去
and also return house.
这不一定是您可以在其他语言中完成的操作
This is not necessarily something you can do in other languages
如果您以前用过其他语言编程
if you have programmed in other languages before.
这取决于语言
It depends on the language.
但看起来 多亏了这个逗号 也许我可以 实际上
But it looks like, thanks to this comma, maybe I can, in fact,
返回[INAUDIBLE]建议的两个值
return two values as [INAUDIBLE] proposed.
好 如果我用这种方式返回第10行的值
Well, if I'm returning to values in this way on line 10,
如何同时获得这两个值？
how do I get both values at the same time?
好吧 有几种方法
Well, there's a couple of ways.
让我继续我的主要任务
Let me go up to my main function.
我知道 至少 我将不得不更改get_name
I know, minimally, I'm going to have to change the get_name
找一间房子去找一名学生
and get_house to get_student.
但是我要把返回值存储在什么地方呢？
But what am I going to store the return value in?
我想我真的能做到
I think I could actually do this.
我们以前见过这种技术 你可以打开行李
And we have seen this technique before, where you can unpack,
可以说 一系列的价值正在回归
so to speak, sequences of values that are coming back.
事实上 你可以认为这就是事实 名字,
And indeed, consider this to be exactly that. name,
房子是我要返回的某种值序列--名字 房子
house is some kind of sequence that I'm returning of values-- name, house.
因此 如果我想打开这些文件并存储退货
So if I want to unpack those and store the return
在两个独立变量中的值 我可以 事实上
values in two separate variables, I can, in fact,
使用赋值运算符左侧的逗号、等号、
use the commas on the left-hand side of my assignment operator, the equal sign,
正是为了做到这一点
to do just that.
现在 为了清楚起见 我不需要在这里将这些变量称为name和house
Now, to be clear, I don't need to call these variables name and house here.
我可以简化这个 在这里只用n 在这里用h
I could simplify this and use just n here and h here,
然后我可以只返回n和h
and then I could return just n and h.
但我认为这对读者来说并不是很清楚到底发生了什么
But I would argue that's not very clear to the reader as to what's going on.
所以我认为 在这种情况下 即使它是
So I think, in this case, even though it's
巧合的是 我在Get_Student中使用了相同的变量名
a coincidence that I've used the same variable names in get_student
和get_name 在Main中 对于像我这样的人来说 它更具可读性
and get_name, and in main, it's a little more readable to someone like me.
所以我会让它保持原样
So I'm going to leave it as is.
好吧 让我们来看看 现在 这个方法是否奏效
Well, let's go ahead and see, now, if this works.
让我清空下面的屏幕 然后运行Student.py的Python 回车
Let me clear my screen down here and run Python of student.py, Enter.
让我们再输入一次哈里
Let's again type in Harry.
让我们再次输入Gryffindor 回车
Let's again type in Gryffindor, Enter.
瞧 我们仍然看到哈里来自格兰芬多
And voila, we still see that Harry is from Gryffindor.
但我们到底在这里做什么呢？
But what are we actually doing here?
我们返回这个值实际上是在做什么？
What are we actually doing by returning this value?
事实证明 我们刚才所做的是使用元组
Well, it turns out that what we've just done is use a tuple.
元组是Python中的另一种数据类型 它是值的集合--
A tuple is another type of data in Python that's a collection of values--
X y或x y z
x, y or x, y, z.
从这个意义上说 它在精神上类似于列表 但它是一成不变的
It's similar in spirit to a list, in that sense, but it's immutable.
它不是可变的
It's not mutable.
那么 这意味着什么呢？
Now, what does that mean?
正如我们以前看到的 列表是Python中的一种数据结构
A list, as we've seen it before, is a data structure in Python
您可以更改的值
that you can change the values of.
您可以进入第一个位置的括号0 并在那里更改值
You can go into bracket 0 for the first location and change the value there.
您可以转到括号1、括号2、括号3 然后实际更改
You can go to bracket 1, bracket 2, bracket 3 and actually change
列表中的值
the values in lists.
但如果您不想更改变量的值
But if you have no intention of changing the values of variables
你想要有效地返回多个值
and you want to return, effectively, multiple values,
您甚至不需要将其作为列表返回
you don't have to even return it as a list.
您可以将其作为元组返回 只需使用逗号
You can return it as a tuple instead, just by using a comma.
事实证明 我们可以清楚地表明--这是一个善意的谎言
And it turns out we can make explicit that-- here's the white lie.
实际上 我并不是要回到价值观本身
I'm not actually returning to values per se.
每当您在第9行使用逗号时
Whenever you use a comma in this way on line 9,
您实际上返回了一个值 这是一个元组
you're actually returning one value, which is a tuple.
现在 该元组内部有两个值
Inside of that tuple now are two values.
所以这在本质上类似于在这里返回一个列表和两个东西
So it's similar in spirit to returning one list with two thing Here
我要返回一个包含两个元素的元组
I'm returning one tuple with two things.
事实是我只用了逗号 没有用其他
And the mere fact that I've used a comma and nothing else
告诉Python我确实想返回一个元组
tells Python that I indeed want to return a tuple.
但是 我们可以使用更显式的语法
But there's more explicit syntax that we can use instead.
我实际上可以--更详细地--用显式的圆括号将值括起来
I can actually-- more verbosely-- put explicit parentheses around the values
为了让我和读者更清楚地了解这个元组
of this tuple just to make more clear to me, to the reader
这本身并不是两种价值
that this isn't two values per se.
这是一个价值 里面有两个东西
This is one value with two things inside of it.
而我实际上能做的也是--
And what I can actually do then, too, is--
可以这么说 我不需要在这里解开这些东西
I don't have to unpack this up here, so to speak.
我可以在这里取个更贴切的名字 比如学生
I can actually go up here and maybe give a more apt name, like student,
我可以给值命名 或者说给变量命名
and I can name the value, or rather name the variable
其中我将get_student的返回值存储为
in which I'm storing the return value of get_student as,
“学生 “
quote, unquote, "student."
所以也许这是一个更好的设计
So maybe this is a little better design now
因为我在抽象学生是什么
because I'm sort of abstracting away what a student is.
它目前被实现为具有两个值的元组
It's implemented at the moment as a tuple with two values.
但至少 现在我有了一个变量 叫做学生
But at least, now I have a variable called what I mean, a student.
但会有一个陷阱
But there's going to be a catch.
在第3行 我仍然想打印出那个学生的名字和他们的房子
On line 3, I still want to print out that student's name and their house.
但是我没有名字变量了 我也没有房子了
But I don't have a name variable anymore, and I don't have a house.
我也没有字典 就像之前说的 所以我甚至不能
And I also don't have a dictionary, as was proposed earlier, so I can't even
按名字去拿钥匙
go at those keys by name.
但元组是什么--它在本质上与列表非常相似
But what a tuple is-- it's very similar in spirit to a list,
但它确实是不可变的
but it is indeed just immutable.
我的意思是我仍然可以索引到它
And what I mean by that is I can still index into it
用数字表示学生[0]
numerically by saying student [0] for the item
在元组的第一个位置
in the first location in that tuple.
然后在这里 我可以说学生 而不是房子
And then over here, instead of house, I can say student [1].
student [1]将给出元组中的第二个位置
student [1] is going to give me the second location in that tuple.
我先去清空终端窗口
Let me go ahead and clear my terminal window.
再次运行student.py的Python
Again, run Python of student.py.
让我们输入哈里
Let's type in Harry.
让我们输入格兰芬多 回车 我们还有一些工作代码
Let's type in Gryffindor, Enter, and we still have some working code.
让我在这里暂停一下 看看是否有
Let me pause here now and see if there are
关于返回元组的技术
any questions on this technique of returning a tuple
并以这种方式索引它
and indexing into it in this way.
观众：我想 什么是一个实际的用例
AUDIENCE: I guess, what's an actual use case where
你会使用元组还是列表或者其他类似的东西？
you would use a tuple versus a list or something else that's similar?
大卫·J·马兰：这是一个很好的问题
DAVID J. MALAN: It's a really good question.
什么时候使用元组而不是列表？
When would you use a tuple versus a list?
当你想进行防御性编程时 或者 一般来说
When you want to program defensively, or, in general,
当你知道这个变量中的值不应该改变时
when you know that the values in this variable shouldn't change,
那么 为什么要使用允许它们被更改的数据类型呢？
so why would you use a data type that allows them to be changed?
它只会招致错误 臭虫 要么
It just invites mistakes, bugs down the line, either
由您或与您的代码交互的同事创建
by you or colleagues who are interacting with your code.
因此 元组只是另一种您可以增加
So tuple is just another way where you can increase
不让任何人 包括你自己
the probability of correctness by just not letting anyone, yourself included,
更改其中的内容
change the contents therein.
所以它只是您工具箱中的另一个工具
So it's just another tool in your toolkit.
但是 让我们明确一下我所说的“不变”是什么意思
But let's make clear, then, what I mean by "immutable."
同样 我声称“不可变”意味着您不能更改该值
Again, I claim that "immutable" means that you cannot change the value.
好吧 让我们继续试着这样做
Well, let's go ahead and try to do this.
让我继续按原样运行这个程序--
Let me go ahead and run this program once more as is--
Student.py的蟒蛇
Python of student.py.
例如 让我继续输入--
Let me go ahead and type in, for instance--
帕德玛的名字呢？
how about Padma's name?
我要说的是 帕德玛
And I'm going to go ahead and say that Padma
是在格兰芬多 就像电影里一样
is in Gryffindor as in the movies.
我们看到了--格兰芬多的帕德玛
And we see-- Padma from Gryffindor.
但严格来说 我走进这个兔子洞是为了看哈利波特
But technically, I went down this rabbit hole in looking at Harry Potter
离得更近
more closely.
严格来说 在书中 我相信帕德玛来自拉文克劳
Technically, in the books, Padma, I believe, was from Ravenclaw.
因此 这实际上是一个错误或不一致
So this is actually a mistake or an inconsistency
在电影和书之间
between the movies and the books.
让我们看看我们是否不能修复代码中的这种不一致
Let's see if we can't fix this inconsistency in our code.
那我们来做这个怎么样？
So how about we do this?
如果输入的学生姓名等于帕德玛
If the student's name that's inputted equals Padma,
我们为什么不不管这房子是什么
why don't we override whatever the house is
把它改成真正的格兰芬多
and change it to be properly Gryffindor.
让我继续做 如果学生--
Let me go ahead and do if student--
现在 如果我想得到帕德玛的名字 我将不得不做学生[0]
now, if I want to get at Padma's name, I'm going to have to do student [0].
我必须知道这个名字在这个元组中的位置
I have to know what location the name is in in this tuple.
但是 如果该值等于Padma 那么让我们继续执行这条if语句
But if that value equals equals Padma, let's go ahead with this if statement
并做出改变
and make a change.
让我们更改学生的[1]值
Let's change the student's [1] value.
所以第二个值 如果我们是零索引--
So the second value, if we're zero indexing--
让我们把它变成哈利波特世界里的另一座房子
let's change it to be another house in the world of Harry Potter
叫拉文克劳
called Ravenclaw.
所以我只是在修复可能是用户的输入
So I'm just fixing maybe the user's input.
他们看了这部电影 然后输入帕德玛·格兰芬多
They watched the movie so they type in Padma Gryffindor,
但是 嗯 在书里 是拉文克劳的帕德玛
but, mm-mm, in the books, it was Padma from Ravenclaw.
好了 让我继续下去 到我的终端窗口
All right, let me go ahead and go down to my terminal window,
清除我的终端 然后执行Student.py的Python 回车
clear my terminal, and do Python of student.py, Enter.
我会像格兰芬多一样模仿哈里 只是为了证明
I'm going to do Harry as well as Gryffindor, just to demonstrate
这一点仍在发挥预期的作用
that that is still working as intended.
不过 让我再次清除屏幕 并在Padma上运行PYSTONT.PY
Let me clear my screen again, though, and run Python of student.py on Padma,
我也会把她放进格兰芬多 就像电影里的那样 然后按Enter键
and I'll put her, too, in Gryffindor, as in the movies, and hit Enter.
现在我只在屏幕上看到一大堆错误
And now I just see a big mess of errors on the screen.
已经抛出了某种例外
Some kind of exception has been thrown.
事实上 确实发生了一个类型错误
And indeed, a type error has happened.
我使用的数据类型中存在错误 错误是什么？
I'm using a data type wherein there's an error, and what is that error?
嗯 “tuple”对象不支持项赋值
Well, 'tuple' object does not support item assignment.
它有点神秘莫测--也就是说 它对用户并不是很友好
It's a little arcanely expressed-- that is, it's not really very user friendly.
但如果你想一想这些话的意思
But if you think about what those words mean,
“tuple”对象不支持项分配
'tuple" object does not support item assignment.
所以作业是从右到左复制的
So assignment is copying from right to left.
因此 不知何故 这是无效的
So somehow, that's invalid.
这是元组的不变性的一个表现
And here is a manifestation of the immutability of tuples.
您不能更改位置0或1或内部的任何内容
You cannot change location 0 or 1 or anything inside.
这是一个特点
That is a feature.
这就是元组的设计
That is the design of a tuple.
所以如果我想推翻这一点 我想我是
So if I want to override that, I think I'm
我们将不得不使用我们以前使用过的不同类型的数据--
going to have to use a different type of data that we've used before--
也就是一份清单 这很好
namely a list, and that's fine.
如果您想让您自己和同事能够使用您的代码
If you want to enable yourself and colleagues using your code
要更改该容器中的内容物
to change the contents of that container,
好的 我们可以继续使用返回不是元组
well, we can go ahead and return not a tuple using
明确的圆括号或没有圆括号 只有逗号
explicit parentheses or no parentheses, just the comma,
但我可以使用方括号
but I can use square brackets.
如果我在左边和右边用方括号
And if I'm using square brackets on the left and the right,
这确实是一份明确的清单
this is indeed explicitly a list.
想法相同 但它是可变的
Same idea, but it's mutable.
也就是说 您可以更改列表的内容
That is to say you can change the contents of a list.
所以不做其他更改 只返回一个列表
So making no other changes, just returning a list
使用方括号 而不是使用圆括号或仅使用逗号的元组
with square brackets instead of a tuple with parentheses or just the comma.
现在让我继续运行PYTHON of Student.py Enter
Let me go ahead now and run Python of student.py, Enter.
让我再输入一次哈利和格兰芬多
Let me type in Harry and Gryffindor again.
这还在起作用
That's still working.
很高兴见到你
Good to see.
让我再运行一次 输入帕德玛和格兰芬多 就像电影里那样
Let me run this once more and type in Padma and Gryffindor, as in the movies,
但现在我们更正为拉文克劳的帕德玛
but no, now we've corrected it to be Padma from Ravenclaw,
就像书上写的那样
as in the books instead.
关于元组和列表或者这个想法还有什么问题吗
Any questions now on tuples versus lists or this idea
不变性与可变性的对比
of immutability versus mutability.
观众：我们可以在Python中使用嵌套元组吗 比如嵌套列表？
AUDIENCE: Can we use a nested tuple in Python, like a nest list?
大卫·J·马兰：当然
DAVID J. MALAN: Absolutely.
Python中不仅可以有嵌套列表
You can have not only nested lists in Python,
其中一个列表中的元素可以是另一个列表
where one of the elements in a list could be another list-- so you
这里有一些方括号 你可能会有一些其他的方括号
have some square brackets out here; you might have some other square brackets
里面
inside.
你完全可以用一个元组做同样的事情
You can absolutely do the same with a tuple as well.
对于可以放入的值的类型没有限制
There is no constraint on the types of values you can put in there.
我们在这件事上还没有这样做的机会
We've not had occasion to do that in this case.
我只是返回一个包含两个元素的简单元组
I'm just returning a simple tuple with two elements.
但是 是的 你绝对可以这样做 太
But yes, you could absolutely do that, too.
关于元组和列表的其他问题？
Other questions on tuples versus lists?
观众：好的 举个例子 当我看到方括号时
AUDIENCE: OK, for example, when I see the square brackets,
主要用于名单？
is it mainly used for the list?
大卫·J·马兰：哦 一个很好的问题
DAVID J. MALAN: Oh, a really good question.
算是吧
Sort of.
所以当你创建一个像列表这样的值时 你要用方括号
So when you create a value like a list, you use square brackets,
这确实是一个视觉指示器
and that would indeed be a visual indicator
这绝对是一份名单
that this is definitely a list.
如果你看到的是圆括号 那是一个视觉指示器
If you instead see parentheses, that's a visual indicator,
当创建一个值时 它肯定是一个元组
when creating a value, that it's definitely a tuple.
然而 有点令人困惑的是 列表和元组都
However, somewhat confusingly, both lists and tuples
在访问它们的内容时使用方括号
use square brackets when you access the contents of them.
当你在位置0或位置1索引它们时
When you index into them at location 0 or location 1
你总是用方括号
you always use square brackets.
这就是区别
So that's the distinction there.
问得好
Good question.
如果可以的话 请允许我提议 我们用另一种方式解决这个问题
Allow me to propose now, if I may, that we solve this problem yet another way,
看看我们是在让事情变得更好还是更糟
and let's see if we're either making things better or for worse than us.
回想一下 字典或dict对象也存在于Python中
Recall that dictionaries, or dict objects, also exist in Python.
字典就是键和值的集合
And a dictionary is this collection of keys and values.
尤其是字典的好处是
And the upside, in particular, of a dictionary
就是它们有更好的语义
is that they have better semantics.
你不需要假设一个名字总是
You don't just have to assume that a name is always
将位于位置0；房屋将始终位于位置1
going to be at location 0; house is always going to be at location 1.
这就是那种事情 特别是如果你有三个、四个或更多的价值观--
That's the kind of thing, especially if you had three, four, or more values--
最终 你或某人将会迷惑并忘记
eventually you or someone is going to get confused and forget
命令是什么 您将编写有错误的代码
what the order is and you're going to write buggy code.
所以词典的功能更强大一点
So a dictionary is a little more powerful
因为您可以在语义上关联关键字、小描述
in that you can semantically associate keys, little descriptions,
有了这些价值观--
with the values--
分别是那些键和那些值
those keys and those values, respectively.
所以让我继续这样做 我们可以用几种不同的方式来做这件事
So let me go ahead and do this, and we can do this in a few different ways.
但让我建议我们在这里重点关注Get_Student
But let me propose that we focus on get_student here .
让我们继续做这件事
And let's go ahead and do this.
让我们继续 按原样删除Get_Student的实现
Let me go ahead and delete the implementation of get_student as is.
让我创建一个学生变量 并将其初始化为空词典
Let me create a student variable and initialize it to an empty dictionary.
我只需要两个花括号就可以做到这一点
And I can do that with just two curly braces here.
然后让我继续 在词典中设置两个键
And then let me go ahead and set two keys inside of that dictionary.
在学生体内 将会有一个“名字”
Inside of the student, there will be, quote unquote, a "name"
键 它的值将是输入的返回值
key, and the value of that is going to be whatever the return value of input
是当我提示用户输入他们的名字时
is when I prompt the user for their name.
然后是同一本学生词典里的“房子”钥匙
And then the "house" key, inside of that same student dictionary,
将是用户键入的任何内容的返回值
is going to be the return value of whatever the user types
为他们的房子买单  最后 我要继续下去 把学生送回来
in for their house. , And lastly I'm going to go ahead and return student.
所以现在我还是要退回一样东西
So now I am literally returning one thing, still,
但这一次 它是一个词典而不是一个元组 而不是一个列表
but this time, it's a dict rather than a tuple, rather than a list.
但这里面还是有两样东西 严格来说有四样东西
But there are still two things in it, technically four things
如果你计算一下键和值
if you count the keys and the values.
但是有两个键值对
But there's two key value pairs.
现在 我这里的代码将不得不稍作更改
Now, my code up here is going to have to change a little bit.
让我们简化这一点 例如 现在删除
And let's simplify this and remove, for instance, now
Padma IF声明只是为了关注手头正在发生的变化
the Padma if statement just to focus on what's changing at hand.
现在让我继续 让2号线单独运行
And let me go ahead now and leave line 2 alone.
我仍然会有一个学生变量 该变量被赋值为返回
I'm still going to have a student variable that gets assigned the return
Get_Student的值
value of get_student.
但我现在想要做的是实际访问其中的密钥
But what I want to do here now is actually access the keys inside of that
字典--不是按元组和列表的数字索引--
dictionary-- not by numeric index, which was for tuples and lists--
0和1 但通过密钥的方式
0 and 1, but by way of the keys.
现在 正常情况下 我可能有这个习惯 因为我个人
Now, normally, I might be in the habit, as I personally
AM 使用双引号--引号 不引号 “名字”在里面
am, of using double quotes-- quote, unquote, "name" inside of there
引用 引述 “房子”在里面
and quote, unquote, "house" inside of there.
但在我运行这段代码并向你们展示一个错误之前--
But before I even run this code and show you a mistake--
看到屏幕上的错误 有谁想喊出来吗
see an error on the screen, does anyone want to call out
我在这里做错了什么？
what I have done wrong here?
这只是一根f弦
This is just an f string.
我只想打印出名字键的值 房子的价值
I just want to print out the value of the name key, the value of the house
输入这本词典
key in this dictionary.
观众：[听不见]
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
大卫·J·马兰：你的音频对我们来说有点乱码
DAVID J. MALAN: Your audio was a little garbled for us.
但我想我听到了双引号和单引号
But I think I heard double quotes and single quotes.
所以我假设 确实 你已经准确地确定了问题所在
So I'm going to assume that, indeed, you've identified precisely the issue.
我现在只是要混淆一下Python
I'm just going to confuse Python right now.
即使这是双引号内的f字符串 以f为前缀
Even though this is an f string inside of double quotes, prefixed with an f,
我不能在我的双引号中使用双引号
I can't actually use my double quotes inside my double quotes
因为这可能会让Python感到困惑
because that's going to potentially confuse Python.
如果我现在运行这个程序 那么Student.py的Python和点击
If I run this program now, Python of student.py and hit
回车 我得到一个语法错误
Enter, I get a syntax error.
因此 该程序甚至没有完全运行
So the program didn't even run fully.
它只是无法理解 因为它被那些双引号搞糊涂了
It just couldn't be understood because it got confused by those double quotes.
所以这里最简单的解决办法就是
So the simplest fix here would indeed just
不是用双引号而是用单引号将键引起来
be to use not double quotes but single quotes around the keys,
或者相反 将外部的双引号改为单引号
or conversely, flip the double quotes on the outside to single quotes,
然后在内部使用双引号
then use double quotes in the inside.
你只想保持一致
You just want to be consistent.
这是一个微妙的细节 但同样 这是特定于词典语法的
So a subtle detail, but again, this is now specific to dictionary syntax.
这并不是我们如何解决当前问题的根本
This isn't fundamental to how we're solving this current problem at hand.
好吧 让我们来试试这个
Well, let's go ahead and try this.
现在让我继续运行Student.py的Python
Let me go ahead now and run Python of student.py.
让我们继续输入哈里
Let's go ahead and type in Harry.
让我们输入格兰芬多
Let's type in Gryffindor.
希望哈里能从格兰芬多回来
And hopefully, Harry is back from Gryffindor.
没有语法错误
No syntax errors.
没有其他错误
No other errors.
我想我又回来做生意了
I think I'm back in business here.
关于使用词典 我想明确的是
And what I do like to be clear about using a dictionary
它让我获得了更好的语义
is that it's allowing me just better semantics.
再说一次 我不需要记住 记住 文件 0是名字；
And again, I don't have to remember, memorize, document that 0 is name;
1是House
1 is house.
相反 “name”是名字 “house”是house
Instead, "name" is name and "house" is house.
它只是更清晰一点 更有表现力一点
It's just a little clearer, a little more expressive.
因此 这通常是一件好事 特别是如果我们存储了更多关于
So that's generally a good thing, especially if we stored more data about
学生不仅仅是他们的名字和他们的房子--如果你有三个领域 四个
students than just their name and their house-- if you had three fields, four,
五到十个不同的领域--
five, 10 different fields--
没有人会想要记住或能够永远记住这是零
no one's going to want to remember or be able to remember forever which is zero
这是1 这是2 以此类推
which is 1, which is 2, and so forth.
最好引入名字 比如本例中的“name”和“house”
Better to introduce names, like "name" and "house" in this case.
但让我进一步收紧这一点
But let me tighten this up further.
我通常习惯于不引入不必要的变量
I'm typically in the habit of not introducing variables unnecessarily,
除非它们使代码更具可读性
unless they make the code more readable.
格式化相同代码的另一种方法是这样
And an alternative way to format the same code would be this.
严格地说 我不需要创建一本空词典
Strictly speaking, I don't need to create an empty dictionary,
然后给它添加一个密钥 然后给它添加第二个密钥
then add one key to it, then add a second key to it,
然后把那本词典还给我
and then return that dictionary.
如果你愿意的话 我可以把这一切归结为一份声明
I can actually consolidate this all into one statement, if you will.
让我继续做这件事
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续说 名称等于输入返回值
Let me go ahead and say name equals inputs return value,
House等于输入返回值 然后
house equals inputs return value, and then,
而不是返回任何变量名学生 这是我要建议的
instead of returning any variable name student, which I'm going to propose
不需要再存在了 让我来创造
doesn't need to exist anymore, let me just create
然后一次把词典全部归还
and return the dictionary all at once.
让我这样做 引用 不引用 这里用小写的“name” 然后是变量
Let me do, quote, unquote, "name" in lowercase here, and then the variable.
它存储用户的姓名
It's storing the user's name.
然后 引用 不引用 “house”作为我的第二个密钥 它的价值
Then, quote, unquote, "house," as my second key, the value of which
将会是House 这个变量
is going to be house, the variable.
现在 这是不是更好了？
Now, is this better?
可能会 也可能不会
Maybe, maybe not.
也许第一种方法更具可读性
Maybe the first way was a little more readable,
这完全可以用来制造变量
and that's totally fine to create variables
如果它们提高了代码的可读性
if they improve the readability of your code.
但要知道 您还可以即时创建和返回词典
But just know that you can also create and return a dictionary on the fly
像这样 可以说 都在一行里 而我
like this, so to speak, all in one line, and I
我认为在这种情况下 这是相当合理的
think it's arguably pretty reasonable in this case.
为什么？
Why?
就是太短了
It's just pretty short.
如果它变得越来越长 我可能不会这么做
I probably wouldn't do this if it got longer and longer and longer.
然后 我至少可以开始将我的键值对移动到不同的行
I might minimally then start moving my key value pairs to separate lines.
但这也只是一种稍微更紧凑的方式
But this would just be a slightly more compact way of doing this as well.
但让我提议我们再做一次改变
But let me propose we do one more change.
让我们继续介绍Padma相同特殊外壳
Let's go ahead and introduce that same special casing of Padma
例如 为了修缮她从格兰芬多到拉文克劳的房子
to fix her house from Gryffindor, for instance, to Ravenclaw.
我们如何用词典做到这一点呢？
How do we do this with dictionaries?
词典和列表一样 都是可变的
Well, dictionaries, like lists, are mutable.
您可以更改它们中的内容 就像您可以列出列表一样
You can change what is in them, just like you can lists.
你怎么做到的？
How do you do that?
只是在句法上有一点不同
It's just a little different syntactically.
因此 让我们返回到Main并进行此修复
So let's go back into main and do this fix.
如果学生变量有一个等于Padma的名称键 那么
If the student variable has a name key that equals equals Padma, then,
缩进 继续并更改该学生体内的房屋钥匙的值
indented, go ahead and change the value of the house key inside of that student
词典改为 引用 不引用 取而代之的是“RavenClaw”
dictionary to be, quote, unquote, "Ravenclaw" instead.
在精神上与我们用清单做的事情非常相似
So very similar in spirit to what we did with a list.
但我们没有使用位置0和1 而是更清楚、更明确地说
But instead of using location 0 and 1, we're much more clearly, explicitly,
语义上使用 引号 不引号 “名字”和 引号 不引号
semantically using, quote, unquote, "name" and, quote, unquote,
“house” 因为您使用数字来索引列表和元组 但您是在索引
"house," because you index into lists and tuples using numbers, but you index
变成使用字符串的词典 就像我在这里所做的那样
into dictionaries using strings, as I've done here.
好的 让我继续运行PYTHON of Student.py
All right, let me go ahead and run Python of student.py.
我们再来一次《格兰芬多》中的哈利
We'll again do Harry from Gryffindor.
我认为一切都很好
And I think all is well.
让我再说一次 这一次是帕德玛 在电影中
Let me run it one more time this time with Padma, who, in the movies,
来自格兰芬多 但实际上应该来自拉文克劳
is from Gryffindor, but should really be from Ravenclaw.
那么 在从元组到列表再到词典的过程中 还有什么问题吗？
Any questions then on this progression from tuples to lists to dictionaries?
除了这些元组之外 我们没有必要引入任何新的东西
We haven't necessarily introduced anything new, other than those tuples,
在这段时间里 我们一直都能得到
which have been available to us all this time.
但目前的目标只是为了证明这一区别
But the goal at the moment is just to demonstrate this distinction
在这些不同的数据类型中以及它们如何
among these different data types and how they
每种方法的工作原理都略有不同
each work a little bit differently.
观众：如果我们的元组中有列表的组合呢？
AUDIENCE: What if a combination of lists is there in our tuple?
我们可以改变列表 因为列表是不变的 但是列表是可变的？
We can change the list because are immutable but lists are mutable?
大卫·J·马兰：正确
DAVID J. MALAN: Correct.
您可以更改列表的内容 并且您可以
You can change the contents of lists, and you
几乎可以放任何你想要的东西--其他的列表或字符串 就像我做的那样
can put most anything you want in them-- other lists or strings, as I've done,
整数或其他任何值
integers, or anything else.
元组您可以执行完全相同的操作 但不能一次更改它们
Tuples you can do the exact same thing, but you cannot change them once
是你创造了它们
you've created them.
字典更像是一个列表 因为它是可变的
A dictionary is more like a list in that it is mutable.
你可以改变的
You can change it.
但是你索引词典的方式是
But the way you index into a dictionary is
通过这些钥匙 这些弦 就像我们一直说的
by way of these keys, these strings, as we keep saying,
而不是通过数字--
rather than by numbers--
那些数字索引
those numeric indices.
好吧 好吧 让我来提议一下
All right, well, let me propose that there is yet
解决这个问题的另一种方法
another way of solving this problem.
我会争辩说 现在有一个机会近在眼前
And I would argue that there's now an opportunity at hand.
尽管这个程序并不是特别复杂--
Even though this program isn't particularly complicated--
我所要做的就是从用户和房子中收集一个名字
all I'm doing is collecting a name from the user and a house
从用户那里--你可以想象想要
from the user-- you could imagine wanting,
从长远来看 为了收集更多的信息
longer term, to collect even more information,
就像学生的守护神或魔咒
like the student's patronus or magical spell
或者一大堆其他可能属于学生的信息
or a whole bunch of other information that might belong in a student.
现在 我们只是使用这些非常通用的数据
And right now, we're just using these very general purpose data
Python中的类型--
types in Python--
用于将一些值组合在一起的元组；用于执行相同操作的列表
a tuple to combine some values together; a list to do the same,
但让我们以后再改吧；字典 它更强大
but let us change it later; a dictionary, which is more powerful
因为它更有条理一些
because it's a little more structured.
它确实有钥匙 而且它有价值 而不仅仅是价值
It does have keys, and it has values, not just values.
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
如果Python的作者 我们就不必进行这次对话
We wouldn't have to be having this conversation if the authors of Python
刚刚给我们提供了一个名为Student的数据类型
had just given us a data type called student.
如果能有一个
Wouldn't it have been nice if there were just
我可以在代码中创建一种变量 叫做student？
a type of variable I could create in my code called student?
那我们就不用搞清楚
Then we wouldn't have to figure out, well,
我们是用元组 列表还是字典
do we use a tuple or a list or a dictionary?
但这也很合理
But that's pretty reasonable.
你可以想象这是一个多么滑的斜坡 可以这么说
You can imagine just how slippery of a slope that is, so to speak,
如果一种语言的创造者必须预见到
if the creators of a language had to anticipate
所有可能的数据类型
all the possible types of data that programmers like you
我想把它存储在你的程序里
and me want to store in your programs.
所以他们只是给了我们这些通用工具
So they just gave us these general purpose tools.
但他们给了我们另一个通用工具
But they gave us another general purpose tool
这也将允许我们创建自己的数据类型
that's going to allow us to create our own data types as well
并给它们起名字 这个术语就是一个类
and actually give them names, and that terminology is a class.
类就像是数据对象片段的蓝图
A class is like a blueprint for pieces of data objects.
类是一个你可以定义和命名的模型
A class is a mold that you can define and give a name.
当你用那个模型或者蓝图的时候
And when you use that mold or you use that blueprint,
你得到的数据类型完全是你想要的
you get types of data that are designed exactly as you want.
所以简而言之 类允许您在Python中发明自己的数据类型
So in short, classes allow you to invent your own data types in Python
给他们起个名字
and give them a name.
这是面向对象编程的主要特征
And this is a primary feature of object oriented programming,
能够以这种方式创建自己的对象
to be able to create your own objects in this way
而且 对于Python中的类 甚至可以给它们一些自定义的名称
and, in the case of Python in classes, even give them some custom names.
那么 这在实际意义上意味着什么呢？
So what does this mean in real terms?
好吧 让我继续
Well, let me go ahead and come back to VS Code
这里 让我建议我们引入一点新的语法
here, and let me propose that we introduce a little bit of new syntax.
我要先清空我的终端窗口
I'm going to go ahead and clear my terminal window first.
我要翻到我的档案的最上面 我只是要开始一个想法
I'm going to go to the top of my file, and I'm just going to start a thought
但还没完成
but not finish it yet.
我将使用这个新的关键字来表示类 字面上叫做class
I'm going to use this new keyword for classes, called, literally, class,
所以我们要用新的关键词
so the new keyword we're going to have here.
如果我回到我们的幻灯片
And if I go back to our slides here, this
将是官方网址 你可以阅读更多
would be the official URL where you can read up more
Python的这个特性
on this particular feature of Python.
在官方教程中 class是我们可以使用的新关键字
In the official tutorial, class is a new keyword we can use.
现在 巧合的是 这与学生有关 因为学生上课
Now, this is coincidentally related to students because students take classes,
但这与我们正在与学生打交道的事实无关
but it has nothing to do with the fact that we're dealing with students.
类在许多语言中是一个通用术语--
Class is a general purpose term in a lot of languages--
其中就有Python 它允许您定义这些定制容器
Python among them-- that allow you to define these custom containers
具有数据片段的自定义名称
with custom names for pieces of data.
因此 让我们回到VS代码
So let's go back to VS Code.
让我们使用这个新的关键字
Let's use this new keyword.
让我提议创建一个名为“学生”的类
And let me propose that we create a class called Student.
按照惯例 我将在这里使用大写的S
And by convention, I'm going to use a capital S here,
接下来 我将使用冒号
and I'm going to go ahead, and with a colon,
稍后 我们将介绍这个类的实现
get to, later, the implementation of this class.
所以我将使用. 这是目前有效的占位符
So I'm just going to use dot dot dot, which is a valid placeholder for now,
这对我来说只是预示着我会回来
that just indicates to me that I'm going to come back
到以后实施这一点
to implementing this later.
但到目前为止 它确实存在
But as of now, it does, in fact, exist.
我现在已经为我定义了一个学生类 现在我可以在这里的代码中使用它
I now have a student class defined for me that I can now use in my code here.
我要怎么用它呢？
How am I going to use it?
好的 首先 让我下楼去找学生
Well, first of all, let me go down to get_student,
让我将这段代码更改为不再使用字典 而是使用这个类
and let me change this code to no longer use a dictionary but to use this class.
我要做这件事
I'm going to do this.
我将给自己一个名为Student的变量 就像我以前做过的那样
I'm going to give myself a variable called student, as I've done before,
但我会将其设置为等于大写学生()
but I'm going to set it equal to capital Student ().
所以我要做的似乎是调用一个函数
So I'm going to do what appears to be calling a function
和那个函数 大写的学生S 通知
and that function, Student with a capital S, notice,
匹配我在文件顶部为这个类指定的名称
matches the name that I gave this class at the top of my file.
好了 我下一步想做什么？
All right, what do I next want to do?
我要继续 给这个学生起个名字
I'm going to go ahead and give this student a name.
现在 如果我还在用字典 我
Now, if I were still using a dictionary, I
会用方括号写出学生 引用 不引用 “名字”
would say student, quote, unquote, "name," using square brackets.
但这不是一本词典
But this is not a dictionary.
事实证明 目前 我们将在课堂上
It turns out classes have what, for now, we'll
调用属性 这是一种允许在
call attributes, properties of sorts that allow you to specify values inside
他们中的一员
of them.
而它的语法恰好是一个点
And the syntax for that happens to be a dot.
我们以前见过圆点
We've seen dots before.
我们已经在模块和库的上下文中更普遍地使用了它
We've used it in the context of modules and libraries, more generally.
这是另一个类似的精神使用点
This is another similar in spirit use of a dot
它能让你从别的东西里得到别的东西
that allows you to get at something inside of something else.
所以student.name将是语法
So student.name is going to be the syntax
我给这个学生取了个名字
I use for giving this student a name.
这个名字将是“Name”的返回值
And that name is going to be whatever the return value of "Name" is.
然后我继续说student.house
And then I'm going to go ahead and say student.house to give
另一个名为“House”的属性 并给出输入的返回值
another attribute called "House" and give that the return value of input
在这里 提示用户进行房屋
here, prompting the user for house.
然后 像以前一样 我只是要返回学生
And then, as before, I'm just going to return student.
但现在关于阶级真正强大的是
But now what's really powerful about class,
和面向对象的编程更普遍地说
and object-oriented programming more generally,
我创建了一种自定义数据类型
is that I've created this custom data type called, literally,
学生 大写S 我在变量中存储了一个这样的学生
Student, capital S. I've stored one such student in a variable
就像我在变量student中做的那样
like I can always do in a variable called student, lowercase s.
但我想怎么叫都行
But I could call it anything I want.
称之为学生也是有道理的 但为了清楚起见 我还是要说清楚
It just makes sense to call it student as well, but lowercase for clarity.
然后我返回这个变量
And then I'm returning that variable.
因为我在第14和15行的语法
And because of my syntax in lines 14 and 15,
结果就是把这个类
that has the result of putting inside of that class
name属性和house属性
a name attribute and a house attribute.
我只需要在这里再做一个改变
I just need to make one more change up here.
我要把帕德玛
I'm going to go ahead and remove our Padma
代码 这样我们就可以只关注新的东西
code, just so we can focus only on what's new,
而不是修房子
rather than fixing her house.
我要在这里修改语法
And I'm going to go in here and change the syntax that
以前是字典
previously was for dictionaries.
同样 字典使用方括号 然后在引号中使用字符串
Again, dictionaries use square brackets and then strings in quotes--
单引号或双引号 取决于上下文
either single quotes or double quotes, depending on the context.
在这里 我将把它改为student.name
Here, though, I'm going to change this to be student.name,
在这里 我将把它改为student.house
and over here, I'm going to change it to be student.house.
这就是我的新语法
And that's just going to be my new syntax for getting the contents of what
似乎是一个叫做学生的类
appears to be a class called student.
让我继续搜索student.py的Python 回车
Let me go ahead and rerun Python of student.py, Enter.
让我们像以前一样输入哈利的名字
Let's type in Harry's name as before.
我们把他送进格兰芬多监狱 像往常一样祈祷
Let's put him in Gryffindor, crossing our fingers as we often do,
哈里确实来自格兰芬多
and Harry is indeed from Gryffindor.
不过 我都做了些什么？
What, though, have I done?
让我们在这里介绍另一个术语
Let's introduce one other bit of terminology here
事实证明 我可以使用那个CLASS关键字创建一个类
it turns out that I can create a class, using that class keyword.
但无论何时使用类 都是在创建所谓的对象
But any time you use a class, you're creating what are called objects.
这里是单词对象 作为一种面向对象的编程 或OOP
And here is the word objects, as an object-oriented programming, or OOP.
让我在这里回到我的代码
Let me go back to my code here.
尽管我还没有真正实现它的大部分--
And even though I haven't really implemented much of it at all--
我真的只留下了一个点 点 点--
I literally just left it with a dot, dot, dot--
这是足够的代码 第1行和第2行 仅仅发明了一个新的数据类型
that's enough code, lines 1 and 2, to just invent a new data type called
学生 首都S 这可能会也可能不会有一些未来的功能
Student, capital S, that may or may not have some future functionality as well.
这足以创建一个类
That's enough to create a class.
然而 我在11号线上做了什么？
What, though, am I doing on line 11?
在第11行 从技术上讲 我要做的是创建该类的对象
On line 11, what I'm technically doing is creating an object of that class.
因此 这也是另一个艺术术语
So this, too, is another term of art.
您可以从类创建对象
You create objects from classes.
因此 如果我们回到那个比喻 这个类是
So if we go back to that metaphor, that a class is
就像房子或班级的蓝图就像一个模具
like a blueprint for a house or a class is like a mold,
对象是指当你使用该蓝图建造特定的房屋时
an object is when you use that blueprint to build a specific house
或者是从石膏 模具里出来的东西 当你实际
or something that comes out of-- in plaster, the mold, when you actually
使用该模具来创建这样的对象
use that mold to create such an object.
因此 类又是一种新数据类型的定义
So a class is, again, the definition of a new data type.
对象是的化身 或技术上的实例化
The object is the incarnation of, or technically instantiation of.
对象的另一个术语实际上是实例
And another term for objects would actually be an instance.
您也有类的实例
You have instances of classes as well.
所以这是大量的词汇量
So that's a lot of vocabulary.
但归根结底 它只是归结为这一点
But at the end of the day, it just boils down to this.
您可以定义自己的类 这实际上是您自己的数据类型
You can define your own class, which is really your own data type.
然后 您可以在其中存储属性 在这里使用这个点符号
You can then store attributes inside of it, using this dot notation here.
然后 您可以使用下面这样的代码访问这些相同的属性
And then you can access those same attributes using code like this here.
现在 我有了一个合适的“学生”数据类型
And now, I have a proper "student" data type,
我不需要把一些东西拼凑在一起
and I don't have to hack something together
使用元组或列表 甚至使用字典
using a tuple or a list or even a dictionary.
我现在有了一个名为“Student”的适当数据类型 该数据类型是Python的作者
I now have a proper data type called "student" that the authors of Python
没有给我 我给了我自己
didn't give me; I gave myself.
现在有没有关于CLASS、这个新关键字、CLASS或这个概念的问题
Any questions now on classes, this new keyword, class, or this idea
这些物体或其实例？
of these objects or instances thereof?
观众：类对象是可变的还是不可变的？
AUDIENCE: Is the class object mutable or immutable?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
我们显然已经为进行这种对话奠定了基础
And we've clearly laid the stage for having that conversation
关于现在的每种数据类型
about every data type now.
我们将看到它们是可变的 但您可以使它们不可变
We will see that they are mutable, but you can make them immutable.
这样你就可以两全其美了
So you can get the best of both worlds.
现在 通过编写一些实际的代码--我们将编写比圆点更多的代码
Now, by writing some actual code-- and we'll write more code than the dot,
点 点进一点 关于类或其对象的其他问题？
dot, dot in just a bit, other questions on classes or these objects thereof?
观众：那么这些职业有什么特点呢？
AUDIENCE: Then what would be the properties of those classes?
大卫·J·马兰：所以现在 这些属性--或者属性
DAVID J. MALAN: So at the moment, the properties of-- or the attributes of,
到目前为止 我一直这样称呼它们--就是“名字”和“房子”
as I've been calling them thus far-- would just be "Name" and "House."
事实证明 类中很可能还内置了其他属性
It turns out that there may very well be other attributes built into classes
我们可能很快就会看到
that we may see before long.
但现在 我唯一关心的两个属性
But for now, the only two attributes that I care about
是我自己创造的--
are the ones that I myself created--
即“名字”和“房子” 或者 再一次 我称之为属性
namely "Name" and "House" or, again, what I would call attributes.
稍后 我们将开始
And in a little bit, we're going to start
将这些相同的属性称为实例变量 更专业地说是实例变量
calling those same attributes, more technically, instance variables.
“名字”和“房子” 就像我在VS代码中展示的那样
"Name" and "House," as I presented them here in VS Code
实际上只是在内部称为“name”和“house”的变量
are really just variables called "name" and called "house" inside
类型为学生的对象的
of an object whose type is student.
好的 那么我们还能用这些课程做些什么呢？
All right, so what more can we do with these classes?
再次说明 第11行是我们要实例化的地方
Well, again, on line 11 is where we're instantiating
学生类的对象 并将其赋给学生变量
an object of the student class and assigning it to a student variable.
然后我们添加属性--
We're then adding attributes--
“名字”和“房子”--目前分别在第12行和第13行
"Name" and "House," respectively-- on lines 12 and 13 currently.
从技术上讲 这两者的价值都是
Both of those have values that are technically
字符串或STR 因为这就是输入的返回值
strings or strs, because that's what the return value of the input is.
但这些属性值实际上可以是任何数据类型
But those attributes values could actually be any data type.
我们只是让事情变得简单 专注于定义学生
We're just keeping things simple and focusing on defining students
就两根弦而言--
in terms of two strings--
“名字”和“房子”
"Name" and "House."
然后 在第14行 我们返回该变量
And then, on line 14, we're returning that variable.
我们将该对象返回给Main 这样我们就可以实际
We're returning that object to main so that we can actually
打印出谁是哪个房子的人
print out who is from what house.
好吧 让我们继续在这里添加一些功能 因为 现在
Well, let's go ahead and add a bit more functionality here because, right now,
在第12行和第13行 这是一个小手册
on lines 12 and 13, this is a little manual.
我太鲁莽了 把所有的东西
And it's a little reckless of me to just be putting anything
我想要进入这个学生物体的内部
I want inside of this student object.
事实证明 与字典不同 课堂上的情况不同
It turns out with classes, unlike with dictionaries,
我们实际上可以更多地标准化这些属性
we can actually standardize, all the more, what those attributes can be
以及您可以将它们设置为什么样的值
and what kinds of values you can set them to.
所以让我继续做这件事
So let me go ahead and do this.
让我提议 它实际上将是真正的
Let me propose that it would actually be really
如果让我继续下去 而不是在这里做这个 那真是太好了
nice if, instead of doing this here, let me go ahead
并按如下方式简化我的代码
and simplify my code as follows.
接下来 让我为自己指定一个名为name的局部变量
Let me go ahead and give myself a local variable called name
并将其设置为等于输入的返回值 就像我们现在多次做的那样
and set it equal to the return value of input, like we've done many times now
已经有了
already.
现在让我给自己另一个变量 叫做house
Let me give myself one other variable for now, called house,
并将其设置为等于输入的返回值
and set it equal to the return value of input
以及提示用户选择他们的房子
as well, prompting the user for their house.
现在 不是从我的学生类创建一个学生对象
And now, instead of creating a student object from my student class
然后手动将名称属性放入其中
and then manually putting the name attribute inside of it
和它里面的房子属性 让
and the house attribute inside of it, let
我实际上做了一些更有力量的事情
me actually do something more powerful.
让我来做吧
Let me do this.
让我调用学生函数 它与类名相同--
Let me call that Student function, which is identical to the class name--
只需定义一个类 就可以获得一个函数
just by defining a class, you get a function
其名称与类名相同 包含大写字母
whose name is identical to the class name, with the capital letter included.
但是 不是只做开括号
But instead of just doing open parenthesis,
右括号 让我把我的名字传进去
closed parenthesis, let me pass in the name that I
我想用这个物体和我想放进那个物体的房子来填充
want to fill this object with and the house that I want to put in that object
也是
as well.
现在让我像以前一样设置返回值为学生等于 就像这样
And now let me set the return value as before to be student equals like this.
那么 我做了什么不同的事情呢？
So what have I done that's different?
从根本上说 我仍然以同样的方式获得用户输入
Fundamentally, I'm still getting user input in the same way.
我在第11行使用输入 在第12行使用输入
I'm using input on line 11 and input on line 12.
我只是碰巧将这些返回值存储在局部变量中
And I just so happen to be storing those return values in local variables.
现在 我们正在为类的更强大的功能做准备
And now we're setting the stage for the more powerful features of classes
以及更一般的面向对象编程
and object-oriented programming more generally.
注意 我是故意传递给这个首都S的学生
Notice that I'm deliberately passing to this capital S Student
功能 名字 房子--
function, name, house--
我正在向该函数传递参数
I'm passing in arguments to the function.
现在 学生们还不知道该怎么处理这些东西
Now, the student class is not going to know what to do with those yet,
但现在 我正在标准化如何将数据传递到这个学生班级
but now I'm standardizing how I'm passing data into this student class.
最终 这将给我一个犯错的机会
And ultimately, it's going to give me an opportunity to error
检查这些输入 以确保名称有效 并且具有值
check those inputs, to make sure that the name is valid, that it has a value
而且 不仅仅是用户按了Enter键
and it's not just the user hitting Enter.
这将使我能够确保它是一所有效的房子 它是
It's going to allow me to ensure that it's a valid house, that it's
格兰芬多、赫奇帕奇、拉文克劳或斯莱特林
Gryffindor or Hufflepuff or Ravenclaw or Slytherin
或者不只是按回车键或用户输入的某个随机值
or not just hitting Enter or some random value that the user types in.
因为我要把“名字”和“房子”传给学生
Because I'm passing "Name" and "House" to the student
类 这个特殊的函数 我要
class, this particular function, I'm going
以便更好地控制我的数据的正确性
to have more control over the correctness of my data.
现在让我们来看看学生班 到目前为止
So let's now go up to the student class, which, up until now,
我离开时只是点点 点点 点点
I left as just dot, dot, dot.
事实证明 在课程的背景下
It turns out that, in the context of classes,
有许多不只是属性或实例
there are a number of not just attributes or instance
可以放在里面的变量 也可以放入方法
variables that you can put inside, but also methods.
类带有某些方法 或其中的函数
Classes come with certain methods, or functions inside of them,
你可以定义 他们只是以一种特殊的方式行事
that you can define, and they just behave in a special way,
从本质上讲 它是如何工作的
by nature of how Python works.
这些函数允许您以标准方式确定行为
These functions allow you to determine behavior in a standard way.
从这个意义上说 它们是特殊的方法
They are special methods in that sense.
现在 我这么说是什么意思
Now, what do I mean by this.
好吧 让我回到VS代码这里
Well, let me go back to VS Code here.
让我提议我开始定义一个标准函数
And let me propose that I start to define a standard function
被称为下划线 或下划线 因为它是
called underscore underscore, or Dunder, as it's
缩写、缩写、下划线、下划线
abbreviated, init, underscore underscore,
然后我要继续做开括号
and then I'm going to go ahead and do open parentheses,
然后我要在这里加上 字面上的 自我这个词
and then I'm going to put in here, literally, the word self.
稍后将详细介绍这一点
More on that in just a moment.
但现在 在这个函数中 我将有机会
But now, inside of this function, I'm going to have an opportunity
若要自定义此类的对象 请执行以下操作
to customize this class's objects.
也就是说 这个下划线 下划线init方法
That is to say this underscore, underscore init method,
或者DUnder Init方法具体称为实例方法
or Dunder init method is specifically known as an instance method,
它的名字就是这个
and it's called exactly this.
这是由Python的作者设计的
This is designed by the authors of Python.
如果您想从类中初始化对象的内容
And if you want to initialize the contents of an object from a class,
您定义了这个方法 我们将在这里看到它将要做什么
you define this method, and we'll see what it's about to do here.
让我回到VS代码 让我来做一些类似的事情
Let me go back to VS Code, and let me do something like this.
Self.name=name self.house=house
self.name = name, and self.house = house.
但我不想只是泛泛地初始化这个对象
But I don't want to just init this object very generically.
我希望这种名为init的方法不仅接受自己 还接受名字
I want this method, called init, to take in not just self but name,
豪斯也是
house as well.
现在 世界上到底发生了什么？
Now, what in the world is going on?
因为这里有很多奇怪的语法
Because there's a lot of weird syntax here.
有一种DUnder Init方法--
There's this Dunder init method--
双下划线 初始化 双下划线
double underscore, init, double underscore.
突然间 这个参数被称为SELF
There's, all of a sudden, this parameter called self.
然后是这个新的语法--self.name和self.house
And then there's this new syntax-- self.name and self.house.
现在 您真正看到了面向对象编程的一种表现
Now you're seeing really a manifestation of object-oriented programming.
从根本上说 这并没有什么不同
It's not all that different fundamentally
从我们几周来对词典所做的工作来看
from what we've been doing for weeks with dictionaries,
通过向词典添加关键字
by adding keys to dictionaries.
但在这种情况下 我们向对象添加变量 也就是
But in this case, we're adding variables to objects, a.k.a.
将实例变量转换为对象
instance variables to objects.
现在 这是怎么回事？
Now, what's going on?
让我们反过来来做这件事
Let's do this in reverse.
让我们回到前面编写的代码行
Let's go back to the line of code we wrote earlier.
在第15行 我把这个班级的名字
On line 15, I am treating the name of this class--
学生用大写S--作为函数
Student with a capital S-- as a function.
我要传递两个值--
And I am passing in two values--
“名字”和“房子”
"Name" and "House."
我在屏幕上第15行突出显示的是
What I've highlighted here on the screen, on line 15,
通常称为构造函数调用
is generally known as a constructor call.
这行代码将为我构造一个学生对象
This is a line of code that is going to construct a student object for me.
使用同义词 它将为我实例化一个学生对象
Using synonyms, it is going to instantiate a student object for me.
再说一次 它将如何创建那个对象？
And again, how is it going to create that object?
它将使用学生类作为模板 作为某种模型
It's going to use the student class as a template, as a mold of sorts
所以每个学生的结构都是一样的
so that every student is structured the same.
每个学生都会有一个名字
Every student is going to have a name.
每个学生都会有一所房子
Every student's going to have a house.
但是因为我可以把参数传递给这个学生函数 大写的S
But because I can pass in arguments to this Student function, capital S,
我将能够定制该对象的内容
I'm going to be able to customize the contents of that object.
所以如果你想一想现实世界--如果你曾经走在街上
So if you think about the real world-- if you've ever been on a street
或者是一个社区 所有的房子看起来都一样 但他们可能
or a neighborhood where all of the houses look the same but they might be
油漆不同；它们的装饰可能会略有不同
painted differently; they might be decorated a little bit differently
在外面 所有这些房子都可能是用完全相同的
on the outside, all of those houses might have been built using the exact
同样的蓝图--
same blueprint--
一个模子 如果你愿意的话
a mold, if you will.
但然后你就可以专门研究那些房子的细微之处了
But then you can specialize exactly the finer points of those houses.
通过给外面涂上不同的颜色或种植不同的树
By painting the outside a different color or planting different trees,
您可以设置不同的样式
you can style them differently.
在精神上与这里相似 我们有一个学生蓝图
Similar in spirit here, we have a Student blueprint
它现在总会有名字和房子 但这取决于你和我
that's always going to have now a name and a house, but it's up to you and me
传递我们想要的任何名字和任何房子
to pass in any name and any house that we want.
现在 这个函数在哪里？
Now, where is this function?
我叫学生 大写 S 然后是一个括号
The fact that I'm calling Student, capital, S and then a parenthesis
和一个内含参数的右括号
and a closed parenthesis with arguments inside
暗示在某个地方有一个函数
suggest that there's a function somewhere
在已经定义的世界中 使用def 这将被称为
in the world that has been defined, with def, that's going to be called.
嗯 正如您现在可能已经猜到的那样 函数
Well, as you might have guessed by now, the function
通过定义Python类的工作方式 它将始终被调用
that will always be called, by definition of how Python classes work,
是一个名为双下划线、初始化、双下划线的函数
is a function called double underscore, init, double underscore.
为什么？
Why?
这是一个疯狂的名字 但它是Python的作者
It's a crazy name, but it's what the authors of Python
选择只在Python中实现对象的初始化
chose to just implement the initialization of an object in Python.
现在 唯一奇怪的是--
Now, the only weird thing--
我承认 特别奇怪的是 这一点
especially weird thing, I will admit, is this.
对我来说 如果初始化的唯一两个参数是
It would be way clearer, to me, too, if the only two parameters for init we're
只是名字 豪斯
just name, house.
到目前为止 我们就是这样定义类中的每个函数的
That's how we've defined every function thus far in the class.
您只需指定希望函数接受的参数
You just specify the parameters that you want the function to accept.
这与我在第15行所做的是一致的
And that lines up with what I'm doing on line 15.
我只向学生函数传递了两件事
I am only passing in two things to the student function.
但事实证明 Python的作者
But it turns out that the authors of Python
需要在这里给我们一点帮助
need to give us a little bit of help here
因为假设您将“name”和“house”传递给这个init方法
because suppose that you pass in "Name" and "House" to this init method.
而方法只是类中的一个函数
And a method is just a function inside of a class.
你打算怎么处理这个名字和房子？
What are you going to do with the name and the house?
从字面上看 你打算把它们放在哪里？
Literally, where are you going to put them?
如果你想记住这个学生的名字和房子
If you want to remember the name and the house for this student,
你必须能够将这些值存储在某个地方
you've got to be able to store those values somewhere.
以及如何将它们存储在当前对象中
And how do you store them in the current object
刚刚被“实例化”了吗？
that has just been "instantiated?"
好吧 Python语言的作者们决定
Well, the authors of Python decided that the convention
这个初始化方法也会半秘密地
is going to be that this init method also, semi secretly, takes
第三个论点 那必须放在第一位
a third argument, that has to come first.
按照惯例 它被称为SELF 但你可以
By convention, it's called self, but you could
严格来说 你可以叫它任何你想要的东西
call it technically anything you want.
但惯例是 它总是自称是自己
But the convention is to always call it self.
而SELF 顾名思义 给了你访问
And self, as its name implies, gives you access
添加到刚刚创建的当前对象
to the current object that was just created.
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
再一次 现在 在第14行 现在它向下移动了一点
Again, now, on line 14, now that it's moved down a little bit,
这里的这行是一个构造函数
this line here is a constructor.
它构造了一个学生对象
It constructs a student object.
但最初那个物体里什么都没有
But there's nothing in that object initially.
没有名字 没有房子
There's no name; there's no house.
但该对象存在于计算机的内存中
But the object exists in the computer's memory.
现在 您需要将姓名和房子存储在该对象中
It's up to, now, you to store the name and the house inside of that object.
你怎么做到的？
How do you do that?
嗯 Python会自动为您调用这个init方法
Well, Python will just automatically call this init method for you,
它将自动传递对一个参数的引用 该参数
and it's going to automatically pass in a reference to an argument that
表示它刚刚在内存中为您构造的当前对象
represents the current object that it just constructed in memory for you,
而这取决于你用价值观来填充它
and it's up to you to populate it with values.
这意味着 在您的init方法中
And what this means is that, inside of your init method,
从字面上看 您可以使用self.name来创建一个新的属性 也就是
you can literally do self.name to create a new attribute, a.k.a.
一个实例变量 位于该变量内部 否则为空
an instance variable, inside of that otherwise empty
对象 并将此名称放入其中
object and put this name inside of it.
它允许你自己做房子 并储存房子的价值
It allows you to do self.house and store that value of house.
现在 你可以给这些东西取任何你想要的名字
Now, you could call these things anything you want.
它们可能是n
They could be n.
它们可能是h 就像以前一样
They could be h, as before.
但这真的不是很清楚
But that's really not very self-explanatory.
做这样的大会要好得多 Self.name等于name
Much better to do this kind of convention. self.name equals name.
自个儿 房子等于房子
self.house equals house.
这就像是将值名称安装到其他空的对象中
And this is like installing into the otherwise empty object the value name
并将它们存放和存储在名称完全相同的实例中
and house and storing them in, really, identically named instance
对象中的变量
variables in the object.
同样 对象只是类的一个实例
And again, an object is just an instance of a class.
现在 我知道那是很多词汇量
Now, I know that was a lot of vocabulary.
这是很多奇怪的语法
That's a lot of weird syntax.
所以任何关于这个初始化方法的问题 它在生活中的目的
So any questions on this init method, whose purpose in life,
还是要在第一次创建一个空对象时对其进行初始化？
again, is to initialize an otherwise empty object when you first create it?
受众：那么init方法和默认方法有什么不同呢
AUDIENCE: So what is the difference between the init method and default
构造者？
constructor?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
所以在其他语言中--如果你以前编程过
So in other languages-- if you programmed before.
例如 Java--有一些函数被显式调用
For instance, Java-- there are functions that are explicitly called
构造对象的构造函数
constructors that construct an object.
它们使用值对其进行初始化
They initialize it with values.
从技术上讲 Python将这个init方法称为初始化方法
Python technically calls this init method the initialization method.
它初始化值
It initializes the value.
现在我的代码在第15行 如果我向下滚动 从技术上讲 我是
It's on line 15 now of my code, if I scroll back down, that I'm technically
构建对象
constructing the object.
原来 在Python中还有另一种特殊的方法
It turns out there's another special method in Python,
今天我们不会详细讨论
that we won't talk about in detail today,
调用下划线下划线、新下划线、下划线
called underscore underscore, new, underscore underscore
它实际上处理了创建
that actually handles the process of creating
在我们的记忆中有一个空的物体
an empty object in memory for us.
但是 总的来说 你这个程序员
But, generally speaking, you, the programmer,
不需要操控新函数
don't need to manipulate the new function.
它只对你有效
It just works for you.
相反 您可以在这里定义您自己的init方法
Instead, you define your own init method here
和init函数在您的类中 该方法
and init function inside of your class, and that method
初始化对象的内容
initializes the contents of the object.
所以从技术上讲 构造对象与构建对象之间存在区别
So there's technically a distinction between constructing the object
使用new并使用init对其进行初始化
with new and initializing it with init.
但在Python的世界中 您几乎只担心init方法
But in the world of Python, you pretty much only worry about the init method.
Python通常会为您完成另一部分工作
Python generally does the other part for you.
问得好
A good question.
其他?
Others?
观众：如果你想存储多个名字怎么办？
AUDIENCE: What about if you want to store more than one name or more
不只是一栋房子？
than one house?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
如果要存储多个名称或多个房屋
If you want to store more than one name or more than one house,
你可以用不同的方式来做这件事
you can do this in different ways.
您可以创建其他属性--技术上称为实例变量--
You could create other attributes-- technically called instance variables--
如self.name1、self.name2
like self.name1, self.name2.
但我们在过去已经看到 这并不是
But we've seen, in the past, that that is not
一个非常好的设计 仅仅是有多个变量来存储
a very good design, just to have multiple variables to store
多件事
multiple things.
也许 相反 您有一个名为self.name、复数
Maybe, instead, you have an instance variable called self.names, plural,
你把它设置成一个名字列表或一个房屋列表
and you set it equal to a list of names or a list of houses.
现在 在这种情况下 我不认为这真的解决了问题 因为我
Now, in this case, I don't think that really solves a problem because I'm
试图实现一个学生 单数 所以它没有真正的意义
trying to implement a student, singular, so it doesn't really make sense
有多个名字
to have multiple first names.
可能是昵称 也可能是姓氏 所以我们也可以加上这些
Maybe a nickname, maybe a last name, so we could add those, too.
但我不认为我们本身需要多个名字
But I don't think we need multiple names per se
在这种情况下 还有多栋房子
and, in this case, multiple houses.
但绝对可以使用我们熟悉的一些构建块来实现这一点
But absolutely, you could do that using some of our familiar building blocks
就像清单一样
like lists.
还有其他问题吗？
Other questions?
观众：类或对象在内存中是如何表示的？
AUDIENCE: How are classes or objects represented in memory?
David J.Malan：类和对象在内存中是如何表示的？
DAVID J. MALAN: How are classes and objects represented in memory?
所以从技术上讲 这个类只是代码
So the class is technically just code.
这是我文件顶部的代码--第1行到第4行--
It is the code on the top of my file-- lines 1 through fou4--
它定义了蓝图 模板 如果你愿意的话
that defines that blueprint, that template, if you will.
对象存储在计算机的内存中
Objects are stored in the computer's memory
通过占用一定数量的字节
by taking up some number of bytes.
所以您可能对字节、千字节或兆字节很熟悉
So you're probably familiar with bytes or kilobytes or megabytes.
有一些字节块 可能都是
There's some chunk of bytes, probably all
在计算机内存中的相同位置
in the same location in the computer's memory
或RAM 其中存储这些对象
or RAM, where those objects are stored.
但这就是程序Python为您处理的
But that's what Python, the program, handles for you.
解释程序会找出将其放在计算机内存中的位置
Python the interpreter figures out where in the computer's memory to put it.
你和我 作为程序员 在这个层面上思考和解决问题
You and I, the programmers, get to think and solve problems at this level.
作为解释器的Python将为您处理这些较低级别的细节
Python, the interpreter, handles those lower level details for you.
最后一个关于类和对象的问题怎么样？
How about one final question on classes and objects?
听众：所以我的问题是 我们是否也能这样做
AUDIENCE: So my question is if we can the same do
字典也是如此 那么为什么要使用类呢？
the same thing with the dictionaries, so why to use classes?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: Good question.
如果你能用字典做同样的事情
If you can do the same things as you can with dictionaries,
为什么要使用类？
why should you use classes?
因为我们现在只是触及了什么的皮毛
Because we are just scratching the surface now of what
你可以用课程来应付
you can do with classes.
现在 请允许我回到我的键盘上 向你们展示
Allow me to go back, now, to my keyboard and show you
更多关于您可以使用类所做的事情
more of what you can do with classes.
但简而言之 您可以使用类做更多的事情
But in short, you can do much more with classes.
使用类可以更好地确保数据的正确性
You can ensure the correctness of your data much more with classes.
你可以错误地检查一些东西
You can error-check things.
通常 您可以更有效地设计更复杂的软件
And generally, you can design more complicated software more effectively.
今天我们将继续看到一些特色
And we'll continue to see, today, features
更广泛地说 是关于Python和面向对象编程的
of Python and object-oriented programming more generally
这使我们能够做到这一点
that allows us to do just that.
所以让我提议 事实上 首先 让我们收紧这股电流
So let me propose, in fact, that first, let's just tighten up this current
实现 这也为我们提供了一个init方法 它只声明了两个
implementation, which again has us with an init method that just declares two
实例变量--self.name和self.house house 同样
instance variables-- self.name and self.house, house, which, again,
只是在原本为空的对象内创建这些变量 并将
just creates those variables inside of the otherwise empty object and assigns
他们的价值观--
them values--
分别是名字和房子
name and house, respectively.
让我继续在这里做一件小事
Let me go ahead and just do one little thing here.
我真的不需要这个学生变量
I don't really need this student variable.
让我来加强一下 这样每次我们改进或更改代码时
Let me just tighten this up so that each time we improve or change the code,
我们真的只关注最小的变化
we're focusing, really, on just the minimal changes alone.
所以我从根本上没有做任何不同的事情
So I've not fundamentally done anything different.
我刚刚去掉了变量名 我只是
I just got rid of the variable name, and I'm just
返回此学生函数的返回值
returning the return value of this student function
这是在为我构建我的新对象
that's constructing my new object for me.
因此 我只是像过去多次做的那样 收紧措施
So I'm just tightening things up as we've done many times in the past.
那么 如果在创造这个学生的过程中出了什么问题呢？
Well, what if something goes wrong in creating this student?
例如 如果用户没有给我们提供姓名 他们只是点击
For instance, what if the user does not give us a name, and they just hit
系统提示输入名称时 请输入
Enter when prompted for name.
我不想把我的电脑的内存
I don't want to put in my computer's memory
一个没有名字的假学生对象
a bogus student object that has no name.
理想情况下 我甚至希望在创建它之前检查错误
I'd ideally like to check for errors before I even create it
所以我不会创造一个无名的学生
so I don't create a nameless student.
拥有一个没有名称的对象会很奇怪 而且可能是一个错误
It would just be weird and probably a bug to have an object that has no name.
同样 我不希望用户能够输入
Similarly, I don't want the user to be able to type
在随机的地方 比如他们的房子
in something random as their house.
至少在哈利波特的世界里 真的有
At least in the world of Harry Potter, there's really
只有四栋房子 至少在霍格沃茨
only four houses, at Hogwarts at least.
又是格兰芬多和赫奇帕奇
There's, again, Gryffindor and Hufflepuff
以及拉文克劳和斯莱特林--四所有效房屋的名单
and Ravenclaw and Slytherin-- a list of four valid houses.
如果我以某种方式验证用户的输入确实是
It would be nice if I somehow validated that the user's input is indeed
在那张单子上
in that list.
现在 我可以在我的Get_Student函数中执行所有的验证
Now, I could do all of that validation in my get_student function.
我可以查一下 名字是空的吗？
I could check, is the name empty?
如果是这样的话 不要创建学生对象
If so, don't create the student object.
这栋房子是那四栋房子中的一栋吗？
Is the house one of those four houses?
如果不是 请不要创建学生对象
If not, don't create the student object.
但这将与学生本身脱钩
But that would be rather decoupled from the student itself.
Get_Student目前仅作为我自己的函数存在于我的Student.py文件中
get_student currently exists as just my own function in my student.py file.
但是类--以及真正的面向对象编程--更多
But classes-- and really, object-oriented programming-- more
通常会鼓励您在内部封装
generally encourages you to encapsulate, inside
类的所有功能 所有与该类相关的功能
of a class, all functionality related to that class.
因此 如果你想验证一个名字是否存在--
So if you want to validate that a name exists--
如果你想验证房子是正确
if you want to validate that a house is correct,
从根本上说属于学生这个阶层
that belongs just fundamentally in the class called student itself,
而不是你在别处写的随机函数
not in some random function that you wrote elsewhere.
这只是一种方法 因为
Again, this is just methodology because, again,
如果我们考虑写越来越长的代码
if we think about writing code that gets longer and longer, more and more
很复杂 它应该只是直观的感觉
complicated, it should make just intuitive sense that,
如果你保留所有的房子
if you keep all the house--
所有的名字和所有与房子相关的代码
all of the name and all of the house-related code in the student,
只是更好的组织
it's just better organization.
把所有相关的代码放在一起
Keep all of the related code together, and that's probably
会让你更成功
going to set you up for more success.
实际上 这是我们方法论的一部分
And indeed, that's part of this methodology
面向对象的编程
of object-oriented programming.
现在让我来给我的学生换个班
Let me go ahead now and change my students classes
init方法来实现
init method to do this.
如果名字是空的--
If the name is blank--
所以如果不是name--我们以前见过这种语法
so if not name-- and we've seen this kind of syntax before.
如果你在Python中说 如果不是name
If you say in Python, Pythonically, if not name,
做这种事的人
that's doing something like this.
如果name等于 等于 引号 不引号
If name equals, equals, quote, unquote--
但我可以做得更优雅一点
but I can do this a little more elegantly.
只是说 如果没有名字 将是更多的Pythonic
Just say, if not name, would be the more Pythonic.
我想返回一个错误
Well, I want to return an error.
我可能想做这样的事
I might want to do something like this.
打印缺少的姓名
Print missing name.
但这还不够
But this is not good enough.
仅仅打印缺少的姓名是不够的
It does not suffice to just print out missing name
然后让剩下的代码通过
and then let the rest of the code go through.
好吧 好吧 那我能做什么呢？
All right, well, what could I do instead?
在过去 我们已经看到了另一种技术 我可以做系统退出
In the past, we've seen another technique I could do sys.exit,
我可以说一些像缺少名字的东西 我可以在这里
and I could say something like missing name, and I could go up here
我可以导入系统
and I could import sys.
但这是一个非常令人讨厌的解决问题的方法
But this is a really obnoxious solution to the problem.
只是因为你或者某个同事搞砸了
Just because you or maybe a colleague messed up
并调用了一个具有无效名称的函数
and called a function with an invalid name,
你要退出我的整个项目吗
you're going to quit my whole program?
这反应真的很极端
That's really, really extreme of a response,
如果你的程序
and you probably don't want to do that if your program is
在跑步的中途
in the middle of running.
你可能想清理一下
You might want to clean some stuff up.
您可能想要保存有时不想退出程序的文件
You might want to save files you don't want to just exit a program sometimes
在某些任意行中 只是因为输入无效
in some arbitrary line, just because input was invalid.
因此 我认为我们也不想这么做
So I don't think we want to do that either.
但我们现在确实有一种发出错误信号的机制
But we do, now, have a mechanism for signaling errors.
不幸的是 我不能做这样的事
Unfortunately, I can't do something like this.
我可以试着一个都不回 然后说 嗯-嗯 这个学生不存在
I could try returning none and say, uh-uh, this student does not exist.
我要一分钱都不还给你
I'm going to hand you back none instead.
但为时已晚
But it's too late.
如果我们向下滚动到我创建学生的位置 它在第17行
If we scroll back down to where I'm creating the student, it's on line 17
现在我突出显示了这段代码
now where I've highlighted this code.
已经创建了该学生
The student has already been created.
在计算机内存中的某个地方有一个对象
There is an object somewhere in the computer's memory
作为一名学生 这是一种结构
that's structured as a student.
只是它里面没有任何价值
It just doesn't have any values inside of it.
但因此 现在什么都不回已经太晚了
But it's too late, therefore, to return none.
那艘船已经启航了
That ship has sailed.
该对象存在
The object exists.
你不能突然说 不 不 没有物体
You can't just suddenly say, nope, nope, there is no object.
有一件物品
There is an object.
这取决于你是否发出错误信号
It's up to you to signal an error.
如何发出错误信号？
And how do you signal an error?
实际上 我们以前见过这种情况 但我们还没有机会
Well, we've actually seen this before, but we haven't had occasion
制造我们自己的错误
to create our own errors.
原来 在Python中 还有另一个与异常相关的关键字
It turns out, in Python, there's another keyword related to exceptions
它本身用来引发我们的所有异常
that Python itself uses to raise all of those exceptions we've
在过去曾被谈论过
talked about in the past.
当您发现值错误或其他类似的异常时
When you've caught things like value errors or other such exceptions that
和Python一起来 好吧 原来你 程序员可以提出--
come with Python, well, it turns out you, the programmer can raise--
那就是当某些事情真的出了问题时 创建自己的例外--
that is create your own exceptions when something just really goes wrong--
还没有错到你想退出并退出整个计划
not wrong enough that you want to quit and exit the whole program,
但足以让您以某种方式提醒程序员
but enough that you need to somehow alert the programmer
这是一个错误
that there has been an error.
一些不同寻常的东西 以一种非常糟糕的方式--一些东西
Something exceptional, in a very bad way-- something
异常已经发生 让他们在需要时尝试捕获该异常
exceptional has happened, and let them try to catch that exception as needed.
因此 让我回到VS代码 并提出建议
So let me go back to VS Code here and propose
如果用户传入了无效的名称--它只是空的
that, if the user passes in an invalid name-- it's just empty,
所以没有名字
so there's not a name.
我真正想做的是这件事
Well, what I really want to do is this.
我想引发一个值错误
I want to raise a value error.
我们以前也见过数值错误
And we've seen the value errors before.
我们以前曾意外地制造了价值错误
We've created value errors accidentally before.
一般来说 如果他们发生了 你和我都会试图抓住他们
And generally, you and I have tried to catch them if they happen.
嗯 在像Python这样的语言中 这种异常特性的另一面
Well, the flip side of this feature of exceptions in a language like Python
作为程序员 您也可以引发异常
is that you, the programmer, can also raise exceptions
当一些不寻常的事情发生时
when something exceptional happens.
你甚至可以说得更准确
And you can even be more precise.
您不必引发泛型值错误并让程序员找出
You don't have to raise a generic value error and let the programmer figure out
哪里出了问题
what went wrong.
您可以将值错误和Python中的所有异常视为类似的函数
You can treat value error and all exceptions in Python like functions
并向他们传递一条解释性信息 比如 引用 不引用
and actually pass to them an explanatory message like, quote, unquote,
“缺少名字” 至少让程序员在遇到
"Missing name," so that at least the programmer, when they encounter
这个错误 知道 哦 我搞砸了
this error, knows, oh, I messed up.
我不确定该用户是否有名字
I didn't make sure that the user has a name.
现在 你想做什么呢？
And now, what do you want to do instead?
现在 如果你是程序员 你可以做这样的事情
Well, now, if you're the programmer, you could do something like this.
您可以尝试创建一个学生 除非存在值错误
You could try to create a student except if there's a value error.
然后你就可以用某种方式来处理它
Then you could handle it in some way.
我要用一个圆点
And I'm going to wave my hand with a dot, dot, dot,
你会如何处理这件事
at how you would handle it.
但您将使用尝试和接受来处理它 就像我们过去所做的那样
But you would handle it using try and accept, just like we have in the past,
这将允许你 作为程序员
and that would allow you, the programmer,
试图创造出这个学生
to try to create the student.
但如果出了问题 好吧 我还是会处理的
But if something goes wrong, OK, I'll handle it nonetheless.
所以 这里的新内容是 再一次 这个提升关键字
So what's new here, again, is this raise keyword,
这只是让你和我实际上提出了我们自己的例外
that just lets you and I actually raise our own exceptions
发出这些错误的信号
to signal these errors.
好吧 让我回到我的代码 我只是
Well, let me go back to my code here, and I'm just
我要继续下去 不费心尝试或捕捉这个错误
going to go ahead and not bother trying or catching this error.
现在 我们只专注于提高它 并假设
For now, we'll just focus on raising it and assume
从我们的侦察例外中 您可以添加尝试和接受
that, from our recon exceptions, you could add try and accept
在一些地方需要的时候
as needed in places.
让我回到这里的代码 并建议其他东西可以
Let me go back to the code here and propose that something else could
豪斯出事了
go wrong with house.
如果有名字的话 我们就没问题了
If there is a name, we're good.
但如果我们得到了一所房子 但它是无效的
But if we're given a house but it's invalid,
我们也应该破例一次
we should probably raise an exception for that, too.
如果我们这么做呢？
So what if we do this?
如果豪斯不在格兰芬多的名单上
If house is not in the list containing "Gryffindor," quote, unquote,
“赫奇帕奇” 原话是
"Hufflepuff," quote, unquote--
我想想 “拉文克劳 ”引用 不引用 或者“斯莱特林 ”
let's see, "Ravenclaw," quote, unquote, or "Slytherin,"
引用 引用 然后 用我的冒号 让我们
quote, unquote, then, with my colon, let's
引发另一种类型的值错误
raise another type of value error.
但是 与其引发一般值错误
But rather than raise a generic value error,
让我们传递一个参数 引用 不引用 “无效的房子 “
let's pass in an argument, quote, unquote, "Invalid house."
所以我们现在看到了一种能力
And so here we now see a capability that we
可以用字典做不到的类
can do with classes that we can't with dictionaries.
如果你给字典添加一个属性 一个键
If you add an attribute to a dictionary, a key to a dictionary,
无论如何都要进去
it's going in no matter what.
即使名字是空的 即使房子是完全随机的字符串
Even if the name is empty, even if the house is a completely random string
不属于这四所房子的文字
of text that's not one of these four houses,
就会被收入字典里
it's going into that dictionary.
但是对于类 通过这个init方法
But with a class, and by way of this init method,
你和我现在可以精确地控制将要安装的东西 如果你愿意的话
you and I can now control exactly what's going to be installed, if you will,
在这个物体里面
inside of this object.
你现在对正确性有了更多的控制
You have a little more control now over correctness.
现在让我继续向下滚动到终端窗口
And so now let me go ahead and scroll back down to my terminal window
并清除它
and clear it.
让我运行student.py的Python
Let me run Python of student.py.
让我输入一些像哈里
Let me type in something like Harry.
让我输入Gryffindor Enter 然后我们看到
Let me type in Gryffindor, Enter, and we see
哈利确实是格兰芬多的
that, indeed, Harry is from Gryffindor.
如果我犯了个错误呢？
What if I made a mistake, though?
如果我运行student.py的Python并输入Harry作为名字
What if I ran Python of student.py and typed Harry as the name,
但这次输入的是女贞路四号
but this time typed in Number Four, Privet Drive, which
是他长大的地方而不是他真正的霍格沃茨
is where he grew up, instead of his proper Hogwarts house.
现在按下Enter键 您将看到一个值错误
Let me hit Enter now, and now you see a value error.
但本质上 这不是Python为我们生成的
But this isn't one that Python generated for us, per se.
我提出了这个错误
I raised this error.
因此 如果我在get_student函数中编写更多的代码
And therefore, if I went in and wrote more code in my get_student function,
我也可以用我们常用的try except语法来捕获这个错误
I could also catch this error with our usual try except syntax.
所以我们现在所拥有的不仅仅是工具箱中的类 还有更多的功能
So all we have now is not just classes in our toolkit, but even more powers
而不仅仅是我们自己去捕捉它们
when it comes to exceptions, and not just catching them ourselves
但我们自己也要抚养他们
but raising them ourselves, too.
关于类和init的用法还有这个能力
Any questions now on this use of classes and init and now this ability
在初始化过程中出错时引发异常
to raise exceptions when something goes wrong inside of the initialization?
观众：那么如果用户有一个中间名呢？
AUDIENCE: So what if the user has a middle name--
名字中间名和姓氏
name, middle name, and last name?
你要怎么解决？
How would you fix that?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: Good question.
如果你想让学生有名字、中间名和姓氏
If you wanted the student to have a first name, middle name, and last name,
我们可以用很多不同的方法来做
we could do this in a bunch of different ways.
最简单的 如果--让我清空屏幕
The simplest, though, if-- let me clear my screen here, and let
我只是暂时这么做
me just temporarily do this.
让我建议init方法接受第一个参数 一个中间参数
Let me propose that the init method take in a first argument, a middle argument,
最后一个论点
and a last argument.
然后我想我会在这里做的是最终有第一=第一
And then what I think I would do down here is ultimately have first = first,
然后我会对中间和最后做同样的事情
and then I would do the same thing for middle and last.
中间和中间 最后和最后
So middle and middle, and then last and last.
接下来我要做的是
And then what I would have to do here is,
当我问用户他们的名字时
when I actually ask the user for their name,
我可能真的需要全力以赴
I might need to really go all out.
我可能要先问他们的名字
I might need to ask them first for their first name
并将其存储在一个名为first的变量中 因此首先传入
and store that in a variable called first, and therefore pass in first.
我可能同样需要问他们的中间名
I might similarly need to ask them for their middle name
并将其存储在一个变量中 然后传入第二个参数 middle
and store that in a variable and then pass in a second argument, middle.
最后 如果你愿意 让我继续创造
And then lastly, if you will, let me go ahead and create
第三个变量last 输入他们的姓氏
a third variable called last, get the input for their last name,
把它也传进去
and pass that in as well.
我可以只使用一个输入 只要求他们输入全名
I could instead just use one input and just ask them for their whole name.
所以输入大卫·马兰 回车 或者大卫·J·马兰--三个都是
So type in David Malan, Enter, or David J. Malan-- all three of them,
也许我可以用Python的split函数
and maybe I could use Python's split function,
也许是一个正则表达式来区分它
maybe a regular expression to tease it apart.
这可能会很麻烦 因为
That's probably going to be messy because there's
他们的名字不会只有两三个
going to be people who don't have just two or three names.
他们可能有四个或五个
They might have four or five.
因此 有时使用多个提示可能更好
So maybe sometimes it's better to have multiple prompts.
但这不是问题 因为 在上课的时候
But that's not a problem because, with a class,
如果我们想要 我们有表现力接受更多的论点
we have the expressiveness to take in more arguments if we want.
如果我们愿意 我们甚至可以列一张单子
We could even take a list if we wanted.
但我认为我们可能会想要进行更多的错误检查
But I think we'd probably want to have even more error checking then,
不仅是名字 而且是第一次 然后可能是中间 然后是
not just for name but for first, and then maybe for middle, and then
也许是最后一次
maybe for last.
所以它只是越来越多的代码 尽管会有
So it just is more and more code, though there would be
或许也有巩固这一点的方法
ways to perhaps consolidate that, too.
让我把所有这些都撤销 看看现在课堂上是否还有其他问题
Let me undo all of that and see if there are other questions now on classes.
观众：我想上课是我
AUDIENCE: I assume classes are something I
在项目开始时可能会做的事情
might do at the beginning of a project.
我可以将它们放在不同的文件中并导入它们吗
Can I just put them in a different file and import them
根据需要添加到我的项目中 还是我的主代码中？
into my project, or my main code as needed?
大卫·J·马兰：当然
DAVID J. MALAN: Absolutely.
这是一个非常好的问题
A really good question.
你可以想象想要利用这个学生
You could imagine wanting to use this student
类 不仅在Student.py中 而且在您的其他文件或其他项目中
class, not just in student.py but in other files or other projects of yours.
当然 您可以创建自己的类库
And absolutely, you can create your own library of classes
通过将学生类放入您自己的模块或包中
by putting the student class in your own module or package,
根据我们过去对图书馆更一般的讨论
per our discussion in the past about libraries more generally.
当然 你可以做到的
And absolutely, you can do that.
今天晚些时候 我们看到的是我们实际上
And later today, what we see is we've actually
我以前一直在第三方库中使用类--你和我
been using classes-- you and I-- before, in third party libraries.
所以你也完全可以做同样的事情
So you, too, can absolutely do the same.
再问一个关于课上的问题如何？
How about one more question on classes?
听众：你可以在类中有可选变量吗？
AUDIENCE: Can you have optional variables in classes?
第二 你能有自己的错误名称吗 比如--
And two, can you have your own error names, like--
让我们以自我为中心 说我想提出Eric Error？
let's be egotistical and say I want to raise Eric error?
大卫·J·马兰：简而言之 是的
DAVID J. MALAN: Short answer, yes.
这些初始化函数更像是Python函数
These init functions are just like Python functions more
一般说来 尽管它们很特别 但它们
generally, even though they're special in that they're
它将自动由Python为您调用
going to get called automatically by Python for you.
但如果你想让房子变成可选的
But if you wanted to make house optional,
你可以做这样的事情
you could do something like this.
您可以在init函数的签名中给它一个缺省值
You could give it a default value in the init function's signature
可以这么说--在第二行第一行代码中
so to speak-- in that first line of code on line two.
这样我就不用进屋了
And that would allow me to not have to pass in house.
在这种情况下 我将继续传递姓名和住所
In this case, I'm going to continue to always pass in name and house,
但你可以把这些设置为可选的
but you could make things optional.
是的 关于你的第二个问题 如果你想有你自己的错误信息
And yes, to your second question, if you wanted to have your own error message,
就像Eric错误一样 您实际上可以创建自己的Eric错误异常
like an Eric error, you could actually create your own Eric error exception.
稍后我们会看到 实际上
And we'll see, in a little bit, that there's actually
一整套存在的例外 你也可以发明这些例外
a whole suite of exceptions that exist, and you, too, can invent those as well.
不过 让我提议 我们现在介绍
Let me propose, though, that we now introduce
另一个方面是 我们尝试打印出学生的样子
one other aspect of this whereby we try printing out what a student looks like.
目前 如果我向下滚动到我的主要功能
At the moment, if I scroll back down to my main function,
我还在非常手动地打印这名学生的姓名和住处
I'm still printing the student's name and house very manually.
我要进入物体的内部 做学生 名字
I'm going inside of the object, doing student.name,
我要再次进入这个物体 让学生 房子
and I'm going inside of the object again and getting student.house,
只是想看看这名学生来自哪里
just to see where the student is from.
但如果我能把学生的指纹印出来
But wouldn't it be nice if I could just print the student,
就像我已经打印了几个星期--
like I've been printing for weeks--
ANY、INT或FLOAT、STR或任何其他数据类型？
any, int, or float, or str, or any other data type?
好吧 让我们看看如果我试着打印学生会发生什么
Well, let's see what happens if I just try printing the student,
而不是手动进入并试图自己创建这句话
instead of manually going inside and trying to create that sentence myself.
好的 在我的终端窗口中--让我继续运行PYTHON of Student.py
Well, in my terminal window-- let me go ahead and run Python of student.py
再来一次
again.
让我输入哈里
Let me type in Harry.
让我输入格兰芬多
Let me type in Gryffindor.
看 哈利--哇 好的 主要学生对象在0x102733e80
And voila, Harry-- whoa, OK, main student object at 0x102733e80.
好吧 这是怎么回事？
Well, what is going on?
如果你要运行相同的代码 你
Well, if you were to run the same code, you
可能会在您的计算机上看到一些不同的内容
might actually see something different on your computer
就这个数字而言
in terms of that number.
但你真正看到的是潜在的表示 作为一个字符串
But what you're really seeing is the underlying representation, as a string,
这一特定物体的
of this specific object.
特别是 您可以看到它在计算机内存中的什么位置
In particular, you're seeing where in the computer's memory it is.
这个数字30x102733e80实质上指的是一个特定的位置
This number, 30x102733e80, refers to, essentially, a specific location
在计算机的内存或RAM中
in the computer's memory or RAM.
这对我或你来说都不是很有趣 或者 总的来说
That's not really that interesting for me or you or, generally speaking,
程序员 但这只是默认的描述方式
programmers, but it's just the default way of describing,
通过印刷品 这是什么东西
via print, what this thing is.
但我也可以推翻这一点
But I can override this as well.
原来 在Python中还有其他特殊的方法
It turns out that there are other special methods in Python
当涉及到课程时--
when it comes to classes--
不只是下划线 初始化 下划线
not just underscore underscore, init, underscore underscore,
但是 继续使用相同模式 在下划线、字符串
but, continuing in that same pattern, underscore underscore, str,
下划线
underscore underscore.
因此 这也是一个特殊的方法 如果您在类中定义它
So this, too, is a special method that, if you define it inside of your class,
Python将自动调用此函数
Python will just automatically call this function
任何时候 某个其他函数想要将您的对象视为字符串
for you any time some other function wants to see your object as a string.
Print希望将您的对象显示为字符串
Print wants to see your object as a string.
但默认情况下 如果您的类中没有定义此方法
But by default, if you don't have this method defined in your class,
它将打印出非常难看的深奥的化身
it's going to print out that very ugly esoteric incarnation thereof,
其中写着Main__ 学生对象在0x 点
where it says main__.Student object at 0x, dot, dot, dot.
那么 我该如何定义自己的str函数呢？
Well, how can I then define my own str function?
好了 回到VS Code 让我提议我进入
Well, here, back in VS Code, let me propose that I go in
不仅定义__init 还让我在这个类中定义第二个函数
and define not just __ init, but let me define a second function in this class
这里 如下所示--
here, as follows--
定义__字符串__
def __ str __.
有两个
There are two.
尽管VS代码中的字体将这两个下划线放得如此之近
Even though the font in VS Code is putting the two underscore so close,
它看起来就像是一个更长的下划线
it just looks like a longer underscore.
确实有两个 在左边和右边 就像init一样
There are indeed two there, on the left and the right just like for init.
这一论点只有一个论点 按照惯例 总是被称为自我
This one only takes one argument that, by convention, is always called self
这样你就可以访问它了
so that you have access to it.
然后 在冒号后面缩进
And then, indented below that after a colon,
我将继续创建格式字符串并返回它
I'm going to go ahead and create a format string and return it.
所以让我继续下去 回到--
So let me go ahead and return--
不如先说个普通的词 比如“一个学生”
how about something generic first like "a student."
所以我甚至不会费心去找出
So I'm not going to bother even trying to figure out
这个学生的名字或住处是什么
what this student's name or house is.
我只会一直返回“一个学生”
I'm just going to always return "a student."
现在让我回到我之前的代码 它在第16行有print(Student)
Let me go back now to my earlier code, which has print (student) on line 16.
让我清除我的终端窗口 并重新运行Student.py的Python 回车
Let me clear my terminal window and rerun Python of student.py, Enter.
输入哈里 输入格兰芬多
Type in Harry, type in Gryffindor.
上一次 我看到了非常神秘的输出
Last time, I saw that very cryptic output.
这一次 我看到 更笼统地说 “一个学生”
This time, I see, more generically, "a student."
更具可读性 但不太有启发性
More readable but not very enlightening.
这是哪个学生？
Which student is this?
注意 双下划线字符串方法在这个self参数中接受
Well, notice that the double underscore str method takes in this self argument
默认情况下 这正是Python作者设计此方法的方式
by default. It's just the way the Python authors designed this method.
它将始终被传递一个对当前学生对象的引用
It will always be passed a reference to the current student object.
我这么说是什么意思？
What do I mean by that?
当调用第6行上的这行代码时
When this line of code on line 6 is called,
打印 因为它希望它会得到一个字符串
print, because it's hoping it's going to get a string,
将触发下划线、字符串、下划线
is going to trigger the underscore underscore, str, underscore
给要调用的方法加下划线
underscore method to be called.
对于您来说 Python将自动传递到该方法中
And Python, for you, automatically is going to pass into that method
引用正在尝试成为的对象
a reference to the object that's trying to be
打印出来 这样作为程序员 您就可以做这样的事情
printed so that you, the programmer, can do something like this.
和往常一样 这里有一个带有双引号的f字符串
Here's an f string with double quotes as usual.
我要用一些花括号 然后说打印出来
I'm going to use some curly braces and say print out
来自self.house的self.name
self.name from self.house.
所以我刚才所做的并没有什么新意
So there's nothing new in what I've just done.
这只是一个f弦--开头是f
It's just an f string-- an f on the beginning,
两个双引号 几对花括号
two double quotes, a couple of pairs of curly braces.
但这是因为 可以说 这个字符串方法会自动传递给自己
But because, automatically, this str method gets passed self, so to speak,
对当前对象的引用 我可以进入该对象的内部
a reference to the current object, I can go inside of that object
然后取下名字
and grab the name.
我可以再一次进入那个物体里面 然后拿到房子
I can go inside that object again and grab the house.
所以现在 当我回到我的终端窗口--
So now, when I go back to my terminal window--
此前 它只是打印出了一个学生
previously it just printed out a student.
但现在 如果我运行Student.py的Python 输入--
But now, if I run Python of student.py, Enter--
输入Harry 输入Gryffindor 然后再按一次Enter
type in Harry, type in Gryffindor, and one more time hit Enter,
哈利又是从格兰芬多来的
Harry is again from Gryffindor.
但如果我再运行一次--
But if I run this yet again--
比方说 德拉科来自斯莱特林 回车
let's, for instance, do Draco is from Slytherin, Enter.
德拉科来自斯莱特林
Draco's from Slytherin.
现在 它针对我们试图打印的特定对象进行了定制
Now it's customized to the specific object that we're trying to print.
关于这个功能的问题--
Questions on this function here--
此DUnder字符串方法
this Dunder str method.
观众：下划线还有什么要强调的吗？
AUDIENCE: Is there anything else that the underscore underscore,
字符串方法能做什么？
str method can do?
另一个问题是 str和epr之间有什么不同
The other question is, what's the difference between str and repr.
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
因此 还有许多其他方法随Python类一起提供
So there are many other methods that come with Python classes
这是以下划线开始的
that start with underscore underscore.
我们只是触及了皮毛 我们几乎会
We're just scratching the surface, and we'll pretty much
主要集中在这些方面
focus primarily on these.
但是 是的 还有很多其他的 我们会
But yes, there are many others, and we'll
至少在一小段时间内能看到另一个
see at least one other in just a little bit.
其中有一个名为REPR的软件 它是
Among the others is one called repr, which is
Python对象的表示形式
a representation of the Python object.
一般而言 下划线、REPR、
Generally speaking, the underscore underscore, repr,
下划线方法是给开发人员看的
underscore underscore method is meant for developers' eyes.
它通常比《格兰芬多来的哈利》有更多的信息
It typically has more information than "Harry from Gryffindor."
它还会说明它是什么类型的对象 比如学生、首都
It would also say what type of object it is, like a student, capital
S 而下划线、字符串、下划线通常是
S, whereas underscore underscore, str, underscore underscore is generally
面向用户--
meant for users--
该程序的用户 它的目的是更友好的用户
the users of the program, and it's meant to be even more user-friendly.
但这两个都可以在你认为合适的情况下被推翻
But both of those can be overridden as you see fit.
好吧 现在让我提议 我们继续我们停止的学生
Well, let me propose now that we pick up where we've left off on student
添加更多的功能 但不仅仅是这些特殊的方法
and just add even more functionality, but not just these special methods
如双下划线init和双下划线str
like double underscore init and double underscore str.
让我们创建我们自己的方法 因为这是真正的力量所在
Let's create our own methods because therein lies the real power
以及类的灵活性 如果你和我都是程序员
and flexibility of classes if you and I as the programmers
可以发明专门针对学生的新功能
can invent new functionality that's specific to students.
例如 霍格沃茨的学生 在校期间
For instance, students at Hogwarts, over the time in school,
学习如何施展某种类型的咒语
learn how to cast a certain type of spell.
所以当他们说 Expeto Patronum时
So when they say, Expecto Patronum, something
从他们的魔杖里出来的东西通常类似于
comes out of their wand that typically resembles
一种动物之类的东西
an animal or something like that.
这是一种特殊的咒语 他们必须练习和练习
It's a special spell that they have to practice and practice.
所以让我们看看我们是否不能存储 不仅仅是学生的名字和他们的房子
So let's see if we can't store, not just the student's name and their house,
还有他们的“守护神” 实际上 他们
but also their "patronus," what, actually, they
在使用这个咒语时召唤
conjure when using this spell.
好吧 让我继续清理我的终端窗口
Well, let me go ahead and clear my terminal window.
在我代码的顶部 在学生的init方法中 让我继续
And in the top of my code here, in the init method of Student, let me go ahead
并开始期待除了self之外的第三个参数 这会自动
and start expecting a third argument, in addition to self, which automatically
被传递进来 被称为守护神
gets passed in, called patronus.
现在 我不会担心 关于验证
And I'm not going to worry, for now, on validating
官方有效赞助人名单中的赞助人或赞助人
the patronus from an official list of valid patronuses, or patroni.
相反 我将继续并盲目地分配
I'm instead going to go ahead and just blindly assign
它属于自己 守护神=守护神 而我们
it to self.patronus = patronus, and we're
现在将允许用户输入他们想要的任何内容
going to let the user type whatever they want for now.
但是我当然可以添加更多的错误检查
But I could certainly add more error checking
如果我想把赞助人限制在这里的特定名单上
if I wanted to limit the patronus to a specific list of them here.
现在让我继续并提示用户输入此守护神
Let me go ahead now and prompt the user for this patronus,
在我的Get_Student函数中 通过定义一个变量
as by-- in my get_student function-- defining a variable
被称为守护神或其他任何东西 提示用户
called patronus or anything else, prompting the user
为他们的守护神提供意见
for input for their patronus.
现在我要继续 传递第三个变量
And now I'm going to go ahead and pass in that third variable here.
因此 在精神上类似于只是添加越来越多的属性
So again, similar in spirit to just adding more and more attributes
对全班同学来说 我要把三门课都通过
to the class, I'm going to pass in all three
而不是只有两个
of these values instead of just two.
我还不打算用这个值做任何有趣的事情
I'm not going to do anything interesting with that value yet.
但为了确保我不会因为破坏密码而让事情更糟
But just to make sure I haven't made things worse by breaking my code,
让我运行Student.py的Python
let me run Python of student.py.
我来打哈里
I'll type in Harry.
我会打进格兰芬多
I'll type in Gryffindor.
结果发现他的守护神是一只雄鹿
And it turns out his patronus was a stag, .
然后按回车键我还没有看到他的庇护在我的输出中是什么
And hit Enter I haven't seen what his patronus is in my output
因为我还没有更改我的str方法
because I didn't change my str method yet.
但至少我没有任何语法错误
But at least I don't have any syntax errors.
所以至少我没有让事情变得更糟
So at least I've not made anything worse.
但是假设 现在 我想要有功能 而不仅仅是
But suppose, now, I want to have functionality, not just
用于初始化学生并打印出学生
for initializing a student and printing out a student.
如果我的班级真的是一名学生 我能做的是
If my class is really meant to be a student, what I can do
不仅仅是记住有关学生数据的信息
is not just remember information about data about students.
与字典不同 课堂的强大之处在于
What's powerful about classes, unlike dictionaries alone,
is that classes can have, not just variables or instance variables--
those attributes we keep creating.
They can also have functions built in, a.k.a.
methods.
When a function is inside of a class, it's called a "method,"
but it's still just a function.
At this point, we've seen two functions already-- two methods--
called a double underscore init and double underscore str,
but those are special methods in that they just work.
If you define them, Python calls them automatically for you.
But what if you wanted to create more functionality for a student
so that your class really represents this real world, or maybe "fantasy"
world notion of a student, where students not only have names and houses
and patronuses; they also have functionality.
They have actions they can perform like casting a charm, a spell, magically.
Could we implement, therefore, a function called charm, that
actually uses their magical knowledge?
Well, let's go ahead and define our very own function as follows.
Let me clear my terminal window, scroll back up to my student class.
And instead of creating yet another function that's special,
with double underscores, I'm going to invent my own function, or method,
inside of this class.
I want to give Harry and Hermione and all of the other students
the ability to cast charms, so I'm going to define a function that I
can completely, on my own, call charm.
I could call this function anything I want.
But because it's a method inside of a class,
the convention is that it's always going to take at least one argument, called
self, by convention so that you have access to the current object,
even if you don't plan to use it, per se.
All right, let me go ahead and propose that we implement charm in such a way
that the method returns an emoji that's appropriate for each student's
patronus.
如何实现这一点--嗯 在Charm方法内部
How to implement this-- well, inside of the charm method,
让我们继续比赛吧 帕特诺斯
let's go ahead and match on self.patronus,
它是包含一个字符串的实例变量 该字符串
which is the instance variable containing a string that
代表每个学生的资助人
represents each student's patronus.
如果它与一只雄鹿匹配 例如 对于哈里 让我们继续
And in the case that it matches a stag, for instance, for Harry, let's go ahead
并返回最接近的表情符号--
and return maybe the closest emoji--
这匹马在这里
this horse here.
以水獭为例呢？
How about in the case of an otter?
好吧 那样的话 让我们继续回去吧 哦 也许是最接近的匹配
Well, in that case, let's go ahead and return, oh, maybe the closest match
这可能就是这个表情符号
to the otter, which might be this emoji here.
让我们看看 在a的情况下 对于罗恩 而不是赫敏
And let's see, in the case of a-- for Ron, rather than Hermione--
一只杰克·罗素梗犬 让我们继续前进并返回--
a Jack Russell terrier, let's go ahead and return--
在这里没有那么多的选择
don't have as many options here.
如果是那样的话 我们为什么不把最可爱的狗还回去呢？
Why don't we go ahead and return the cutest available dog in that case.
在不承认赞助人的情况下
And in the case of no patronus recognized,
就像覆盖像德拉科这样的人一样 我们继续
as might cover someone like Draco, let's go ahead
并像过去一样使用使用下划线的默认大小写
and use a default case using the underscore as in the past,
让我们继续下去 回到这个--哦 会发生什么
and let's go ahead and return for this-- oh, what should happen
如果有人没有守护神呢？
if someone doesn't have a patronus?
为什么我们不直接看看魔杖呢？
Why don't we just see a magical wand that
似乎失败了 就像这件事一样？
seems to fizzle out, as in this case?
好的 现在 与其只打印学生的照片
All right, well, now, rather than just print the student,
让我们开始打印他们的实际赞助人吧
let's go about printing their actual patronus.
因此 我将在这里介绍我的主要功能
So I'm going to go down to my main function here.
使用Get_Student函数 我仍将获得一名学生
I'm going to still get a student, using the get_student function.
但是 与其打印学生 不如让我们宣布“Exspecto Patronum！”
But rather than print student, let's go ahead and declare "Expecto Patronum!"
仅将其作为纯文本打印出来
printing out just that as pure text.
现在让我们继续打印出来 不是学生 而是
And now let's go ahead and print out, not the student but, rather,
返回值属于自己的魅力方法
the return value of their own charm method.
因此 让我返回到我的终端窗口并运行Student.py的Python
So let me go back down to my terminal window and run Python of student.py
然后进入
and Enter.
名字--让我们从哈里开始
Name-- let's start with Harry.
他住在格兰芬多
He lives in Gryffindor.
守护神是只雄鹿
Patronus is a stag.
让我们来看看--
And let's see--
期待守护神！
Expecto Patronum!
当然 我们还会看到雄鹿表情符号
And of course, we'd see the stag emoji.
像德拉科这样的人呢 至少在书上是这样的
What about someone like Draco, who, at least in the books,
没有已知的守护神？
doesn't have a known patronus?
好吧 让我们继续清理我的终端窗口
Well, let's go ahead and clear my terminal window,
重新运行Student.py的Python 这一次 让我们键入Draco作为名称
rerun Python of student.py, and this time, let's type in Draco for name,
斯莱特林为豪斯 守护神未知
Slytherin for house, and Patronus is unknown.
所以我要继续按Enter键
So I'm just going to go ahead and hit Enter.
现在 Expeto Patronum！
And now, Expecto Patronum!
取而代之的是 它只发出了嘶嘶声
And it just of sizzles instead.
好吧 让我提议 现在 我们删除这个守护神代码
Well, let me propose, now, that we remove this patronus code just
简化我们的世界 专注于其他一些核心
to simplify our world and focus on some of the other core
类的能力
capabilities of classes.
所以冒着让人失望的风险 我要去
So at the risk of disappointing, I'm going
为了摆脱所有这些美丽的表情符号和魅力
to get rid of all of these beautiful emoji and charms,
我要继续下去 现在停止向用户索要他们的守护神
and I'm going to go ahead and stop asking the user now for their patronus.
我不会再把它传递给init了
And I'm going to stop passing it into init here.
我在这里不会再这么做了
And I'm going to stop doing this here.
我要继续 恢复我们对印刷品的使用 学生
And I'm going to instead just go ahead and restore our use of print student
在这里 我要继续下去 摆脱这里的守护神
here, and I'm going to go ahead and get rid of patronus down here.
所以 从根本上说 只要取消我们刚刚创造的所有有趣的魅力
So just essentially undo all of the fun charms we just created.
所以我们现在回到故事的这一点 我们有一个学生班
So we're now back at the point in the story where we have a student class,
只有两种方法--
with only two methods--
Init和str.
init and str.
当然 第一个镜头是赛尔夫
The first of those takes, of course, self
像往常一样 第一个论点 加上另外两个--名字和房子
as the first argument as it always will, plus two more now-- name and house,
不再有守护神了
no more patronus.
我们正在验证上面的名字
We're validating name up here.
我们在这下面验证豪斯
We're validating house down here.
然后我们会分别指定名字和房子
And then we're assigning name and house, respectively,
也称为name和house的两个实例变量
to two instance variables called name and house also.
但我们使用SELF来访问当前对象
But we use self to get access to the current object,
将这些值存储在其中
to store those values therein.
然后我们在这里仍然有我们的str方法 它接受一个参数--
We then still have our str method here, which takes one argument--
默认情况下是Self 仅此而已
by default, self, and that's it.
该函数将在任何时候被自动调用
And that function is going to be called automatically any time
您想要将学生对象转换为字符串
you want to convert a student object to a string,
就像印刷品在这里可能想要做的那样
just like print might want to do here.
所以让我继续下去 只是确保我没有打碎任何东西
So let me go ahead and just make sure I haven't broken anything.
让我运行Student.py的Python
Let me run Python of student.py.
我来打哈里
I'll type in Harry.
我会输入格兰芬多 回车
I'll type in Gryffindor, Enter.
好了 我们又开始营业了
OK, we're back in business.
魅力和守护神消失了 但至少我又回到了一个
Gone are the charms and patronus, but at least I'm back to a situation
我有名字和房子的地方
where I have names and houses.
但事实证明 目前 我们对类的使用
But it turns out, at the moment, our use of classes
并不是很强健 尽管我们有这个机制 非常聪明
is not very robust, even though we have this mechanism, very cleverly,
如果可以的话 在我们的初始方法中
if I may, in our init method of making sure
我们正在验证名字和房子 确保名字不是空的
that we're validating name and house, making sure that name is not blank,
并确保这所房子是霍格沃茨四所房子中的一所有效的房子
and making sure that house is a valid house among those four Hogwarts houses.
事实证明 课程仍然会让我
It turns out that classes will still let me
获取那些属性 那些所谓的实例变量
get at those attributes, those so-called instance variables,
无论如何都要用点符号
using dot notation anyway.
那么让我向下滚动 试着以一种相反的方式来做这件事
Let me scroll down then and try to do this a little adversarially.
假设在线16我继续调用Get_Student
Suppose that online 16 I go ahead and call get_student,
和以前一样存在 然后我将返回值存储在一个学生
which exists as before, and then I store the return value in a student
变量--同样在第16行
variable-- again, on line 16.
这将确保Get_Student被调用 它调用输入和输入
That will ensure that get_student gets called, which calls input and input.
然后它调用学生构造函数
And then it calls the student constructor,
它自动调用该init方法
which invokes, automatically, this init method.
因此 通过我们如何布局我的代码 我们
So by way of how we've laid out my code, we're
要确保名字不是空的 房子肯定是
going to ensure that name is not blank and house is definitely
这四个值之一
one of those four values.
我的纠错--或者说错误检查已经到位
My error correction-- or error checking is in place.
但如果我有一点敌意 我仍然可以绕过它
But if I'm a little adversarial, I can still circumvent it.
假设--好吧 需要我输入哈利和格兰芬多吗？
Suppose that-- fine, going to require me to type in Harry and Gryffindor?
我要继续输入Student.house
I'm going to go ahead and type in student.house
等于 引号 引号 “女贞路四号 ”
equals, quote, unquote, "Number Four, Privet Drive,"
你阻止不了我的
and you're not going to be able to stop me.
为什么？
Why?
嗯 事实证明 使用类和对象
Well, it turns out, with classes and objects
因此 您和我仍然可以访问这些实例变量
thereof, you and I can still access those instance variables
使用这个熟悉的点符号
using this familiar dot notation.
这就是我们如何开始类的故事--只需设置这些属性
That's how we began the story of classes-- just setting these attributes
我们自己
ourselves.
但您也可以读取这些属性本身
But you can also read these attributes themselves
如果你想的话以后再换
and change them later if you want.
这将有效地绕过IF条件和另一个IF条件
And this will effectively circumvent the if condition and the other if condition
在我们的init方法中 因为只有当你第一次
in our init method because that is only called when you first
创建学生对象
create the student object.
现在没有什么能阻止我
There's nothing stopping me, at the moment,
从只是改变房子或名字后
from just changing the house or the name after.
所以如果我现在清除终端窗口并运行student.py的Python
So if I now clear my terminal window and run Python of student.py,
我还是会输入哈利和格兰芬多来满足我的要求
I'll still type in Harry and Gryffindor to meet my requirements
这房子是这四个之一
that the house be one of those four.
但是当它被打印出来的时候 注意 我还是覆盖了它
But when it's printed, notice, I've still overridden it.
因此 虽然类确实允许我们对数据进行更多的控制
So it seems that, while classes do allow us a little more control over the data
我们储存的信息 并不一定能阻止用户--
we're storing, it doesn't necessarily prevent the user--
或者更确切地说是程序员--可能是我自己 也可能是同事
or rather the programmer-- be it myself or maybe a colleague,
把事情搞砸
from still messing things up.
在这里 同样 本着编程的精神
So here, too, in the spirit of programming a little more
为了防御 请允许我介绍Python的另一个特性--
defensively, allow me to introduce another feature of Python as well--
即财产
namely properties.
所以属性实际上只是一个属性
So a property is really just an attribute
有更多的防御机制
that has even more defense mechanisms put into place,
多一点的功能 防止像我这样的程序员
a little more functionality implemented by you to prevent programmers, like me
还有你 把这些属性搞砸了
and you, from messing things up like these attributes.
同样 属性是一个属性 你和我只是
So again, a property is going to be an attribute that you and I just
有更多的控制权
have more control over.
怎么做？
How?
我们只是使用一些Python约定编写了更多的代码
We just write a little more code, using some Python conventions.
我们要做的是 马上 使用一个功能--
And how we're going to do that is going to use, in just a moment, a feature--
一个名为@property的关键字 从技术上讲 它是一个函数
a keyword known as @property, which is technically a function.
属性是Python中的一个函数
Property is a function in Python.
但是我们即将看到一些新的@语法 它允许你装饰函数
But we're about to see some new @ syntax that allows you to decorate functions.
这也是一种艺术术语
And this, too, is a term of art.
在Python的世界里 你可以有装饰器
In the world of Python, you can have decorators,
它们是修改其他函数的行为的函数
which are functions that modify the behavior of other functions,
如果你愿意的话 我们就不谈这个了 不谈太多的杂草
if you will, and we'll leave it at that without going too much into the weeds.
我们将通过例子来了解如何使用这些装饰器
And we'll see, by, example how you can use these decorators,
特别是定义属性
specifically to define properties.
让我们回到VS Code
So let me go back to VS Code here.
我建议我来做
And let me propose that I do this.
我要继续下去 创造--
I'm going to go ahead and create--
一个叫房子的房产怎么样 如下所示
how about a property called house as follows.
在我的学生课堂上 我将继续--在我的init方法下面
Inside of my student class, I'm going to go ahead-- and below my init method
在我str方法下面 我将继续定义
and below my str method, I'm going to go ahead and define
一个名为house的函数 它总是至少接受一个参数
a function called house that takes, as it always must, one argument at least,
叫赛尔夫
called self.
我现在要做的就是把自己送回去
And what I'm going to do now is return self.house.
所以我只需要定义一个名为
So I'm just going to define a method called
房子 其生活的唯一目的是返还房子的价值
house, whose sole purpose in life is to return the value of house.
但我将定义另一种方法 奇怪的是 它也被称为House
But I'm going to define one other method, curiously also called house,
但作为论据 这将涉及到两个价值观--
but that's going to take into, as arguments, two values--
一如既往的自我 也有一种叫房子的价值
self as always and also a value called house.
现在我要这样做了
And I'm going to now do this.
我要自己动手
I'm going to do self.house = house.
现在 我做了什么？
Now, what have I done?
那么 让我暂时在这里补充一些评论
Well, let me just temporarily add some comments here.
稍后 我们将开始泛泛地提到这一点
In a moment, we're going to start referring to this generally
作为一名吸毒者
as a getter.
在这里 我将把这称为二传手
And down here, I'm going to refer to this as a setter.
这是在Java世界中经常看到的术语
And this is terminology frequently see in the world of Java.
你们中的一些人以前用Java编程过
Some of you have programmed in Java before.
但是顾名思义 getter是一个函数
But as the names imply, a getter is a function
对于获得某些属性的类
for a class that gets some attributes.
Setter是某个类中设置某些值的函数
A setter is a function in some class that sets some value.
现在 尽管我们还没有完成 代码中有一点错误
And now, even though we're not done, and there's a bit of a mistake in the code
直觉上 我已经写过了 我们要做的是
I've already written, intuitively, what we're going to do is this.
我们正在努力防止程序员 包括我自己
We're trying to prevent programmers, myself included,
避免我的错误检查 即我
from circumventing my error checking that I
把名字和房子放在适当的位置
put into place for name and house.
我怎么能做到这一点？
How can I do that?
嗯 我们在编程方面没有那么多的积木
Well, we don't have that many building blocks in programming.
我们有数据的变量 我们有行动的函数
We have things like variables for data, and we have functions for actions.
好吧 为什么我们不这样做呢？
Well, why don't we do this?
为什么我们不以某种方式要求 为了访问属性
Why don't we somehow require that, in order to access an attribute,
你要经历一些功能
you go through some function.
让我们要求 为了设置一些属性
And let's require that, in order to set some attribute,
你要经历一些功能
you go through some function.
通常 这些函数称为getter函数和setter函数
And conventionally, those functions are called a getter function and a setter
功能
function.
为什么我们要在类中使用函数或方法呢？
And why are we using functions or, in this case, methods inside of a class?
嗯 一旦你有了功能 这些就只是动作或动词
Well, once you have functions, those are just actions or verbs
你和我可以创造我们自己
that you and I can create ourselves.
我们可以在这些函数中添加我想要的任何纠错
We can put any error correction I want in these functions
因为这是要从上到下执行的代码
because it's code that's going to get executed top to bottom.
那么 我现在如何防止用户将房屋设置为无效值呢？
So how can I now prevent the user from setting the house to an invalid value?
让我借用前面的一些逻辑 而不是盲目地这样做--只需设置
Let me borrow some logic from before rather than blindly do this-- just set
Self.house等于传入的房屋价值--让我们加上我们的错误
self.house equal to the house value that's passed in-- let's add our error
在那里检查
checking there.
因此 如果豪斯不在格兰芬多或赫奇帕奇的以下名单中
So if house is not in the following list of Gryffindor or Hufflepuff
或者拉文克劳或斯莱特林 就像以前一样
or Ravenclaw or Slytherin, just as before,
让我们继续引发一个值错误 只是为了表示 嗯-嗯 某件事
let's go ahead and raise a value error, just to signify that, uh-uh, something
出了问题
has gone wrong.
我会说得更清楚些
I'll be more explicit.
我会加上一条消息 比如 “无效的房子 ”引用 不引用
I'll include a message like, "invalid house," quote, unquote.
否则 我将继续 现在 第21行 设置自己 挨家挨户
Otherwise, I'm going to proceed on, now, line 21 to set self.house to house.
所以我只是复制了 或者重新输入了我的错误检查
So I've just copied, if you will, or retyped my error checking inside
这个所谓的setter函数
of this so-called setter function.
现在 我为什么要这么做？
Now, why have I done that?
明确地说 每当用户或程序员
Well, to be clear, whenever the user or the programmer
像这样写代码 Student.house等于 什么是
writes code like this, student.house equals, what's
即将神奇地发生的是 Python将不仅仅是
about to happen magically is Python will not just
让程序员直接访问学生宿舍--该属性
let the programmer access student house directly-- that attribute,
那个实例变量 也就是
that instance variable, a.k.a.
自己的房子
self house.
取而代之的是它会神奇地自动调用
It's instead going to magically automatically call
这个定时器对我来说很有作用
this setter function for me.
Python是如何知道要这样做的？
How does Python know to do that?
嗯 如果是这样的话 在左手边 有自己的房子
Well, if it's see that, on the left-hand side, there is self.house,
其中house是获取者或二传者的名字 然后它看到一个等号
where house is the name of the getter or setter, and then it sees an equal sign,
指示任务 这只是一个足够的视觉线索说
indicating assignment, that's just enough of a visual clue to say,
等一下
wait a minute.
我不会让您直接访问该属性
I'm not going to let you access that attribute directly.
我将改用定位器
I'm going to use the setter instead.
为什么？
Why?
因为等号表示我在试着设置
Because the equal sign means I'm trying to set.
我正在尝试将一个从右到左的值赋给该属性
I'm trying to assign a value from right to left into that attribute.
因此 Python将自动执行的操作
So what Python's is going to do automatically
就是为我调用这个函数
is call this function for me.
这很令人惊讶 因为现在我可以执行代码--一个用于检查的算法
And that's amazing because now I can execute code-- an algorithm to check,
我想让用户--
do I want to let the user--
程序员是否将该属性设置为该值？
the programmer set that attribute to that value?
如果不是 我将引发一个值错误
If not, I'm going to raise a value error,
你就是做不到
and you're just not going to be able to do it.
如果真是这样的话
If so fine.
我去给您安排一下
I'll go ahead and set it for you.
但为了做到这一点 我们需要更多的语法
But in order to do this, we need a little more syntax.
我要去掉我的评论 我要用那个装饰物
And I'm going to get rid of my comment, and I'm going to use that decorator.
我需要告诉Python将此方法作为一个getter来处理
I need to tell Python to treat this method as a getter.
然后 setter的语法略有不同
And then the syntax for the setter is a little different.
你现在说的是house.setter
You now say house.setter.
我希望一个是得到者 另一个是塞特人
I wish one was getter and the other was setter.
这不是他们设计的方式
That's not the way they designed it.
当您想定义一个getter时 只需在函数上方加上@Property即可
When you want to define a getter, you just say @property above the function.
并且您可以完全按照您希望的属性来命名函数
And you name the function exactly like you would like the property
被称为--引用 引用 “房子 ”
to be called-- quote, unquote, "house."
这样做之后 您现在就可以使用新的装饰器了
Once you do that, you can now use a new decorator
它是自动为您创建的 名为@House
that's automatically created for you called @house,
因为我叫它房子
because I called it house.
然后你字面上说 @house.setter
And then you literally say, @house.setter.
而这一整行 在第17行 是关于Python的线索
And this whole line, on line 17, is a clue to Python
这就是一个名称完全相同的函数--
that here comes a function, whose name is identical--
但请注意 它需要两个参数--都是self 所以您可以访问
but notice that it takes two arguments-- both self, so you have access
对象的内容 和房子 这是公正的
to the contents of the object, and house, which is just
将是来自程序员的字符串 来自人工输入返回
going to be a str that comes from the programmer from the human input return
值 以便您也可以设置该值
value so that you can set that value as well.
但我现在有一个问题需要解决 就是这里
But there's one fix I need to make now, here.
我认为 其他一切都还不错
Everything else, I think, is still good.
然而 看看这个
However watch this.
我在这里不再需要这个错误检查
I no longer need this error check here.
为什么？
Why?
因为 如果我向下滚动到我的代码
Because, if I scroll back down to my code here,
我刚才声称 像这样的代码 带有Student.house等于
I claimed a moment ago that code like this, with student.house equals,
会自动让Python为我调用我的setter
is going to automatically get Python to call my setter for me.
你猜怎么着？
Guess what?
即使在这里 在我的init方法中 调用self.house也等于
Even up here, in my init method, calling self.house equals
还将调用我的setter方法 这很令人惊讶
is also going to call my setter method, which is amazing
因为现在我可以将所有错误检查保存在setter中的一个位置
because now I can keep all of my error checking in one place in the setter,
当我第一次创建对象时 它现在将被调用
and it will now get called either when I create the object for the first time,
因为init 或者即使程序员
because of init, or even if the programmer
尝试绕过init方法并更改该属性值
tries to circumvent that init method and change the value of this attribute,
我的二传手也会被叫来
my setter will also get called.
每当我访问.house时 我的setter都会被调用
My setter will get called any time I access .house.
但有一件事我需要解决
But there's one fix I need to make.
不幸的是 我的名字有冲突
Unfortunately, I have collided names.
现在 如果我们往上走 在第5行 这是一个实例变量
Right now, if we go up here, on line 5, this is an instance variable.
它是我自己内部的一个字符串 在当前的学生对象内部
It's a string inside of my self, inside of the current student object,
骂人的名字
called name.
这是另一个名为house的实例变量
And this is another instance variable called house.
不幸的是 如果我有一个名为name and house的实例变量
Unfortunately, if I have an instance variable called name and house,
我不能同时拥有称为House的功能
I cannot also have functions called house.
它们将会相撞
They're going to collide.
你必须做出决定
You've got to decide.
是否要将该变量命名为house？
Do you want the variable to be called house?
或者 您希望将该功能命名为House？
Or do you want the function to be called house?
不幸的是 你不能两者兼得 因为现在
Unfortunately, you can't have both because now Python
会把其中一个混淆为另一个
is going to confuse one for the other.
因此 传统的解决办法是这样做--
So the conventional fix for this is to do this--
为了让setter不存储在self.house中传递的值
to have the setter not store the value that's passed in self.house,
但使用一个几乎相同的名字 但使用一个小指示器
but to use an almost identical name, but to use a little indicator that
意味着你知道这样做是正确的
means you know doing this correctly.
按照惯例 您通常会加下划线
You typically, by convention, put an underscore
在实例变量的名称前面
in front of the instance variable's name.
当你在这里返回它的时候 你同样会加一个下划线
And when you return it up here, you similarly put an underscore.
所以现在 从技术上讲 我的实例变量名为_house
So now, technically, my instance variable is called _house,
但我的财产 这是一个更华丽的属性 如果你愿意的话
but my property, which is a fancier attribute, if you will,
叫孤家寡人
is called house alone.
我知道语法量很大 但它是一个非常强大的功能
Huge amount of syntax, I know, but it's a very powerful feature.
这也是为什么你可以从字典中毕业
And again, this is why you can graduate from dictionaries alone and have
更多功能任您使用
so much more functionality at your disposal.
让我继续清理我的终端窗口 运行student.py的Python
Let me go ahead and clear my terminal window and run Python of student.py,
输入姓名
Enter, name.
好吧 让我们继续输入哈里
All right, let's go ahead and type in Harry.
让我们继续输入格兰芬多
Let's go ahead and type in Gryffindor.
像往常一样交叉手指
Crossing my fingers as always.
而现在 看 "病人的房子.“
And now, look, "Invalid house."
这是好事
This is a good thing.
为什么要这样？
Why?
因为 注意 在我的主函数中
Because, notice, in my main function, I'm
仍然试图 恶意地 如果你愿意 改变哈利的房子
still trying, maliciously, if you will, to change Harry's house
不属于四个有效之一
to not be one of the four valid ones.
我想把它改成他童年的家女贞路四号
I'm trying to change it to his childhood home of Number Four, Privet Drive.
但是因为Python知道 等一下 你要分配--
But because Python knows that, wait a minute, you're trying to assign--
也就是说 设定一个值--
that is, set a value--
这个值也就是房屋 现在被定义为
and that value, a.k.a. house, is now defined
作为一个属性 你将不得不通过setter函数
as a property you're going to have to go through the setter function instead
让你改变这个值
to even let you change that value.
因为我有这个加薪ValueError
And because I have this raise ValueError.
如果房子不像预期的那样
If the house is not as intended, you're not
将被允许将其更改为无效值
going to be allowed to change it to an invalid value.
所以我通过init方法在进入的过程中保护数据
So I'm protecting the data on the way in, through the init method,
如果你试图在那里覆盖它 我甚至会为数据辩护
and I'm even defending the data if you try to override it there.
所以我认为对我这个程序员来说
So I think the only solution for me, the programmer,
别试图破解我的密码
is, don't try to break my own code.
让我把这句话去掉 因为它不起作用
Let me remove that line because it's just not going to work.
让我运行student.py的Python 再次输入Harry;
Let me run Python of student.py and, again, type in Harry;
输入格兰芬多 回车 哈利确实是格兰芬多的
type in Gryffindor, Enter, and Harry's indeed from Gryffindor.
如果我做错了什么 就像《四号》里的哈利
If I did something incorrect, like Harry from Number Four,
女贞路 回车 我们再次看到值错误
Privet Drive, Enter, we're again going to see the value error
因为我的代码不允许手动输入这个值
because my code just doesn't let that value in via manual input now
或者通过这种对抗性的变化
or via that adversarial change.
好吧 这是很多
All right, that was a lot.
关于财产有什么问题吗？
But any question on properties?
问：为什么我们使用getter 然后使用setter？
AUDIENCE: Why we are using getter then setter?
只是为了让我们能找到
It's just for the purpose so that we can find
那个方法 我们代码中的函数
that method, that function in our code.
大卫·J·马兰：我之所以要费力去定义
DAVID J. MALAN: The reason that I'm going through the trouble of defining
这个getter或setter是因为我想确保程序员不能
this getter or setter is because I want to make sure that programmers cannot do
诸如此类的事情
things like this.
如果我正在经历验证的麻烦
If I'm going through the trouble of validating
这些学生对象的属性
the attributes for these student objects,
我不希望你能进去 随意更改它们
I don't want you to be able to go in there and just change them at will.
我想要对那个物体有一定的控制权
I want to have some control over that object
这样你就可以相信它会像设计的那样正确
so that you can just trust that it's going to be correct as designed.
所以使用getter和setter实际上只是启用了
So using a getter and setter really just enables
当您尝试手动设置值时 可以自动检测到这一点
Python to automatically detect when you're trying to manually set a value.
等号和圆点 就像我在这里强调的
The equal sign and the dot, as I've highlighted here,
足以让我们意识到 等一下
is enough of a clue to Python to realize, wait a minute,
你在试着设定一个价值
you're trying to set a value.
让我看看这个类是否定义了setter
Let me see if this class has a setter defined.
如果是这样的话 我会把它称为 我不仅仅是
And if so, I'm going to call that, and I'm not just
从右到左盲目赋值
going to blindly assign the value from right to left.
所以它只是给了我更多的控制权
So it's just giving me more control.
关于属性的其他问题
Other questions on properties.
听众：当我们使用getter时 我们只有一个参数
AUDIENCE: When we use getters, we just have just one argument.
如果我们使用setter 它总是会有两个参数？
And if we use setters, it's always going to be two arguments?
这正常吗？
Is that normal?
大卫·J·马兰：正确
DAVID J. MALAN: Correct.
永远只有一个争论--自我
It's always going to be one argument-- self
对于getter setter有两个参数--self和其他东西
for the getter, two arguments for the setter-- self and something else.
直觉是 如果你得到了一个价值
And the intuition for that is, if you're getting a value,
您不需要传入任何其他内容 因为您已经知道该对象
you don't need to pass anything else in because you already know the object.
在这种情况下 它被称为学生
It's called student in this case.
所以你只需要得到这处房产的价值
So you're just going to get the value of that property.
但如果要将该属性设置为其他值
But if you want to set the property to something else,
你必须把这一论点传递出去
you've got to pass in that argument.
您必须传入要为其设置的值
You've got to pass in the value to which you want to set it.
所以它总是0或1
So it's always 0 or 1.
但是 您可以将其视为1或2 因为同样 类中的任何函数
However, you see it as 1 or 2 because, again, any function inside of a class,
也就是
a.k.a.
一个方法 将自动传递给您自己 这样您就可以访问
a method, is going to be automatically passed self so that you have access
到内存中的当前对象
to that current object in memory.
另一个关于房产的问题怎么样？
How about one other question on properties?
观众：为什么我们没有使用相同的下划线房屋初始化方法？
AUDIENCE: Why didn't we use the same underscore house init method?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
所以即使我在我的二传手里用的是下划线的房子
So even though I'm using the underscore house here, in my setter,
下划线的房子在我的吸尘器里
and the underscore house here, in my getter,
我故意不在这里用它
I deliberately did not use it up here.
原因是 通过使用self.house和这个等号
The reason for that is that, by using self.house and this equal sign,
这与我希望Python识别的模式是相同的
that's the same pattern that I want Python to recognize.
我希望Python自动调用setter
I want Python to automatically call the setter,
即使当我通过init方法进入房子时也是如此
even when I'm passing in the house via the init method.
如果我改变这一点来做这件事 那就绕过了二传手
If I were to change this to do this, that would circumvent the setter,
现在 无论如何 在init中都没有错误签入
and now there's no error checking in init whatsoever.
因此 这是一条如此微妙的界线
So it's such a fine line.
唯一阻碍我们进行错误检查或不进行错误检查的事情
The only thing standing between us and error checking or no error checking
是有没有这个下划线
is the presence or absence of this underscore.
但这是通常的惯例
But that's typically the convention.
通过不使用那里的下划线 确保
By not using the underscore there, make sure
即使是这项任务也要经过设定者
that even that assignment goes through the setter
所以 老实说 我 不必复制粘贴同样的错误
so that, honestly, I, don't have to copy paste the same error
入住两个地方
checking in two places.
我可以把它放在二传手里
I can put it just in the setter.
所以这是一个更好的设计 这就是为什么我一开始手动重新打字的原因
So it's a better design, and that's why I manually retyped it at first,
但后来我把它从init中删除了
but then I deleted it from init.
好吧 请允许我提议我们对这份文件做另一项修改
Well, allow me to propose that we make one other change to this file.
不妨继续为名称定义一个属性
Might as well go ahead and define a property for name as well.
让我继续做这件事--也许是在房产上方
And let me go ahead and do this-- maybe above the house property
只是为了让事情保持在我之前定义的相同顺序
just to keep things in the same order as I defined them earlier.
让我给自己另一处房产吧
Let me give myself another property.
这一次将被称为名字
This one is going to be called name.
它将一如既往地采用一个叫做自我的论点
It's going to take one argument called self, as always.
与此非常相似的是 这个函数将返回self._name
And this one, very similarly, is just going to return self._name.
所以我会预料到我会去
So I'm going to anticipate that I'm going
还必须重命名名称 这样我就不会发生与
to have to rename name also so that I don't have that same collision as
在此之前
before.
但现在让我继续定义另一个二传手--
But now let me go ahead and define another setter--
这是名字的名字
this one for name.
因此 约定为@name.setter
So the convention is @name.setter.
为什么要取这个名字？
Why name?
因为我刚刚创建的属性名为Name
Because the property I just created is called name.
因此 如果您愿意的话 getter和setter以这种方式协同工作
So the getter and setter work in conjunction in this way, if you will.
让我们使用名称setter来定义另一个函数
Let me go down under that name setter and define another function,
也叫名字
also called name.
但这里的关键是 它们并不完全相同
But the key thing here is that it's not identical.
它不是完全相同的函数名称和完全相同的参数数量
It's not the exact same function name and the exact same number of arguments.
同样 setter接受第二个参数
The setter, again, takes a second argument.
我可以随心所欲地叫它 但我
And I can call it anything I want, but I'm
我要给它起个名字 因为这就是传入的东西
going to call it name because that's what's being passed in.
我要把我的错误检查放在这里
And I'm going to put my error checking here.
如果不是名称 就像我们以前所做的那样 让我们继续并引发一个值错误
If not name, just like we used to do, let's go ahead and raise a value error,
让我们加上一条解释性的信息 比如“缺少名字” 引用 不引用
and let's put an explanatory message like "Missing name," quote, unquote.
否则 让我们继续并将self._name更新为等名
Otherwise, let's go ahead and update self._name to equal name.
而且我不需要改变它的名字 只是为了摆脱它
And I don't have to change init except to get rid
重复错误检查 因为 再一次
of this duplicate error checking now because, again,
如果我使用self.name等于这里 使用self.house等于这里
if I use self.name equals here and self.house equals here
没有下划线 这两个作业
with no underscore, both of those assignments
现在我们来看看我的两个setter函数
are going to go through my two setter functions now.
在我们开始之前 让我继续删除
Before we run this, let me go ahead and remove
这个敌对的代码 我们知道它不会起作用 因为我们正在捕获它
this adversarial code, which we know won't work because we're catching it.
让我返回到我的终端窗口并运行Student.py的Python
Let me go back down to my terminal window and run Python of student.py,
进来吧
Enter.
让我们输入哈里
Let's type in Harry.
让我们输入格兰芬多
Let's type in Gryffindor.
这似乎奏效了
And that seems to work.
不过 让我们再次尝试运行Student.py的Python
Let's try though, again, to run Python of student.py
和来自女贞路四号的哈里
with Harry from Number Four, Privet Drive.
这是行不通的
This will not work.
无效房屋的值错误 因为这不是
A value error with invalid house, because that's not
霍格沃茨的四所房子中的一所
one of the four Hogwarts houses.
现在 为了更好地衡量 让我们再运行一次
And now, for good measure, let's run it one more time.
我们甚至都不给它起个名字
And let's not even give it a name.
出现提示时 我们只需按Enter键即可
Let's just hit Enter when prompted.
我可以为房子打任何东西
I can type anything for the house.
我继续 格兰芬多 请进
I'll go ahead and still give it Gryffindor, Enter.
现在我们得到另一个值错误 但这个错误是因为缺少名称
And now we get another value error, but this one is for missing name.
所以我们现在似乎有了更多的防御机制
So we seem, now, to have all the more of a defense mechanism in place
确保这个名字符合我们的预期
to ensure that name is as we expect.
它必须有非空的值
It's got to have some value that's not blank.
房子也如我们所料
And house is as we expect.
它必须有这四个值之一
It's got to have one of those four values.
但冒着戳破每个人的泡沫的风险
But at the risk of bursting everyone's bubble
让你想知道 为什么我们要经历这一切
and making you wonder, why did we just go through all of that,
不幸的是 Python真正关注的是约定 而不是硬约束
unfortunately Python really focuses on conventions, not hard constraints.
我说的是这个
And by that, I mean this.
如果我在第30行找到一个学生后
If I go back into my main function after I've gotten a student on line 30
我试着用相反的方式做一些事情--student.house等于
and I try to adversarially do something like this-- student.house equals
“女贞路四号”我们知道
"Number Four, Privet Drive," we know this
因为我的家犬会被传染的
won't work because my setter for house is going to catch this.
再看一遍
Watch again.
Python的student.py
Python of student.py.
让我们输入哈里
Let's type in Harry.
让我们输入格兰芬多 这至少会通过
Let's type in Gryffindor, which will at least pass
我们的检查由init引发
our check that's induced by init.
但是第31行将触发调用同一个setter
But line 31 is going to trigger the same setter to be called,
我们会抛出一个值错误 说“无效的房子 “
and we're going to raise a value error saying "Invalid house."
不幸的是 如果你们中的一些人已经
Unfortunately, and if some of you are already
想想你能做什么
thinking a little adversarially, tragically, look what you can do.
你可以改变.房子是._房子
You can change .house to be ._house.
为什么要这样？
Why?
实例变量现在被称为_house
Well, the instance variable is now called _house.
房子的名字是house 没有下划线
The property is called house, no underscore.
但是作为实例变量实现的基础属性仍然被调用
But the underlying attribute implemented as an instance variable is still called
_房子
_house.
可悲的是 学生的Python
And tragically, Python of student.py.
让我们输入哈里
Let's type in Harry.
我们输入格兰芬多 这是正确的
Let's type in Gryffindor, which is correct.
但看看现在发生了什么
But watch what happens now.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我们溜过去
We slip through.
那么我强调的重点是什么呢
So what was the point of all of this emphasis from me
用“正确的方式”来做事情 Python的快速方式是让这个getter
on doing things the "right way," the Python quick way by having this getter
setter？
and setter?
与Java等语言不同
Well, unlike languages like Java, that just
防止你做这样的事情 Python
prevent you from doing things like this, Python
它本身允许您指定某些实例变量可以
itself allows you to specify that certain instance variables can
是公开的 任何人的代码都可以访问 或者是受保护的
be public and accessible to anyone's code, or protected,
或私有 这意味着其他任何人都不能更改这些值
or private, which means that no one else should be able to change these values.
在Python的世界里 这只是一个荣誉系统
In the world of Python, it's just the honor system.
它并没有融入到语言本身中
It's not baked into the language itself that there's
可见性的概念 公共的或私人的 甚至介于两者之间的某个地方
a notion of visibility, public or private or even somewhere in between
受到保护
protected.
取而代之的是 你在荣誉体系中
Instead, you're on the honor system.
通常的惯例是 如果一个实例
And the convention generally is, if an instance
变量以下划线开头 请不要碰它
variable starts with an underscore, please don't touch it.
就是不要
Just don't.
如果你碰了那个变量 弄坏了东西 那就怪你了
That's on you if you touch that variable and break things.
下划线表示约定
The underscore is meant to signify a convention
这本应是“私人的” 但它真的只是
that this is meant to be "private," but it really just
意思是 请不要碰这个
means, please don't touch this.
有时 如果有两个下划线 你可以使用
Sometimes, if there's two underscores, which you can use,
同样 这也是程序员们更大的努力 他们说
too, that's an even greater effort by programmers to say,
真的不要碰这个
really don't touch this.
但从技术上讲 没有什么能阻止你或我
But technically speaking, there's nothing stopping you or me
绕过所有这些机制 这些特性
from circumventing all of these mechanisms, these properties,
这些获得者和二传者
these getters and setters.
我们最终只是在荣誉系统上
We're ultimately just on the honor system
当我们看到实例变量以1为前缀时 不要这样做
not to do so when we see instance variables prefixed with one,
或者甚至是两个下划线
or perhaps even two underscores.
好了 这是一下子做了很多事--
All right, so this is a lot all at once--
这是面向对象编程的入门
this Introduction to object-oriented programming.
但这可能会让人相当惊讶 即使我们
But it might come as quite a surprise that, even though we
在过去的几周里可能已经认出了OOP的名字
might have identified OOP by name in weeks past,
在这堂课上 我们已经使用类和对象好几个星期了
we've all been using classes and objects for weeks now in this class.
事实上 如果你回想一下我们在这堂课上做的第一件事
In fact, if you think back on one of the very first things we did in this class,
我们使用了整数 只是从用户那里获得了整数
we used integers and just got integers from the user.
但如果你还没有--
But if you haven't already--
如果您深入研究有关整数的文档
if you go and dig into the documentation for integers,
同样 它位于这个URL上 您
which, again, lives at this URL here, you
会发现INT本身就是一门课 几周来一直是这样
would actually find that int itself is and has been for weeks a class.
事实上 这是对int的构造函数调用的签名
And in fact, this is the signature of the constructor call for an int,
借此传入x 如数字、引号、不引号、“50”或引号
whereby you pass in x, like a number, quote, unquote, "50" or, quote,
引用一句话 还有一些东西--你可以选择性地传递基数--
unquote, something else-- you pass in optionally the base--
10表示十进制 2表示二进制或其他任何值
10 for decimal, 2 for binary or anything else.
这个整型函数会一直返回给你
And that int function will actually return to you, all this time,
类型为int的对象
an object of type int.
也就是说 int是一个类
That is to say int is a class.
它是一个模板 一个在内存中创建整数的蓝图
It is a template, a blueprint for creating integers in memory.
任何时候 只要你和我把一个字符串转换成一个整型
And any time you and I have converted a string, for, instance to an int,
您和我一直在创建一个int类型的对象 该对象调用
you and I have been creating an object of type int that was calling,
显然 下划线 init 下划线下划线方法
apparently, the underscore underscore, init, underscore underscore method,
其他人--《巨蟒》的作者--
that someone else-- the authors of Python--
写给我们的是正确的整数
wrote to give us back that proper integer.
除此之外 如果你相信的话 STR、Python中的字符串
Besides that, if you can believe it, strs, strings in Python
从这节课的第一周就开始上课了
have been classes since the first week of this class as well.
如果您在文档中查找字符串
If you look up the documentation for a str,
它位于一个类似的URL中 您会发现 当您实例化
which lives at a similar URL there, you will find that, when you instantiate--
也就是说 创建一个字符串--
that is, create a str--
它可选地接受一个在这里称为Object的参数
it takes, optionally, a parameter called object here,
其缺省值为JUST、QUOTE、UNQUOTE、
the default value of which is just, quote, unquote,
这实际上允许您创建一个空字符串、一个空字符串、
which allows you to create, in effect, an empty string, a blank string,
如果你愿意的话
if you will.
但任何时候你和我创建了STR或甚至明确使用
But any time you and I have created strs or even used explicitly
Str函数 您将返回一个str类型对象
the str function, you are getting back an object of type str.
任何时候您和我根据文档将字符串强制为小写时
Any time you and I have forced a string to lowercase per the documentation,
使用这样的语法 您和我已经获取了一个类型为str的对象
using syntax like this, you and I have been taking an object of type str
并通过调用名为Low的方法将其全部强制为小写
and forcing it all to lowercase by calling a method called lower,
一种由Python的作者构建到str类中的方法
a method that the authors of Python built into the str class,
但它从一开始就存在 所以这个方法的概念不是
but it's been there from the get-go, so this notion of methods is not
即使是今天的新鲜事
even new today.
你不会这么做这么久的
You wouldn't have been doing it for this long.
如果您曾经调用strain来删除前导空格和尾随空格
If you've ever called strip to remove the leading and the trailing whitespace
从Python中的一个字符串中 您将调用另一个随Python提供的方法--
from a string in Python, you are calling another method that came with Python--
由Python的作者编写
written by the authors of Python.
尽管我们当时并没有把它叫做课程
And even though we didn't call it a class at the time,
一直以来 字符串都是一门课
a str, all this time, has been a class.
字符串的实例本身就是对象
And instances of strings are, themselves, objects.
因此 这些对象具有以下功能
And those objects come therefore with these functions
内置--也就是 允许我们做像武力这样的事情的方法
built in-- a.k.a. methods that allow us to do things like force
从开头和结尾开始小写并去掉空格
to lowercase and strip whitespace from the beginning and end.
让我们再来一次
Let's do another.
List--任何时候您创建了一个列表 无论是语法上的Square
list-- any time you've created a list, either syntactically with square
括号或字面意思是L-I-S-T 左括号 右括号
brackets or literally with L-I-S-T, open parentheses, closed parentheses,
这也是可能的 你一直在使用一个类
which is also possible, you have been using a class.
如果您转到列表的文档 请访问类似的URL
If you go to the documentation for list, at this similar URL
在这里 或者更具体地说 关于在Python中的列表的教程
here, or more specifically, the tutorial on lists here in Python,
你会看到一份清单现在和过去都是
you will see that a list is and has been,
从这节课的前几周开始 一节课就开始了
since the early weeks of this class, a class itself.
作为其初始化的一部分 该List类
And that list class takes, as part of its initialization,
可选的可迭代的 可以迭代的东西--比如1 2 3
an optional iterable, something that can be iterated over-- like 1, 2, 3,
或某个值列表 然后您可以返回
or some list of values, and you can then get back
包含这些相同可迭代值的列表
a list containing those same iterable values.
如果你曾经在这节课的列表上添加过什么
If you've ever appended something to a list in this class,
就像我过去做的那样 你一直
as I have myself in the past, you've been
使用List类附带的名为append的方法 根据x
using a method called append that comes with the list class that, per the x
在这里 接受一个允许您追加某些内容的参数
here, takes an argument that allows you to append something
添加到当前名单中 也就是
to the current list, a.k.a.
在这种方法的背景下 自我
Self in the context of that method.
我们可以一整天都这样做
We can do this all day long.
如果你用过Python中的词典或词典--
If you've used a dictionary or a dict in Python--
实际上 一直以来 我都把它们叫做词典对象
I've actually, all this time, been calling them dict objects,
这是有原因的
and that's for a reason.
DICT本身就是一个用Python编写的类 如果你把它拉上来
dict itself is a class in Python, if you pull up
它的官方文件在这里
its official documentation here.
您将看到它确实被定义为一个类
And you'll see that it is defined, indeed, as itself a class.
而且这个类也附带了方法
And that class comes with methods as well.
所以 每当我们操纵词典时
And so any time we've manipulated dictionaries,
我们已经在引擎盖下 使用了所有这些相同的方法
we've been underneath the hood, using all of those same methods.
事实上 如果我们真的很好奇 我们就能看到这一点
And in fact, we can see this if we're really curious.
让我回到这里来VS Code
Let me go back over here to VS Code.
让我们继续创建一个新文件 该文件非常简单
And let me go ahead and create a new file that, very simply, does
与数据类型有关的东西
something play around with data types.
让我继续创建一个新文件 例如
And let me go ahead and create a new file, for instance,
名为type.py 这样我就可以查看一些值了
called, say, type.py, just so that I can poke around inside of some values.
在type.py中 我将继续执行此操作
And in type.py, I'm just going to go ahead and do this.
我要打印出任何类型的东西 比如说数字50
I'm going to print out whatever the type is of, say, the number 50.
这是一个你们还没有见过我用过的函数
And This is a function you've not necessarily seen me use already,
而且您不会在自己的代码中频繁使用它
and it's not one you would frequently use in your own code.
如果需要的话 还有其他方法可以检测到
There are other ways to detect, if you need to,
变量的类型是什么
what the type is of a variable.
但在这种情况下 50的类型只会告诉我 然后打印出来
But in this case, type of 50 is just going to tell me and then print out
该值的数据类型是什么
what the data type is of that value.
现在 希望我们所有人都能猜到 50确实是
Now, hopefully, all of us could guess that 50 is indeed
将会是一个整数--
going to be an integer--
这是一个int 但我们可以这样看它
that is, an int, but we can see it in this way.
这也是懂一点编程的强大之处
And this, too, is what's powerful about knowing a bit of programming.
如果你想知道问题的答案
If you want to know the answer to a question,
试一试 就像我在这里一样
just try it out, like I am here.
因此 让我继续运行type.py的Python 回车
So let me go ahead and run Python of type.py, Enter.
事实就是如此
And there it is.
当你打印出数字50的类型时 你会在屏幕上看到
When you print out the type of the number 50, you'll see on the screen,
在这个神秘的语法中 类为“int”
in this cryptic syntax, class 'int.'
这可能不是您想要向用户展示的东西
This is not something that you probably want to show to the user.
但如果你自己只是想四处走走看看发生了什么
But if you yourself just want to poke around and see what's going on
或者以某种方式利用这些信息 这是
or maybe use that information somehow, it's
当然 您可以使用此类型的函数来实现这一点
certainly at your disposal to use this type function for that.
让我们稍微改变一下
Let's change it around a little bit.
不是作为参数传递给类型50 而是作为整型传递
Instead of passing as the argument to type 50, as an int,
让我们输入一些熟悉的东西 比如“Hello world ”
let's type something also familiar, like "hello, world,"
在双引号或单引号中
in double or single quotes.
让我回到我的终端窗口 清除屏幕
Let me go back to my terminal window, clear the screen,
并再次运行type.py的Python
and run Python of type.py again.
现在 瞧 就是这样
And now, voila, there it is.
一直以来 字符串也是一个类
All this time, a str is also a class.
我们可以再这样做几次 因为
We can do this a few more times, For.
实例
Instance.
让我们继续 把“你好 世界”变成一个空的清单--
Let's go ahead and change "hello, world" to just an empty list--
开方括号和闭方括号
open square bracket, closed square bracket.
这看起来有点神秘
And this is starting to look a little cryptic,
但是 再说一次 注意我在做什么
but, again, notice what I'm doing.
方括号中是一个空列表
In square brackets is an empty list.
我们以前也这么做过
We've done that before.
这是这个新类型函数的唯一参数
That is the sole argument to this new type function.
它只是被传递给打印函数
And that's just being passed to the print function
这样 type的返回值就是要打印的参数
so that the return value of type is the argument to print.
因此 如果我现在运行这段代码 即type.py的Python 它就在那里
So if I now run this code, Python of type.py, there it is.
清单也是一个类
A list is a class, too.
您可能还记得我说过 您还可以创建一个空列表
You might recall that I said that you can also create an empty list
按字面意思做list()
by literally doing list ().
这有点不一致 就像我们现在可以做的那样
This is a bit of an inconsistency, as we can now
标识int和字符串 现在列出--从技术上讲 它们都是小写
identify that int and str and now list-- they're technically all lowercase.
我不遗余力地创建了我的学生班级 以拥有这样的资本
And I went to great lengths of creating my student class to have that capital
这是一次会议
S. That's a convention.
因为int、stir、list和其他代码都是随Python一起提供的
Because int and stir and list and others come with Python,
他们决定让他们的内置数据类型--尽管它们是类--
they decided to make their built-in data types-- even though they're classes--
全是小写字母
all lowercase.
但是约定 在创建时在Python社区中的推荐
But the convention, the recommendation in the Python community when creating
你们的课程是大写第一个字母 就像我做的那样
your classes is to capitalize the first letter, as I did,
在像学生这样的地方 大写S 但是list()等同于
in something like Student, capital S. But list () is identical to really just
两个空的方括号
two empty square brackets.
如果我清空屏幕并再次运行type.py 您将看到完全相同的结果
If I clear my screen and run type.py again, you see the exact same thing.
这个类被称为List
The class is called list.
让我们再来一次
Let's do one more.
让我将列表更改为不是方括号 而是花括号
Let me change the list to be not square brackets but curly braces.
我们以前也这么做过
We've done this before.
每当我做了两个中间没有花括号的花括号时 当然
Any time I've done two curly braces with nothing in between, this, of course,
是空词典 或者是Python中的Dict对象
is an empty dictionary, or a dict object in Python.
嗯 我们现在可以看到了
Well, we can see that now.
让我清空我的屏幕 运行type.py的Python 回车
Let me clear my screen, run Python of type.py, Enter,
这就是--班级的口头禅 “
and there it is-- class 'dict."
它一直都在那里
It's been there this whole time.
我们只是直到今天才把它称为一门课
We just didn't call it a class until today.
我同样可以明确地做这一件事
I can similarly do this one explicitly.
我们不用两个大括号 而是用两个圆括号写出dict
Instead of two curly braces, let's write out dict with two parentheses.
现在我们又有了很多圆括号 就像List一样
Now we have a lot of parentheses again, like with list.
但这只是更加清楚地表明 DICT对象的类型
But this is just making even more clear that the type of a dict object
确实是班级 DICT 本身
is indeed the class, dict, itself.
这就是说 尽管今天的许多概念和语法都很新
So this is to say that, as new as a lot of today's idea and syntax,
可能你真的在用它 也许你不知道
might be you've actually been using it, perhaps unbeknownst to you,
已经好几个星期了
for weeks now.
我们现在只有一些术语来描述
We now just have terminology to describe what
这是我们一直在做的事情
it is we've been doing all this time.
现在你有了表现力 通过一些练习
And you now have the expressiveness, with some practice,
要创建您自己的类 其中包含您自己的实例变量
to create your own classes, inside of which are your own instance variables,
可能包装了这些属性和您自己的实例方法
perhaps wrapped with those properties and your own instance methods.
但事实证明 世界上还有其他类型的方法
But it turns out there's other types of methods in the world.
到目前为止 我一直在慎重地打电话给
Thus far, I've been deliberate in calling
我们的所有变量、实例变量和所有方法实例
all of our variables instance variables and all of our methods instance
方法：研究方法
methods.
结果发现还有其他类型的变量和方法
It turns out there's other types of variables and methods out there,
其中之一被称为类方法
and one of those is called class methods.
事实证明 有时这并不是真正必要或明智的
It turns out that sometimes it's not really necessary or sensible
要将函数与类的对象相关联
to associate a function with objects of a class,
而是与班级本身有关
but rather with the class itself.
实例或类的对象是其非常特定的化身
An instance, or an object of a class, is a very specific incarnation thereof.
再说一次 在那个有许多外观相同的建筑的社区
Again, on that neighborhood that has a lot of identical looking buildings,
但它们都有一点不同 因为油漆不同
but they're all a little bit different because of different paint and such,
有时 您可能有相关的功能
sometimes you might have functionality related
对每一栋房子来说都不是独一无二的
to each of those houses that isn't distinct or unique for any
所有的房子
of the houses.
它的功能将是完全相同的 不是
It's functionality that's going to be exactly the same no
让问题中的房子变得更重要
matter the house in question.
面向对象编程领域也是如此
Same in the world of object-oriented programming.
有时你想要一些功能 一些动作
Sometimes you want some functionality, some action
与类本身相关联 而不管特定对象的
to be associated with the class itself, no matter what the specific object's
自己的值或实例变量是
own values or instance variables are.
为此 我们有一个名为@类方法的关键字
And for that, we have a keyword called @classmethod.
这是另一个装饰者--真的 另一个
This is another decorator-- really, another
函数--你可以用它来指定这个方法不是
function-- that you can use to specify that this method is not,
默认情况下 隐式地提供一个实例方法
by default, implicitly an instance method that
可以访问self 对象本身
has access to self, the object itself.
这是一个不能访问self的类方法
This is a class method that's not going to have access to self,
但它知道自己所在的类
but it does know what class it's inside.
那么我这样说是什么意思呢？
So what do I mean by this?
让我们回到VS Code
Well, let me go back to VS Code here.
我建议我们创建一个新文件
And let me propose that we create a new file this time implementing
分院帽的概念 也来自哈利波特的世界
the notion of a-- the sorting hat, from the world of Harry Potter as well,
保持主题
to stay on theme.
我将继续运行hat.py的代码
I'm going to go ahead and run code of hat.py.
在hat.py中 让我们实现排序帽的概念
And in hat.py, let's implement the notion of the sorting hat.
如果在书中和电影中不熟悉
If unfamiliar in the books and in the films
有一顶尖尖的帽子
there is literally a pointy hat that, when
一个学生把它戴在头上 可以说
a student put it's on their head, that sorting hat, so to speak,
决定学生住哪间房子--不管是
decides what house the student is in-- whether it's
格兰芬多或者别的什么
Gryffindor or something else.
让我们用代码实现这个排序帽的概念
So let's implement, in code, this notion of a sorting hat such that,
当我们把一个学生的名字传递给排序帽时
when we pass to the sorting hat the name of a student, like, quote, unquote,
“哈利”这个排序帽 用代码实现
"Harry" this sorting hat, implemented in code,
会告诉我们那个学生应该在哪个房子里
will tell us what house that student should be in.
好吧 让我们开始吧
Well, let's go ahead and do this.
在hat.py中 首先 让我们继续定义一个名为hat的类
In hat.py, first, let's go ahead and define a class called hat,
然后让我们回到实现它本身
and then let's get back to implementing it itself.
我发现这是一个有用的技巧 不仅仅是教学
And I find this to be a helpful technique, not just with teaching
而是写代码的时候
but when writing code.
我知道我想上帽子课
I know I want a hat class.
我还不知道我想让它做什么
I don't necessarily know what I want it to do yet,
所以我要创建这个占位符 点
so I'm going to create this placeholder, dot, dot, dot,
所以我会回到这个话题
so I'll come back to that.
现在让我们试着使用这个类 就好像它存在一样
Let's now try to use this class as though it existed.
从那里 我也许能意识到
And from there, I perhaps can realize exactly what
类需要具备的功能来支持我的用例
functionality that class needs to have to support my use case.
让我们继续 在所有的数组中创建一个名为hat的变量
Let me go ahead and create a variable called hat in all lowercase
并实例化一个帽子对象
and instantiate a hat object.
所以不管帽子班最后是什么样子
So no matter what the hat class ends up looking like,
这是实例化的常用语法
this is the common syntax for instantiating
某一类的物体
an object of a certain class.
在过去 我们看到学生都是小写的
In the past, we saw student, all lowercase,
等于大写的学生 左括号 右括号
equals capital Student, open parenthesis, close parentheses,
最后 我们加上了名字和房子之类的东西
and then eventually, we added in things like name and house.
现在 让我们假设这顶帽子比一个学生简单得多
For now, let's assume that the hat is much simpler than a student,
而且它只有分类能力
and it only has sorting capabilities.
因此 我甚至不会在这里传递任何论点
So I'm not going to even pass any arguments there, too.
让我假设分类帽有一个函数--其中有一个方法
Let me assume that the sorting hat has one function-- one method inside of it
叫 Sort
called, sort.
因此 如果我要HAT.Sort(“Harry”) 让我们建议打印出什么房子
And so if I do hat.sort ("Harry"), let's propose that that prints out what house
那个学生应该在里面
that student should be in.
就是这样了
So that's it.
我要概括一下--
I'm going to encapsulate--
它被藏在一个帽子班里--
that is tuck away inside of a hat class--
所有这些必需的功能 我将打印到屏幕上
all of this requisite functionality, and I'm going to print out onto the screen
什么帽子--
what hat--
哈利属于哪所房子
what house Harry belongs in.
现在我想我需要开始实际初始化这个类了
Now I think I need to get into the weeds of actually initializing this class.
好吧 让我继续做这件事
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
如果我不介意将帽子参数化--
If I don't care to parameterize hat--
例如 我只想对值进行排序
I just want to, for instance sort values,
让我们继续定义这个函数 首先是排序
let's go ahead and define this function, sort, first.
所以让我们定义Sort 作为第一个参数
So let's define sort, as taking a first argument, self,
在将实例方法定义为
which is always going to be the case when defining an instance method as
在此之前
before.
但Sort方法显然接受了程序员我的一个参数--
But the sort method clearly takes one argument from the programmer, me--
即学生的名字
namely the student's name.
再说一次 我们以前见过这种二分法
And again, we've seen this dichotomy before.
即使我试图传递一个参数 当我定义该方法时
Even though I'm trying to pass in one argument, when I define the method,
它需要这么多的争论 再加上一个--
it's got to take that many arguments, plus one more--
自身 它始终将由Python自动传入
self which is always going to be automatically passed in by Python
第一
first.
我想要做什么？
What do I want to do?
好吧 让我们继续做这样的事情
Well, let's go ahead and do something like this.
Print 这个名字--比如“is in” “Some House”
Print, this name-- how about "is in," "some house."
我将再次使用一些占位符代码
I'm going to, again, use some placeholder code
对于我自己来说 因为我不太确定如何完成这个排序
for myself because I'm not quite sure how to finish implementing this sorting
帽子
hat.
但我认为这足以测试我的代码现在在哪里
But I think that's enough to just test where my code is at now.
让我继续运行hat.py的Python 然后按Enter键
Let me go ahead and run Python of hat.py and hit Enter.
而且看起来 哈里确实在某个房子里
And it looks like, indeed, Harry is in some house.
我们还没有完成 因为它显然没有做任何有趣的事情
We're not done yet because it's clearly not doing anything interesting,
但它至少运行正常 没有任何错误
but it at least is running correctly with no errors.
好吧 让我们现在继续 决定在哪里--
Well, let's go ahead now and decide where--
通过引入一点随机性 哈里到底应该是什么样的人
what house Harry should actually be in by introducing a bit of randomness
并随机选择一所房子
and choosing a house randomly.
虽然我可以用几种方法来做到这一点 但让我们
While I can do this in a few ways, Let.
我继续做这件事
Me go ahead and do this.
我需要一份某处的房屋清单
I need to have a list of houses somewhere.
我该把它放在哪里呢？
So where can I put that?
我可以用不同的方法解决这个问题
I could solve this problem in different ways.
让我提议我做这件事
Let me propose that I do this.
让我定义一个名为init的方法 就像我以前所做的那样
Let me define a method called init, as I've done before,
这是针对自己的 但没有其他论点
that takes in self, but no other arguments.
无论何时实例化分类帽子 我们都要这样做
And whenever the sorting hat is instantiated, let's do this.
让我们创建一个House实例变量 复数 等于这个列表--
Let's create a houses instance variable, plural, that equals this list--
格兰芬多 赫奇帕奇 拉文克劳 斯莱特林
Gryffindor, Hufflepuff, Ravenclaw, Slytherin,
所以我们之前用过的一模一样的名单
so the exact same list that we've used before,
我将它存储在这个类的一个实例变量中
and I'm storing it in an instance variable inside of this class.
我不会拿自己以外的任何论点来灌输
I'm not taking any arguments beyond self to init,
但我只是需要这个值列表的某个地方 例如
but I just need this list of values somewhere, for instance.
那么我能在这里做些什么呢？
So what can I do here?
好吧 让我继续把一些房子换成真正的房子
Well, let me go ahead and replace some house with the actual house.
那么 我在这里能做什么呢？
Well, what could I do here?
嗯 我想在那里建一栋房子
Well, I want to put a house there.
好 让我们继续创建一个名为house的变量
Well, let's go ahead and create a variable called house.
如果你回想一下我们在随机模块中对库的讨论
And if you think back to our discussion of libraries, in the random module,
有一个名为Choose的函数 如果您传入一个选项列表
there is a function called choice that, if you pass in a list of choices,
就像自己的房子一样 它会从这四个房子中随机挑选一座房子
like self.houses, that will pick a random house out of those four.
然后在第7行 我可以把它传进去
And then on line 7, I can pass it in.
如果我想加强这一点 让我继续并突出显示该代码
If I want to tighten this up, let me just go ahead and highlight that code,
去掉变量
get rid of the variable.
从技术上讲 这是不必要的
It's technically unnecessary.
而且由于代码行仍然很短
And because the line of code is still pretty short,
我可以把所有的事情都放在一句话里
I'm OK with just putting it all in one line.
但我肯定可以像刚才一样使用这个变量
But I could certainly use the variable like I did a moment ago.
那么我做了什么呢？
So what have I done?
在我的init函数中 我定义了对象的初始化
In my init function, I have defined a initialization of the object
储存在自己的房子里 有四栋房子
that stores in self.houses the list of four houses.
然后 在某种程度上 我访问了同样的列表
And then, in sort, I'm accessing that same list,
但我随机选择了那里的一套房子
but I'm randomly choosing the set of houses there.
现在 我为什么要这样做呢？
Now, why have I done it in this way?
这也是普遍的惯例
This, too, is general convention.
任何时候你有一张清单--谁知道呢？
Any time you have a list of things that-- who knows?
也许会随着时间的推移而改变
Maybe will change over time.
像哈佛这样的地方多年来一直在建造新房子
Places like Harvard have constructed new houses over the years,
因此 您可能需要更改可用房屋的列表
so you might have to change the list of available houses.
这并没有出现在哈利波特的七本书或八部电影中
It didn't happen in seven books or eight films of Harry Potter.
但你可以想象也许霍格沃茨最终
But you could imagine maybe Hogwarts eventually
有第五宫 所以把常量列表放在
has a fifth house, so there's generally some value in putting list of constants
在你的文件顶部 在类的顶部 所以它只是
toward the top of your file, toward the top of the class so it's just
很明显 值的列表是什么
obvious what the list of values is.
你不一定想把它藏在某些功能中
You don't want to necessarily tuck it away in some function,
就像排序一样 特别是当你想使用这个函数的时候--
like sort, especially if you might want to use that function--
抱歉 特别是如果您想在多个功能中使用该列表 而不是
sorry, especially if you want to use that list in multiple functions, not
只是整理一下
just sort.
但如果我继续增加这门课 你可能会
But if I kept adding to this class, you might
想要在多个功能中使用相同的房屋列表
want to use that same list of houses in multiple functions.
因此 让我们通过将其存储在self.house中来将其保存在对象本身中
So let's keep it in the object itself by storing it in self.houses.
好吧 好吧 我们可能要改变历史进程了
All right, well, we're about to change the course of history here perhaps.
让我来做一个HAT.PY的蟒蛇 我想我们即将把Harry
Let me do Python of hat.py, and I think we're about to assign Harry
去那四所房子中的一所
to one of those four houses randomly.
嗯 名字错误
Huh, NameError.
未定义名称‘RANDOM’
Name 'random' is not defined.
嗯 等一下 我哪里出错了？
Well, wait a minute, where did I go wrong here?
回想一下我们关于图书馆的课程 为什么我的代码崩溃了 而没有告诉我
Thinking back to our class on libraries, why did my code break and not tell me
哈里要去哪里？
where Harry is to be?
观众：您没有导入随机库
AUDIENCE: You did not import the random library.
大卫·J·马兰：没错
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
如果我想使用随机库或模块
If the random library or module is something I want to use,
我需要在我的文件顶部告诉Python这一点
I need to tell Python that at the top of my file.
所以让我在这里做随机导入
So let me go up here and do import random.
然后 在这下面 让我继续清除我的终端窗口
And then, below that, let me go ahead and clear my terminal window
再试一次
and try again.
在我的手指上祈祷 看看哈里将会在哪里结束
Python of hat.py, crossing my fingers, seeing where Harry is going to end up.
好了 哈里现在正式加入赫奇帕奇了
And, OK, Harry as of now is officially in Hufflepuff,
不管你读过或看到过什么
despite everything you've read or seen.
好吧 让我们再来一次
Well, let's run this again.
让我清理我的窗口并运行Python中的hat.py 现在他在RavenClaw
Let me clear my window and run Python of hat.py, and now he's in Ravenclaw.
这与使用随机数是一致的
That's consistent with using random.
我们清除它 然后再运行一次
Let's clear that and run it again.
他还在拉文克劳 但这是有可能的
He's still in Ravenclaw, but that could happen,
尽管有四个选择
even though there's four choices.
我们再来一次吧
Let's do it again.
赫奇帕奇--回到赫奇帕奇
Hufflepuff-- back in Hufflepuff.
我们似乎得不到正确的答案
We can't seem to get the right answer.
现在他在格兰芬多 尽管是随机的
Now he's in Gryffindor, albeit randomly.
因此 我们似乎有一个项目 基于这些有限的测试
So we seem to have a program that, based on these limited tests,
似乎是在随机给哈里分配一所房子
seems to be assigning Harry to a house randomly.
现在 我有点懒得让SORT打印出这个值
Now I'm somewhat lazily just letting sort print out this value.
我可以做其他的事情 比如返回一个字符串 然后让我在第13行
I could do something else, like return a string, and then let me, on line 13,
帮我打印一下
do the printing for me.
但就目前而言 我认为我们有一个名为Hat的班级的例子
But for now, I think we have an example of a class called hat that,
尽管如此 今天还是应用了我们到目前为止学到的一些经验教训
nonetheless, applies some of our lessons learned thus far today,
在那里我创建了一个类--因为坦率地说 分院帽是--
where I've created a class-- because a sorting hat is, frankly--
好吧 我正要说真实世界的实体 但真的
well, I was about to say real world entity, but really
一个虚幻的世界实体
a fantasy world entity.
事实上 这可能是一种常见的启发式或心智模式
And indeed, that's a, perhaps, common heuristic or mental model to have.
应该在什么时候使用类来表示代码中的某些内容？
When should you use a class to represent something in your code?
通常 当你试图代表一些真实世界的实体时
Very often, when you're trying to represent some real world entity
或者是幻想世界的实体 比如学生 这是现实世界中的东西
or fantasy world entity, like a student, which is something in the real world,
就像一顶分院帽 好吧 根本不存在
like a sorting hat, which, OK, doesn't exist,
但它确实是这样的 所以有一个关于HAT的类是很合理的
but hat's certainly do, so quite reasonable to have a class for hat.
类代表真实世界实体的情况并不总是这样
And that's not always the case that classes represent real world entities.
但到目前为止 我们已经看到int、stir、list和dict--这些
But we've seen thus far that int and stir and list and dict-- these
都是你在现实世界中可能会有的结构
are all structures that you might have in the real world.
我们有整数和文本字符串以及其他东西
We have integers and strings of text and other things.
因此 更严格地说 甚至代表这些东西也是有意义的
So it rather makes sense to represent even those things, more technically,
也使用类
using a class as well.
你可以只用一本词典来代表一个学生或一顶帽子
You could use just a dictionary to represent a student or a hat.
但同样 类带来了所有这些 甚至更多的功能
But again, with classes come all this and even more functionality.
但老实说 我在这里并没有以“正确的方式”使用类
But I honestly am not using classes in, really, the "right way" here.
为什么？
Why?
好吧 在哈利波特的世界里 真的只有
Well, in the world of Harry Potter there really is only,
据我所知 一顶分院帽
to my knowledge, one sorting hat.
然而 在这里 我实现了一个名为Hat的类
And yet, here I have gone and implemented a class called hat.
同样 类就像一张蓝图 一个模板
And again, a class is like a blueprint, a template,
允许您在其中创建一个或多个对象的模具
a mold that allows you to create one or more objects thereof.
到目前为止 我的大多数程序都很简单
Now, most of my programs Thus far have been pretty simple,
我刚刚创造了一个学生
and I've just created one student.
但可以肯定的是 如果我花更多的时间和编写更多的代码
But certainly, if I spent more time and wrote more code,
您可以想象编写一个程序
you could imagine writing one program that
有一份学生名单--更多的学生
has a list of students-- many more students
而不仅仅是我们一直在演示的那个
than just the one we keep demonstrating.
然而 这会有点奇怪--
Yet it would be a little weird--
这与现实或幻想有点不一致
it's a little inconsistent with the real or the fantasy
哈利波特世界实例化一个、两个、三个或更多的分类帽子
world of Harry Potter to instantiate one, two, three or more sorting hats.
真的只有一个
There really is just one.
真的只有一个人 如果你愿意的话 那就是
Really one singleton, if you will, which is
在许多编程环境中 这是一种艺术术语
a term of art in a lot of contexts of programming.
所以让我建议我们实际上改进分拣帽的设计
So let me propose that we actually improve the design of the sorting hat
这样我们就不必实例化分类帽了 因为现在
so that we don't have to instantiate a sorting hat because right now this
允许我做一些像帽子1=帽子 帽子2=帽子 帽子3=
is kind of allowing me to do something like hat 1 = hat, hat 2 = hat, hat 3 =,
以此类推
and so forth.
我并不真的需要这种能力
I don't really need that capability.
我真的只需要用一个类来表示分拣帽
I really just need to represent the sorting hat with a class,
但我真的不需要实例化它
but I don't really need to instantiate it.
为什么？
Why?
因为它已经存在了
Because it already exists.
我只需要一个
I need just one.
所以事实证明 在Python中 到目前为止
So it turns out, in Python, that, up until now,
我们一直在使用 就像我一直叫它们的 实例方法--
we've been using, as I keep calling them, instance methods--
在自动传递引用的类中编写函数
writing functions inside of classes that are automatically passed a reference
设置为自身 即当前对象
to self, the current object.
但有时你就是不需要这样
But sometimes you just don't need that.
有时候 仅仅知道这个类是什么就足够了
Sometimes it suffices to just know what the class is
并假设甚至可能没有该类的任何对象
and assume that there might not even be any objects of that class.
因此 从这个意义上说 您可以将类真正用作数据的容器
So in this sense, you can use a class really as a container for data
和/或在概念上有某种关联的功能--
and/or functionality that is just somehow conceptually related--
和分院帽有关的东西
things related to a sorting hat.
还有另一个称为@类方法的装饰符或函数
And there's this other decorator or function called @classmethod
使我们能够做到这一点
that allows us to do just this.
现在让我回到我的代码
So let me go back to my code here.
让我提议 如果我不打算实例化多个房屋
And let me propose that, if I'm not going to instantiate multiple houses,
我真的不需要这个init方法 因为它真的
I don't really need this init method because that's really
旨在从该蓝图、该模板、
meant to initialize specific objects from that blueprint, that template,
那个霉菌
that mold.
所以让我把这个处理掉
So let me get rid of this.
但如果我摆脱了这一切 我就再也无法接触到自我了
But if I get rid of this, I no longer have access to self.
但这没问题 因为事实证明 除了他们现有的班级
But that's OK because it turns out, in addition to their existing class
方法 还有我们所说的类变量
methods, there are also what we might call class variables.
并且类变量存在于类本身中
And class variables exist within the class itself.
而这个变量只有一个副本
And there's just one copy of that variable
对于它的所有目的
for all of the objects thereof.
如果您愿意的话 它们都共享同一个变量--可以是int还是str
They all share, if you will, the same variable-- be it an int or str
或者 在这种情况下 是一份名单
or, in this case, a list.
所以我在这里所做的就是在我的HAT类中 在一个类变量中定义
So what I've done here is define, inside of my hat class, in a class variable
所谓的房子--
called houses--
我不说自我 是因为自我不再相关
I don't say self because self is no longer relevant.
自我是指特定的对象
Self refers to specific objects.
我希望这个类中有一个变量 也就是
I want a variable inside of this class, a.k.a.
与该列表相等的类变量
A class variable that equals that list.
因为它在这顶帽子里 现在 同学们
Because it's inside of this hat, now, class,
我可以在我的任何函数中使用该列表
I can use that list in any of my functions.
我现在只有一个 叫Sort
I've only got one now, called sort.
但如果我有更多 所有这些方法都可以访问它
But if I had more, it would be accessible to all of those methods
也是
as well.
而对于排序 这也没有真正意义上的意义
And with sort, it also doesn't really make sense
在特定的分类帽子中进行排序 因为我再次
to sort within a specific sorting hat because, again, I
我只想有一个
only want there to be one.
所以我实际上可以通过说@类方法来指定这是类方法
So I can actually specify that this is class method by saying @classmethod.
我再也不会通过赛尔夫了
And I don't pass in self anymore.
实际上 按照惯例 我传入了对类本身的引用
I actually, by convention, pass in a reference to the class itself.
它通常被写成CLS
It's typically written as cls.
为什么？
Why?
那么 如果你写的是C-L-A-S-S 那实际上就和这个关键词有冲突
Well, if you wrote C-L-A-S-S, that would actually conflict with the keyword
我们在这里一直用的“类”这个词
"class" that we keep using up here.
所以世界意识到 哦 我们不能在这里重复使用同样的短语
So the world realized that, oops, we can't reuse that same phrase here.
所以我们就把这门课叫作
So let's just call this class.
这在某些情况下很有用 包括这一点
This is useful in some contexts including this one.
为什么？
Why?
好了 注意我现在能做什么
Well, notice what I can now do.
我现在可以把自己变成一个普通的人了
I can now change self to be just class.
为什么？
Why?
因为house现在--不是一个实例变量 可以通过self.house访问
Because houses now-- not an instance variable, accessible via self.houses.
它现在是一个类变量 可以通过类.house访问
It is now a class variable, accessible via class.houses,
或者从技术上讲 在这起案件中是Cls.House
or technically cls.houses in this case.
但现在 最后的繁荣是这样的
But now the final flourish is this.
现在 我不必像以前在这里第13行那样实例化任何HAT对象
Now, I don't have to instantiate any hat objects as I used to on here, line 13.
我可以只使用这个类附带的功能
I can just use functionality that comes with this class.
所以我要把这一行全部删除
So I'm going to delete that line altogether.
我将在这条新的13行上大写帽子 然后只说Hat 排序
I'm going to capitalize the hat on this new line 13 and just say hat.sort,
(“哈利”)
("Harry").
那么我做了什么呢？
So what have I done?
我没有费心实例化一个类型为Hat的对象
I've not bothered instantiating an object of type, hat.
我只是在访问HAT类内部的一个类方法
I am just accessing a class method inside of the hat class
那--你知道吗？
that-- you know what?
都会奏效的
Is just going to work.
这就是类方法的工作方式
This is how class methods work.
您使用类名、大写字母和全部、点方法名、
You use the name of the class, capital letter and all, dot method name,
传递您想要的任何参数
passing in any arguments you want.
Python将自动传入某个变量 通过该变量
Python is going to automatically pass in some variable via which
您可以在该函数中引用该类
you can refer to that class in that function
您在该类中实现的
that you've implemented inside of that class
这样我才能做这样的事
so that I can do something like this.
这并不是说我希望在这个函数中有一个名为house的本地变量
It's not that I want a variable called houses locally in this function,
我想要与当前类关联的名为house的变量
I want the variable called houses that's associated with this current class
因此 我仍然可以访问我在第6行定义的相同列表
so I can still access this same list that I defined on line 6.
现在 如果我返回到我的终端并运行Hot.py的Python
And now, if I go back down here to my terminal and run Python of hat.py,
进来吧 哈里还在赫奇帕奇
Enter, Harry is still in Hufflepuff once more.
哈利又一次加入了赫奇帕奇乐队
Harry is still in Hufflepuff once more.
哈利回到了格兰芬多 至少是随机的
Harry is back in Gryffindor, at least randomly.
现在 关于这些类变量或类方法的问题
Questions, now, on these class variables or these class methods,
它们与实例变量和实例方法形成对比
which are in contrast with instance variables and instance methods.
至少有一件事 那是有点奇怪的
And the one thing, at least, that's a little strange
这就是 尽管有一个叫做“类方法”的装饰者
here is that, even though there's a decorator called @classmethod,
没有一种方法叫@instancemthod
there is not one called @instancemethod.
在以下情况下 一个方法就自动成为所谓的“即时方法”
A method is just automatically a so-called "instant method" when
你不需要任何装饰者来定义它
you define it without any decorator.
观众：你能在另一个班级里有一个班级吗？
AUDIENCE: Can you have a class inside another class?
大卫·J·马兰：你可以的
DAVID J. MALAN: You can.
您可以在另一个类中定义一个类
You can define one class inside of another.
一般来说 这并没有完成 但在那里
Generally speaking, this isn't done, but there
在某些情况下 它可能会有所帮助 尤其是
are cases where it can be helpful, especially
用于更大、更复杂的程序
for larger, more sophisticated programs.
所以 是的 这是可能的
So yes, it is possible.
其他问题
Other questions.
观众：问题是关于房子本身的
AUDIENCE: The question was about the self.houses.
当我们删除它并传递数据时 变量本身就会被创建
When we remove it and we pass data, variable is created itself,
S 我们为什么要去除自我？
s why we remove the self?
大卫·J·马兰：在前面的例子中--
DAVID J. MALAN: So in the previous examples--
无论是帽子演示还是所有学生
both of the hat demonstration and also all of the student
演示--我们创造了一个学生
demonstrations-- we were creating a student
对象 大写S 左括号 右括号
object by calling Student, capital S, open parenthesis, close parenthesis,
最后 带着名字和一栋房子进来了
with, eventually, name and a house passed in.
然后我们使用了双下划线初始化方法
And then we were using the double underscore init method
初始化self.name和self.house实例变量
to initialize the self.name and the self.house instance variables
与这些相应的值对应
therein to those respective values.
在这个最新版本的分院帽中
In this latest version of the sorting hat,
我在任何地方都没有为自己操心 只是因为 从概念上讲 我
I haven't bothered with self anywhere, only because, conceptually, I
不需要也不希望世界上有多顶帽子
don't need or want there to be multiple hats in the world.
我只是将这个类作为一个容器来打包这个房屋列表
I'm just using the class as a container to bundle up this list of houses,
这种排序功能
this sorting functionality.
也许最终都会给它增加更多的功能
Maybe eventually all add more functionality to it.
但仅此而已
But that's it.
因此 有时您可以使用面向对象的编程
And so sometimes you can use object-oriented programming
以这种稍微不同的方式 当您想要有功能时
in this somewhat different way when you want there to be functionality
但它并不特定于任何一顶特定的帽子
but it's not specific to any one specific hat.
它是专门针对分拣帽本身的
It's specific to the sorting hat itself.
现在再来看另一个问题 关于这些类变量或方法--只是
How about one other question now, on these class variables or methods-- just
使用面向对象编程的另一种方法 但要解决
another way of using object-oriented programming but to solve
一个有点不同的问题？
a somewhat different problem?
观众：嗯 这两门课有什么不同
AUDIENCE: Well, what's the difference between the class
帽子和帽子的作用？
hat and a function of hat?
大卫·J·马兰：问得好
DAVID J. MALAN: A good question.
那么 我们为什么要使用一个类 而不仅仅是
So why are we using a class at all and not just
有一个名为hat.py的文件 其中包含一个名为
having a file called hat.py with a variable called
房屋和一个名为Sort的函数？
houses and a function called sort?
为什么我们要增加这种复杂性？
Why are we adding this complexity?
在这种特殊情况下 我们不一定需要这样做
In this particular case, we don't necessarily need to.
我完全可以走进这里
I could absolutely go in here.
我可以把这门课赶走
I could get rid of the class.
我可以解开这个凹痕
I could undo this indentation.
我可以除掉这个装饰师
I could get rid of this decorator.
这样我就可以摆脱帽点了
And I could get rid of hat dot.
我可以这样做 另外
And I could just do this and additionally
让我们说 让我们摆脱这里的类
let's say, let's get rid of class here.
让我们把这里的课去掉吧
Let's get rid of class here.
现在运行hat.py的Python 回车 它仍然可以工作
And now run Python of hat.py, Enter, and it still works.
把哈利放错了房间 但这就是我们所拥有的--
Put Harry in the wrong house, but that's what we have--
随机发生的事情
what happens randomly.
这也很好
That's fine, too.
我们今天要介绍的是 通过面向对象编程
What we're introducing today, by way of object-oriented programming,
是一种不同的建模世界的方式
is just a different way of modeling the world.
像这样的例子并不能令人信服
It's not really compelling with an example like this,
坦率地说 这是相对简单的
frankly, that's relatively simple.
这并不是很复杂
It's not very complex.
没有太多的功能
There's not much functionality.
老实说 我们刚刚输入的版本--这10行--这很好
Honestly, the version that we just typed up-- these 10 lines-- this is fine.
这就解决了这个问题
This solves this problem.
但随着我们的代码变得更长 随着我们开始与其他人合作
But as our code gets longer, as we start collaborating with other people,
随着我们试图用代码解决的问题变得越来越复杂
as the problems we're trying to solve with code get more sophisticated,
您会发现您的代码很快就会变得杂乱无章
you're going to find that your code gets messy quickly.
你会发现你有大量的功能 例如
And you're going to find that you have a huge number of functions, for instance,
在一个文件中
in one file.
它们中的一些是相互关联的 而另一些是不相关的
And some of them are related to each other, but some of them are not.
嗯 在这一点上 组织他们不是很好吗？
Well, at that point, wouldn't it be nice to just organize them
有点不同吗？
a little differently?
在哈利波特的世界里 让我们为学生开设一个班级；
And in the world of Harry Potter, let's have a class for student;
让我们为教授上课；让我们为分院帽上课；
let's have a class for Professor; let's have a class for the sorting hat;
我们来上一堂其他的课吧
let's have a class for something else.
因此 一旦你的世界变得比一些
And so once your world gets much more complicated than some
当我们想要集中注意力时 我们在课堂上做的演示
of the demonstrations we do here in class when we want to focus
就个人观点而言 面向对象编程只是一种方式
on individual ideas, object-oriented programming is just a way
封装相关数据--
of encapsulating related data--
也就是说 变量相关的功能--也就是方法--
that is, variables-- related functionality-- that is, methods--
在有名字的东西里面
inside of things that have names.
这些东西被称为类
These things are called classes.
所以这只是解决问题的另一种方式
So it's just another way to solve problems.
几周前 当我们关注图书馆时
And when we focused on libraries a couple of weeks back,
这也是同样问题的另一种解决方案
that, too, was another solution to the same problem.
你可以定义你自己的模块或包 把你的一些数据
You could define your own modules or packages, put some of your data
和/或功能 这也是很好的
and/or functionality in there, and that's fine, too.
有时你应该使用哪一个是重叠的
And sometimes which one you should use overlaps.
如果你熟悉维恩图 重叠区域
If you're familiar with Venn diagrams, the overlapping region
可能意味着您可以使用类；您可以使用模块或包；
might mean that you could use a class; you could use a module or a package;
您可以只使用单个本地文件
you could just use a single local file.
随着时间的推移 你会发展出一种本能 甚至
Over time, you'll develop an instinct and maybe even
个人对要使用的工具的偏好
a personal preference for which tool to use.
好的 现在让我提议 我们应用类方法的相同概念
All right, let me propose, now, that we apply this same idea of a class method
来清理另一件事
to clean up one other thing as well.
让我关闭Hot.py并重新打开之前离开的Student.py
Let me close that hat.py and reopen student.py as we left it earlier,
让我继续下去 把它简化一点
and let me go ahead and simplify it just a little bit.
我要继续下去 处理掉这些房产
I'm going to go ahead and get rid of the properties,
不是因为他们有什么不对劲
not because there's anything, wrong with them,
但仅仅因为我想让我们把注意力集中在一些关键的想法上
but just because I want us to focus on some of the key ideas
当我们开始这个节目的时候
when we began with this program.
因此 我将继续并保持Main
So I'm going to go ahead and keep main as well.
我不会反驳地试图更改亨利在那里的地址
I'm not going to adversarially try to change Henry's address there.
不过 我打算继续 只打印学生
I'm going to instead go ahead, though, and just print the student.
但这是我在这里想要重点关注的事情
But this is the thing I want to focus on here.
在我们前面的学生示例中 这是一个错失的机会
This, in our previous student examples, was a missed opportunity
来清理我的代码
to clean up my code.
我这么说是什么意思？
Well, what do I mean by that?
好的 在这个文件的顶部--甚至
Well, up here at the top of this file-- even
虽然我简化了它 但去掉了属性
though I've simplified it, but getting rid of the properties
以及所有的错误检查--因为我
and all of that error checking-- because I
现在我想把重点放在这门课的本质上--只讲学生的名字
want to focus on the essence of this class now-- just the student's name
以及房子和它的印刷品
and the house and the printing thereof.
这是面向对象编程中类的本质
This is, by nature of classes in object-oriented programming,
理论上讲 我所有针对学生的功能
theoretically, all of my student-specific functionality.
也就是说 如果我有一个学生的功能和数据 你
That is to say, if I have functionality and data related to a student, you,
程序员 我的同事 会认为
the programmer, my colleague, would assume
它们都被捆绑在一起 被封装起来 所以
that it's all bundled up, encapsulated, so
要说 在学生班里
to speak, inside of the student class.
然而 如果你进一步向下滚动 这是什么？
And yet, if you scroll down further, what is this?
有一个名为Get_Student的函数 它只存在于其他地方
There's a function called get_student that just exists elsewhere
在该文件中 提示用户输入名称 提示用户输入房屋
in this file that prompts the user for a name, prompts the user for a house,
创建学生对象 然后返回
creates the student object, and then returns.
这没有错
That's not wrong.
它起作用了
It works.
我们看到了很多很多次 它一直在工作
And we saw many, many times it kept working.
但这有点奇怪 因为如果这
But this is a little weird because, if this
是一个帮助你获得一个学生的函数
is a function that helps you get a student,
帮你查到一个学生的名字和住处 为什么不
helps you get the name of a student and the house of a student, why isn't
类本身中的功能吗？
that functionality in the class itself?
毕竟 随着我的代码变得越来越复杂 做的事情越来越多
After all, as my code gets more and more complicated and does more things,
我要看的是学生们的课
I'm going to be looking at the student class
用于所有与学生相关的功能
for all student-related functionality.
我不会向下滚动 期待着 哦 也许有
I'm not going to be scrolling down, expecting that, oh, maybe there's
其他一些学生功能只是随机出现在这个文件的后面
some other student functionality just randomly later in this file.
所以这不是错的
So it's not wrong.
但这再次证明了可能是糟糕的设计--
But this is, again, evidence of maybe bad design--
对于这个小程序 就不是那么多了
not so much with this small program.
但这又是一个代码气味的例子
But this is an example, again, of code smell.
这里有股不对劲的味道
Something smells a little off here.
这可能会给我们带来麻烦
This is probably going to get us in trouble
通过分离相关功能
by separating related functionality.
因此 这再一次是设计原则 而不是正确性问题
So again it's a design principle, not a correctness concern.
但是类方法也允许我们解决这个问题
But class methods allow us to address this, too.
让我继续做这件事
Let me go ahead and do this.
我要一起删除Get_Student 离开
I'm going to delete get_student all together, leaving
这里只有main作为我的另一个函数
only main as my other function here.
在我的学生课堂上 我要这么做
And inside of my student class, I'm going to do this.
我将定义一个函数 更简单地称为GET
I'm going to define a function, even more simply called, get.
从类方法的工作方式来看 它是
And by nature of how class methods work, it's
将采用类本身的名称
going to take in the name of the class itself
或将其作为论据引用
or a reference thereto as an argument.
我将把功能从Get_Student移到学生中
And I'm going to move the functionality from get_student into the student
班级
class.
我将这样做--名字等于输入、引号、不引号、名字、房子
And I'm going to do this-- name equals input, quote, unquote, name, house
等于输入、引用、不引用、房子
equals input, quote, unquote, house.
然后这个函数要做的是
And then what this function is going to do
是通过调用类返回一个新学生对象 同样 这也只是
is return a new student object by calling class, which, again, is just
自动传入的对类的引用
an automatically passed-in reference to the class
本身 传递名字和房子
itself, passing in name and house.
我承认这个语法看起来有点奇怪 现在我调用CLS
And I will admit this syntax seems a little strange that now I'm calling cls
我把这些论点传递给大家
and I'm passing in these arguments.
但让我在这里做最后一次修正
But let me do one final fix here.
让我转到此函数的顶部 然后执行更多操作
Let me go to the top of this function and more
显式地说这是一个类方法
explicitly say this is a class method.
这解决了一个潜在的鸡和蛋的问题 可以说
This solves a potential chicken and the egg problem, so to speak,
因此 潜在地 一个需要先于另一个
whereby one needs to come before the other, potentially.
那我在这里做什么？
So what am I doing here?
在我的学生类中 我现在有一个名为Get的函数
Inside of my student class, I now have a function called get.
我要说 它是一个类方法 这意味着什么
It is, I shall claim, a class method what does that mean.
它只是意味着我可以调用此方法 而无需实例化学生
It just means I can call this method without instantiating a student
对象优先
object first.
这就是潜在的鸡和蛋的问题
Therein lies the potential chicken and the egg problem.
如果不熟悉 这是一种表达 意思是 很好 并做了世界
And if unfamiliar, that's an expression, meaning, well, and did the world
先有下蛋的鸡 还是有蛋？
have chickens first that laid eggs, or was there an egg
然后生下了鸡 但鸡蛋是如何到达那里的呢？
that then yielded the chickens, but how did the egg get there?
这是一个奇怪的循环问题
It's this weird, circular problem.
这就是我们现在面临的问题
And that's what we're facing here.
如果您必须创建一个学生对象才能调用Get
It would be weird if you had to create a student object in order to call get,
为了得到另一个学生对象
in order to get another student object.
这听起来很乱
That sounds messy.
让我们通过类方法来获取一个学生
Let's just get a student via a class method
根据定义 这不需要您首先创建一个学生对象
that, by definition, does not require you to create a student object first.
就像帽子一样 在它的最终形式中 我们使用Hat类
Just like the hat, in its final form, we use the hat class
就说Hat 大写H 点排序
to just say Hat, capital H, dot sort.
我们不需要先制作一顶帽子
We didn't need to create a hat first.
我们只是使用了类本身
We just used the class itself.
那么我现在要在这里做什么？
So what am I going to do here now?
让我下到主楼去
Let me go down to main.
注意我现在可以做什么 而不是说Get_Student
And instead of saying get_student, notice what I can now do.
Student.get 其他一切都可以保持不变
Student.get, and everything else can stay the same.
我现在所做的就是把我所有的逻辑
All I've done now is I've migrated all of my logic
来自Get_Student 它是这个自己的独立函数
from get_student, which was this own standalone function,
但显然与学生有名字上的联系
but clearly related to students by name.
我真的将相同的代码移到了内部
I've moved the same code, really, to inside
在名为Get的更简单的命名函数中
of the student class in a more simply named function called get.
但如果我愿意的话 我还是可以叫它Get_Student
But I could still call it get_student if I want.
在学生班上称它为Get_Student似乎有些多余
It just seems a little redundant to call it get_student in a student class,
所以我在简化
so I'm simplifying.
我有一个名为Get的方法 但我将其称为类方法
So I have a method called get, but I'm calling it a class method
以避免鸡肉和鸡蛋的问题
to avoid that chicken and the egg problem.
我希望能够在我的世界中没有学生对象的情况下调用GET
I want to be able to call a get without having a student object in my universe
已经有了
already.
它的语法是@类方法
And the syntax for that is @classmethod.
约定是给该方法至少一个参数
The convention is to give this method at least one argument,
根据称为类的CLS的约定 它正在进行
by convention called cls for class, which is just going
作为对类本身的引用
to be a reference to the class itself.
11号线和12号线和它们以前的样子是一样的
Lines 11 and 12 are identical to what they've always been.
和Get_Student--这里唯一的新语法是
And get_student-- the only new syntax here is this,
但这也是面向对象编程的特性之一
but this, again, is one of the features of object-oriented programming.
现在 只需使用传入的CLS即可实例化学生对象
You can now instantiate a student object by just using cls that's passed in.
从技术上讲 我可以利用学生 资本S
I technically could use Student, capital S,
但事实证明 我在做更传统的事情 因为
but it turns out I'm doing what's more conventional because this
将通过更复杂的代码来解决和避免问题
will both solve and avoid problems down the line with more complicated code.
这一行 在第13行 只是表示创建当前类的对象
This line here, on line 13, just means create an object of the current class.
那是什么班？
What class is that?
好吧 不管CLS是什么
Well, whatever cls is.
嗯 根据它的运作方式的定义 那将是学生
Well, that, by definition of how it all works, is going to be student.
我希望你像往常一样 用名字和房子来初始化它
And I want you to initialize it, as always, with name and house.
现在 向下滚动 我的代码是这样的
So now, scrolling down, my code is this.
这本书读起来很不错
And this is just nice to read.
你可能得先尝一尝--我这句话听起来有点奇怪
You perhaps have to acquire a taste for this-- and I sound a little odd saying,
这本书读起来很不错
this is nice to read.
但事实上 学生 GET只是告诉我发生了什么
But indeed, student.get just tells me what's going on.
我要去找一个学生
I'm going to get a student.
我不需要在文件中使用由我编写的名为Get_Student的单独函数
I don't need a separate function written by me called get_student in the file
它本身
itself.
Get功能内置于类中
The get functionality is built into the class.
我所有与学生相关的代码现在都在一起了
All my student-related code now is together.
因此 让我转到我的终端窗口 运行Student.py的Python 回车
So let me go down to my terminal window and run Python of student.py, Enter.
让我们输入哈里
Let's type in Harry.
让我们输入格兰芬多
Let's type in Gryffindor.
我们又回到了开始的地方
And we're back to where we began.
但是 但是 但是所有与学生有关的东西 现在都在这个班级里
But, but, but everything related to students, now, is in this here class.
文件中唯一的其他内容是main 这是一个有条件的内容
The only other thing in the file is main and this conditional
我们经常使用它来避免在制作
that we always use to avoid accidentally executing main when we're making
模块或包或类似物
a module or a package or the like.
所以 同样 一个问题的解决方案--
So again, a solution to a problem--
对于相对较小的程序来说 不是很大的一个 而是一个
not a big one in the case of a relatively small program, but one
你最终会在你的程序中遇到
that you will eventually encounter as your programs
变得越来越长 需要代表的实体越来越多
get longer and longer, with more and more entities to represent.
现在关于类方法的使用的问题
Questions now on this use of a class method.
迈克尔：类必须在主函数之前定义吗
MICHAEL: Does the class have to be defined before the main function,
就节目的顺序而言？
in terms of the order of the program?
大卫·J·马兰：这是一个非常好的问题
DAVID J. MALAN: A really good question.
所以 如果有疑问 让我们试试这个
So when in doubt, let's try this.
所以让我们试着改变一下顺序
So let's try to change the order.
让我们把主线移到顶端 这是我经常鼓励的
Let's move main to the top, which I've often encouraged.
因此 让我们继续 在全班之上 做这件事
So let's go ahead and, above the class, do this.
请注意 从技术上讲 第二行
And notice now that, technically, line two
提到了学生 直到第6行及以下才存在
is mentioning student, which does not exist until line 6 and below.
让我继续清除我的终端并运行Student.py的Python
Let me go ahead and clear my terminal and run Python of student.py.
到现在为止还好
So far, so good.
哈利--格兰芬多 好的
Harry-- Gryffindor, OK.
事实上 哈里来自格兰芬多
Indeed, Harry's from Gryffindor.
原因 迈克尔 在这种情况下这无关紧要
The reason, Michael, it does not matter in this case
是因为我们实际上直到最后才调用Main
is because we're not actually calling main until the very end.
就像过去一样 这意味着Python有机会读取所有内容
And just as in the past, that means that Python has a chance to read everything,
从上到下 从左到右
top to bottom, left to right.
所以一切都是存在的
So everything exists.
我想说的是 类通常在文件的顶部定义
I would say, generally classes are defined at the top of the file.
然而 移动类定义甚至可能更干净
However, it would be even maybe cleaner to move the Classes definition
到它自己的文件 然后将其导入 所以本质上
to its own file and then import it, so essentially
通过将代码放入您自己的模块或包来生成可重用的代码
to make reusable code by putting it into your own module or package
因此 不仅是这个项目 还有许多其他项目
so that not just this program but many others
也可以使用学生的定义
can use that definition of student as well.
现在关于类、类方法或类似的其他问题
Other questions now on classes, class methods, or the like.
听众：我想问 有没有办法宣布所有可能的--
AUDIENCE: I wanted to ask, is there a way to declare all the possible--
类的所有可能属性？
all the possible attributes of the class?
因为它看起来太不一致了
Because it looks so inconsistent.
大卫·J·马兰：好吧 我要说的是
DAVID J. MALAN: Well, so my takeaway there
这就是Python对这些原则的处理方法
is this is Python's approach to these principles.
不同的语言 如Java 只是采取了不同的方法
Different languages, like Java, just take a different approach
但都有非常相似的特征
but have very similar features.
语法只是有变化的趋势
The syntax just tends to vary.
这就是Python社区选择实现这一想法的方式
And this is how the Python community chose to implement this idea.
归根结底 正确的心理模型是这些实例变量
The right mental model, ultimately, is that these instance variables,
即时方法属于特定对象或对其进行操作--
instant methods belong to or operate on specific objects--
一个特定的学生 一个特定的帽子
a specific student, a specific hat.
类变量和类方法对整个类进行操作
Class variables and class methods operate on the entire class
本身或该类的所有对象 这些对象
itself or, in turn, all objects of that class, which
我们还没有看到演示 但这是一个更高层次的概念
we've not seen a demonstration of, but it's a higher level concept.
所以事实证明 除了这些类方法之外
So it turns out, besides these class methods,
它们与那些实例方法不同 公平地说
which are distinct from those instance methods, which, to be fair,
没有自己的修饰符--默认情况下 它们只是实例方法
do not have their own decorator-- they just are, by default, instance method,
在Python中的类中还可以使用其他类型的方法
there's yet other types of Methods You can have in classes in Python.
它们往往被称为静态方法 它们也是如此
They tend to be called static methods, and they, too,
附带另一个称为@Static方法的装饰器 它
come with another decorator called @static method, which
是一个我们不会掉下去的兔子洞
is a rabbit hole we won't go down.
但要意识到还有其他功能
But realize that there is yet other functionality
您可以在面向对象编程中利用它
that you can leverage within object-oriented programming.
但我们认为我们应该真正专注于一些最终的核心功能
But what we thought we'd do is focus really on some final core features
这不仅在Python中可以看到 在其他语言中也是如此
that you see not just in Python but other languages as well.
而且可能是面向对象编程最引人注目的特性之一
And perhaps one of the most compelling features of object-oriented programming
我们还没有明确使用--尽管事实证明我们已经看到
that we haven't yet used explicitly-- though it turns out we've seen
在过去的几周里--
implicitly over the past weeks--
就是这种继承的概念
is this notion of inheritance.
事实证明 通过面向对象编程
It turns out, via object-oriented programming,
实际上有一个机会来设计你的课程
there's actually an opportunity to design your classes
在分层方式中 可以从一个类继承
in a hierarchical fashion, whereby you can have one class inherit from
或借用属性--即 来自另一个类的方法或变量
or borrow attributes-- that is, methods or variables from another class
如果他们都有这些共同点的话
if they all have those in common.
那么 我在这里所说的是什么意思？
So what do I mean by this here?
好吧 让我建议我们在这里的VS代码中实现
Well, let me propose that we implement, over in VS Code here,
一个名为wizard.py的全新文件
a brand new file called wizard.py.
让我继续运行wizard.py的代码
Let me go ahead and run code of wizard.py.
然后让我们像以前一样开始 定义一个名为Student的类
And then let's start as before, defining a class called student.
让我们继续 首先定义下划线 init方法
And let's go ahead and first define the underscore underscore, init method,
当然 在传统上 最低限度地要接受一个论点
which of course, is minimally going to take an argument traditionally
叫赛尔夫
called self.
在这种情况下 让我们也让它像以前一样接受一个名字和一个房子
And in this case, let's also have it take as before a name and a house.
然后在这个初始化方法中 让我们继续
And then in this init method, let's go ahead
并分配实例变量--self.name=name
and assign the instance variables-- self.name = name,
和自己 房子=房子
and self.house = house.
让我们假设有一些其他功能
Let's assume that there's some other functionality
在这节课上也是一样--点 点 点
in this class as well-- dot, dot, dot.
但现在让我们来实施教授的概念
But let's move on now to implementing the notion of a professor
在魔法界也是如此
in the wizarding world as well.
所以对于这节课 我们就叫它教授吧
So for this class, let's call it Professor.
比如说 一位教授也要去
And a professor, let's say, is also going
要有自己的初始化方法
to have its own initialization method.
所以__init
So __ init.
这需要自我--
It's going to take self--
总是作为第一个论点
always as the first argument.
教授也有名字
A professor also has a name.
所以我们也会以第二名的成绩通过
So we'll pass that in second, too.
尽管有些教授是房子的头儿
And even though some professors are heads of houses,
让我们假设一位教授确实被确认为
let's assume that a professor is really identified
通过他们的名字和他们的学科领域--他们教的班级
by their name and their subject area-- the class that they teach.
所以我们把这第三个论点称为主题
So we'll call this third argument, subject.
现在 像以前一样 让我们继续将self.name=name
Now, as before, let's go ahead and assign self.name = name,
让我们在这里指定self.Subject=SUBJECT
and let's assign self.subject = subject here.
和前面一样 让我们假设有一些更多的相关功能
And as before, let's assume that there's some more functionality associated
教授们也是如此
with professors as well.
那么 在我对学生的定义中 你注意到了什么吗？
Well, what do you notice already here in my definitions of students
教授们呢？
and professors?
通常 我们不太愿意在代码中考虑任何冗余
Typically, we're a bit reluctant to allow for any redundancy in our code.
在这里 我感觉我的初始化方法是为学生取了一个名字；
And here, I feel like my init method is taking a name for students;
我的初始化方法也是取一个教授的名字；
my init method is also taking a name for a professor;
我有这些相同的代码行 比如self.name=name
and I have these identical lines of code, like self.name = name.
如果我现在去补充说 这只会加剧
And this is only going to get exacerbated if I now go and add
一些错误检查
some error checking.
举个例子 如果不是名字 我们
So for instance, how about if not name, we
应该养成养成养东西的习惯
should probably be in the habit of raising something
比如说明性消息中的值错误 比如“缺少名称”
like a value error in an explanatory message, like "Missing name."
你知道吗？
And you know what?
如果一位教授遗漏了他们的名字 我可能应该
If a professor is missing their name, I should probably
把代码复制粘贴到这里
copy, paste that code down here.
这就是危险信号应该发出的地方
And that's where red flags should be going off,
因此 一旦您开始复制粘贴代码
whereby, as soon as you start copy pasting code,
可能有一种更好的方法 这样我们可以只写一次代码 也许
there's probably a better way so that we can write the code once and perhaps
以某种方式重复使用它
reuse it in some way.
在这里 面向对象编程也提供了一种解决方案
And here, too, object-oriented programming offers a solution.
事实证明 Python语言中的面向对象编程
It turns out that object-oriented programming in Python
还支持继承 从而可以定义多个类
also supports inheritance, whereby you can define multiple classes that
以某种方式相互联系
somehow relate to one another.
它们不需要以这种方式并行存在
They don't need to exist in parallel in this way.
实际上 它们之间可能存在某种等级关系
There could actually be some hierarchy between them.
举个例子 在魔法世界里 我们
So for instance, in the wizarding world, we
可以争辩说 学生和教授最终都是
could argue that both a student and a professor are, at the end of the day,
奇才队
Wizards.
所以也许我们真正应该定义的是第三类
So maybe what we should really define is a third class,
例如 名为向导 它有任何
for instance, called wizard, that has any
学生和教授的共同属性
of the common attributes for students and professors alike.
就目前而言 我们保持了相对简单的做法
And for now, we've kept it relatively simple.
它们唯一的共同点就是名字和名字
The only thing they have in common is a name and a name,
分别在学生和教授身上
in student and professor, respectively.
那么 为什么我们不先把这一点考虑到最低限度呢？
So why don't we minimally factor that out first?
好了 让我继续讲下去
All right, so let me go ahead here.
为了让事情井然有序 在我的文件顶部 让我们
And just to keep things organized, at the top of my file, let's
定义名为向导的第三个类
define a third class called Wizard.
并且向导将有其自己的初始化方法
And a wizard will have its own initialization method.
所以 一如既往地定义__init_(Self)
So def __init__(self), as always.
而一个巫师 比方说 现在只会去
And a wizard, let's say for now, is only going
以这种方式使用它们的名称进行初始化
to be initialized with their name in this way.
现在 我将继续进行一些错误检查
And now, I'm going to go ahead and do some of that error checking.
因此 如果不是这样 名称将在向导类中引发一个值错误
So if not name will raise a value error in the wizard class.
否则 我们将继续做自己的名字等于名字
Otherwise, we'll go ahead and do self name equals name,
还有 见鬼 点 也许还有其他一些功能
and, heck, dot, dot, dot, maybe some other functionality as well.
但不是一个特定于教授的主题 而不是一个房子
But not a subject, which is specific to professors, and not a house,
我声称这是专门针对学生的
which I've claimed is specific to students.
现在 我想我们可以开始移除
Now, I think we can begin to maybe remove
我们这里其他班级的一些裁员
some of the redundancies in our other classes here.
举个例子 跟学生打交道 我为什么不
So for instance, down with student, why don't I
继续删除此处的错误检查并删除此错误--
go ahead and remove this error checking here and remove this error--
这个self.name=name的赋值 因为我已经
this assignment of self.name = name because I'm already
在向导中执行此操作
doing that in Wizard.
同样 在这里 教授 为什么我不做同样的事情呢？
And similarly, down here, in Professor, why don't I do the same?
让我们去掉错误检查
Let's get rid of the error checking.
让我们去掉self.name=name 因为我已经在这样做了
Let's get rid of self.name = name because, again, I'm doing that already
巫师也在那里
up there for Wizard as well.
但现在 即使它们都在同一个文件里
But at the moment, even though they're all in the same file,
我没有告诉Python学生是巫师 教授是巫师
I haven't told Python that a student is a wizard and a professor is a wizard.
所以我真的需要把这两者联系起来
So I really need to link these two together.
你可以规定继承的方式 一个类应该
And the way you can prescribe inheritance, whereby one class should
从另一个类继承 或者相反 从一个类继承
inherit from another, or conversely, one class
应该是从另一个进化而来的--我们可以做到
should descend from another-- we can do this.
我可以说是同学
I can say class Student.
但是在冒号之前 我可以在括号里说
But before the colon, I can go in and say in parentheses,
学生继承自向导 或者是向导的子类 相反
a student inherits from, or is a subclass of wizard, which, conversely,
是student类的超类
is the superclass of the student class.
这意味着 当我定义一个学生类时
So this just means that, when I define a student class,
继续前进 并继承所有的特点 一个向导以及
go ahead and inherit all of the characteristics of a wizard as well.
我也会为教授做同样的事
And I'm going to do the same thing for Professor.
所以（巫师）在班级名称教授之后
So (Wizard) after the class name Professor,
这将使我能够访问一些相同的功能
and that's going to give me access to some of that same functionality.
但是因为我的学生班和教授班
But because my student class and my professor class
仍然有相同的init方法
still have their same init methods, those
是将要被调用的方法
are the methods that are going to get called.
每当我用代码创造一个学生或者一个教授
Whenever I create a student in code or I create a professor in code,
我需要明确地说我也
I need to somehow explicitly say that I also
要使用Wizard类的init方法中的功能
want to use the functionality in the Wizard class's init method.
在Python中这样做的方法如下
And the way to do this in Python is as follows.
让我们来看看Student的init方法
Let me go into my init method for Student,
让我给super打个电话 没有参数
and let me call super, with no arguments, which
是对该类的超类的引用
is a reference to the superclass of this class.
如果这个类是Student 那么超类
So if this class is Student, the superclass-- that is,
父类是Wizard
the parent class-- is Wizard.
所以super（）将具有访问超类的效果
So super() will have the effect of accessing the superclass.
然后我将继续并显式调用它的init方法
And then I'm going to go ahead and explicitly call its init method,
我将把它传递给向导的init方法
and I'm going to pass to the Wizard's init method
传递给学生的init方法的名称
the name that the student's init method was passed.
我将继续在Wizard中做同样的事情
And I'm going to go ahead and do the same down here in Wizard.
这是一行复制 粘贴
This is one line of copy, paste.
但我觉得我在这里挺好的因为
But I think I'm OK with it here because it's still
允许我完成所有的名字分配
allowing me to do all of the name assignment
并改为在向导类中进行错误检查
and the error checking up in the Wizard class instead.
我想我们现在只要为两个学生调用Super.init就可以了
I think we're OK now by just calling super.init for both student
和教授一样
and Professor alike.
现在 无可否认 这种语法确实存在--事实是
Now, admittedly, this syntax is definitely out there-- the fact
我们在圆括号和圆点中称其为Super.
that we're calling super in parentheses and dots
并在init的左侧和右侧加下划线
and underscore underscore on the left and the right of init here,
但这只是这两个想法的结合
but it's just a combination of these two ideas.
Super()是以编程方式访问当前类的父类的一种方式
super() is a way of programmatically accessing a current class's parent
类 或超类 当然 __init只是指 现在
class, or superclass, and __init, of course, is just referring to, now,
该类自己的初始化方法
that class's own initialization method.
现在 根据点 点 点--所以可能有
Now, per the dot, dot, dot-- so there could be
在这些课程中有更多的内容
a lot more going on in these classes.
但现在最好的是巫师作为一个班级
But what's nice now is that Wizard as a class
负责所有巫师名字的分配
is taking care of all of the assignment of a wizard's name,
不管那个巫师是学生还是教授
whether that wizard is a student or a professor.
它甚至还进行了一些错误检查 以使
And it's even doing some error checking to make
当然 这个名字确实是传进来的
sure the name was actually passed in.
同时 学生继承了所有这些功能
Meanwhile, student is inheriting all of that functionality
并通过调用超类自己的init方法来使用它
and using it by calling the superclass's own init method.
但它还额外征用了房子 这可能是
But it's additionally taking the house, that's presumably
传递到学生构造函数中
passed into the student constructor function,
并将其赋给自己的实例变量--self.house
and assigning it to its own instance variable-- self.house,
同样 教授 或自我恢复的学科
and similarly, professor, or restoring in self.subject
这个主题也被传递到了那个主题中
the subject that was passed into that one as well.
现在 我们该如何使用这些类呢？
Now, how might we use these classes?
好的 我们将继续挥舞我们的手 在这里介绍一些细节
Well, we'll continue to wave our hands with a little bit of detail here.
但在此文件的底部 或导入此文件的任何其他文件中
But at the bottom of this file, or any other file that imports this one,
我现在可以像这样编写代码了
I could now write code like this.
我可以创建一个学生变量并将
I could create a student variable and assign
它是学生构造函数调用的返回值
it the return value of the student constructor call.
也许那个学生叫哈里和那个学生的房子
and maybe that student is named Harry and that student's house,
例如 可能是格兰芬多
for instance, might be Gryffindor.
同时 我可能会做这样的事情 教授=这里的教授
And meanwhile, I might do something like this. professor = Professor over here.
注意 小写的S在左边 大写的S在右边
And notice, the lowercase S on the left, capital S on the right.
左边的教授也一样--右边是小写和大写
Same for professor on the left-- lowercase and uppercase on the right
分别进行了分析
respectively.
教授 引用 引用 “西弗勒斯” 以及如何
Professor, quote, unquote, "Severus," and how
关于黑魔法防御的话题会是他的主题吗？
about Defense Against the Dark Arts will be his subject?
同时 如果我们愿意 更笼统地说
And meanwhile, if we want, more generically,
我只是个巫师 现在既不是学生也不是教授
just a wizard, who, at the moment is neither student nor professor
积极授课 我们甚至可以这样做
teaching classes actively, we could even do that.
我们可以用右手边的大写W表示WANDIZE=WANDIZE
We could do wizard = Wizard in capital W on the right-hand side
等号 因为它是班级的名字
of the equal sign, because it's the name of the class.
像阿不思这样的人--
And someone like Albus--
只传了阿不思的名字--
passing in only Albus's name--
不是房子 也不是主题 因为在这种情况下 他只被称为巫师
not a house, not a subject, because, in this case, he's known only as a wizard.
同时 对于这些调用中的每一个 这行代码
Meanwhile, with each of these calls, this line of code
这里将确保调用向导类的init方法
here will ensure that the init method for the wizard class is called.
这里的这行代码将确保学生的init方法
This line of code here will ensure that the init method of the student
类 然后调用超类向导的init方法
class and, in turn, the init method of the superclass wizard is called.
最后 在这最后一行代码中
And then lastly, on this final line of code,
此语法是否能确保教授类的init方法
will this syntax ensure that the init method of the professor class
被调用 而后者又调用超类的init方法
is called, which, in turn, calls the init method of the superclass as well.
现在对继承这一概念有任何疑问
Any questions now on this idea of inheritance,
哪一项是许多面向对象编程语言的关键特性？
which is a key feature of a lot of object-oriented programming languages?
迈克尔：就我目前所见 很多时候 都有很多筑巢的地方
MICHAEL: From what I've seen so far, a lot of times, there's a lot of nesting.
如果你做的是超级的 会涨一分吗？
If you do super, does it go one up?
是否存在这样的情况：它也嵌套在向导上方的另一个类中
Is there any situation where it's nested in another class as well, above Wizard,
比方说？
let's say?
大卫·J·马兰：这是一个非常好的问题
DAVID J. MALAN: A really good question.
如果你有一个超级班级--所以
If you were to have a super superclass-- so
您的层次结构甚至比这两个层次结构还要高
your hierarchy is even taller than the two levels of hierarchy
我们目前拥有的 绝对是
that we currently have, absolutely.
继承的好处 顾名思义 是
What's nice about inheritance, as the name implies, is,
就像你作为一个人类可能继承了某些特征一样
just as you might have inherited certain traits as a human
从你的祖父和祖母或你的曾祖父
from your grandfather and grandmother or your great-grandfather
或曾祖母 其中一些财产
or great-grandmother, some of those properties
实际上也可以在代码的上下文中慢慢地传递给你
can actually trickle down to you in the context of code as well.
所以当你从另一个阶级下来的时候
So when you descend from another class--
也就是说 当你子类化一个超类或一个超超类时
that is, when you subclass a superclass or a super superclass,
你实际上继承了所有的功能
you actually do inherit all of the functionality,
不是从你上面一层而是从两三层
not just from one level above you but from two or three,
因此您确实也可以访问某些功能
so you can indeed access some of that functionality as well.
你甚至可以覆盖它 如果你想要其中的一些类
And you can even override it if you want some of these classes
和其他人有一点点不同
to behave a little bit differently than others.
关于继承的其他问题
Other questions on inheritance.
观众：所以它和上一个类似
AUDIENCE: So it's similar to the last one,
但你能让两个父母处于同一水平吗
but can you have two parents on the same level?
David J. Malan：一个非常好的问题
DAVID J. MALAN: A really good question.
因此 有一些方法可以实现多个父代的后代
So there are ways to implement descendants from multiple parents.
有不同的方法来做到这一点 不仅仅是在Python中 还有其他语言
And there's different ways to do this, not just in Python but other languages.
不过 我们在这里保持了简单 只使用一个继承路径
We've kept things simple here, though, by having a single inheritance path.
问得好
A good question.
再问一个关于继承的问题怎么样？
How about one more question on inheritance?
观众：我们可以在super中有多个参数 init？
AUDIENCE: Can we have multiple arguments in super.__init?
大卫·J·马兰：是的 但在这种情况下 我只在第18行传递一个名字
DAVID J. MALAN: Yes, but in this case, I'm only passing a name on line 18,
我只在第10行输入名字
and I'm only passing in name on line 10.
为什么要这样？
Why?
因为 在第2行 当我为Wizard类定义init方法时
Because, on line 2, when I define the init method for the Wizard class,
我只希望有一个论点
I only expect a single argument.
但我完全可以有其他的通用功能
But I could absolutely have other common functionality.
我可以加一个守护神
I could add in a patronus.
如果学生和教授都有赞助人
If both students and professors have patronuses
可以从他们的魔杖中发出 我可以有两个论点
that can come out of their wands, I could have two arguments instead.
我们一直在使用面向对象编程的这个特性
We've been using this feature of object-oriented programming
在很长一段时间内 以例外的形式
now for quite some time in the form of exceptions.
实际上 如果你查看Python中异常的官方文档
Indeed, if you look at the official documentation for exceptions in Python,
你会发现这甚至不是我们在课堂上看到的
you'll see that there's not even the ones we've seen in class,
比如价值错误和其他
like value error and others.
还有很多其他的 但他们都是 他们自己
There's any number of others as well, but they are all, themselves,
等级制的
hierarchical in nature.
这只是内置到Python中的可用异常的一个子集
This is just a subset of the available exceptions that come built into Python.
实际上 作为程序员 您也可以创建自己的异常
And you can actually, as a programmer, create your own exceptions as well.
但正如这张图表所显示的那样
But as this chart here captures hierarchically,
我们到目前为止看到的所有例外情况实际上都是从
all exceptions we've seen thus far actually descend from
或者已经从超类继承
or inherit from superclasses already.
因此 例如 在这个列表的底部
So for instance, at the bottom of this list
下面是ValueError 我们已经见过很多次了
here is ValueError, which we've seen quite a bit.
如果你沿着这张ASCII图表上的直线向上
And if you follow the line straight up on this ascii rendition of this chart,
您将看到ValueError有一个父类、类或超类 称为异常
you'll see that ValueError has a parent, class, or superclass, called exception.
同时 Except类有一个称为基异常的父类
And the exception class, meanwhile, has a parent class called base exception.
为什么Python的作者要这样做呢？
Why did the authors of Python do this?
事实证明 无论是值错误还是键错误
Well, it turns out that, whether you have a value error or a key error
或断言错误或任何数量的其他错误
or an assertion error or any number of others,
所有这些类型的错误都有很多共同的功能
there's a lot of functionality common to all of those types of errors
你想要的--
that you want--
您希望程序员能够使用的
that you want a programmer to be able to use.
所以 事实证明 Python的作者们决定 你知道吗？
And so it turns out that the authors of Python decided, you know what?
我们不要有十几个或更多不同的班级
Let's not have a dozen or more different classes
只是都有复制、粘贴类似的功能
that all just have copy, pasted similar functionality.
让我们创建这个层次结构 这样 即使
Let's create this hierarchy so that, even
尽管这份名单中垫底的例外情况非常准确
though the exceptions toward the bottom of this list are very precise,
他们至少继承了--
they at least inherit--
也就是说 借用上面一些非常常见的功能
that is, borrow some very common functionality up above.
因此 当您在Python中使用Try和Accept关键字时
So it turns out that, when you use the Try and the Accept keyword in Python,
一般来说 我们会尝试捕捉非常具体的例外情况
generally speaking, we've tried to catch very specific exceptions,
比如ValueError
like ValueError.
但从技术上讲 你可以抓住孩子的父母 甚至
But technically, you could capture the parents or even
给定异常的祖父母异常
the grandparent exception for a given exception,
尤其是当你不确定哪一个会被抚养长大的时候
especially if you're not necessarily sure which one is going to get raised.
或者 更好的是 可能会有许多例外被提出
Or, better yet, there could be many exceptions that get raised,
但你想对他们一视同仁
but you want to handle them all the same,
你不一定要列举它们
and you don't want to necessarily enumerate them
在括号中 用逗号隔开
in parentheses, separated by commas.
你想说你想处理某个超类的所有异常
You want to say you want to handle all exceptions of a certain superclass
以同样的方式
in much the same way.
所以这一直都是潜伏的 每当我们
So this has been latent this whole time, any time we've
看到或使用或捕获 或者现在 引发异常 并内置到Python中
seen or used or caught or, now, raised exceptions, and built into Python
就是这种等级制度
is this hierarchy.
如果你要发明自己的例外
And if you were to invent your own exception,
一般来说 你不会想从头开始
generally, you wouldn't want to start from scratch.
你会想要从--也就是说 子类
You would want to descend from-- that is, subclass, one of these existing
异常 并添加自己的扭曲 你自己的功能以及
exceptions and add your own twist on it, your own functionality as well.
面向对象编程的最后一个特点
Well, there's one final feature of object oriented programming
我们今天想和大家分享的
that we'd like to share with you today, and then it
也许会让你大开眼界 看看你现在能做什么
will perhaps be quite the eye opener as to what you can really do now
你可以随意上课
that you have classes at your disposal.
这也是一个令人惊讶的特点
And this, too, surprise, has been a feature
你我已经习以为常了
you and I have been taking for granted for weeks now.
这已经奏效了 但它的实施方式
This has just worked, but it's been implemented in a way
你现在可以利用自己
that you can now leverage yourself.
事实证明 Python和其他一些语言
It turns out that Python, and some other languages, too,
支持这种运算符重载的概念
support this notion of operator overloading, whereby
你可以使用非常常见的符号 比如加号、减号或其他类似的语法
you can take very common symbols, like plus or minus or other such syntax
在键盘上 你可以实现你自己的解释
on the keyboard, and you can implement your own interpretation thereof.
加不等于加
Plus does not have to equal addition.
减不一定等于减
And minus does not have to equal subtraction.
事实上 你和我已经看到了另一个背景
And in fact, you and I have already seen another context
其中加号代表别的意思
in which plus means something else.
在Python中 加号本身并不总是意味着加法
Plus has not always, in Python, meant addition, per se.
Python还用plus做什么？
What else has Python used plus for?
观众：串联？
AUDIENCE: Concatenation?
DAVID J. MALAN：用于连接
DAVID J. MALAN: For concatenation.
对于连接两个字符串 对于添加到列表中 您也可以使用加号
For joining two strings, for adding to a list can you use plus as well.
有趣的是 Python的作者们实际上已经重载了So plus
So plus has actually been, funny enough, overloaded by the authors of Python
为我们
for us.
所以我们可以用和加法一样的方法来使用这个符号
And so we can use the same symbol in much the same way as addition
但使用不同的数据类型来解决略有不同的问题
but with different data types to solve slightly different problems.
我建议我们回到VS Code
Well, let me propose that we go back over to VS Code here,
让我继续创建一个新的最终文件 名为vault.py
and let me go ahead and create a new final file called vault.py.
所以代码是vault.py
So code of vault.py.
让我提议我们实施一个金库的想法
And let me propose that we implement the idea of a vault
在古灵阁 保持主题 其中有
at Gringotts, keeping on theme, wherein there's
哈利·波特世界里的银行
a bank in the world of Harry Potter.
在这家银行里 家庭和个人
And within this bank, families and individuals
在魔法世界里有各种各样的钱
have vaults containing all sorts of money in the wizarding world.
在哈利·波特的世界里
And the type of money that exists in the world of Harry Potter
是被称为加隆、镰刀和克努特的硬币
are coins called galleons and sickles and Knuts,
这些是按价值递减的顺序排列的
and those are in descending order of value.
在金库里可能有一大堆硬币
And so inside of a vault might be a whole bunch of coins--
金 银 铜 基本上 每一个在这些面额
gold, silver, and bronze, essentially, each in those denominations,
藏起来了
tucked away.
那么首先 我该如何实现保险库的概念呢
So how can I go about implementing, first of all, the idea of a vault
这样我就可以储存 比如 哈利波特
so that I can store, for instance, for Harry Potter, how much coinage
是在他家的金库里 还是罗恩·韦斯莱的金库里
is in his family's vault, or for Ron Weasley the same?
好吧 让我继续 vault.py 首先
Well, let me go ahead and vault.py and first
创建一个名为Vault的类 基本上表示银行金库
create a class called Vault, essentially meant to represent a bank vault.
完美 另一个真实的世界 或者幻想的世界
Perfect, another real world, or fantasy world,
我想用代码表示的实体
entity that I want to represent with code.
我可以用一个元组或者一个列表或者一个字典
I could use a tuple or a list or a dictionary.
但是 我还是要用类来获得更多的功能
But again, I'm going to get a lot more functionality with classes,
and we'll我们会see one final最后flourish繁荣with operators运营商.
and we'll see one final flourish with operators.
在跳马课里 我们来做这个
Inside of this vault class, let's go ahead and do this.
让我定义我的init方法 使用它的第一个参数self
Let me define my init method, taking its first argument of self.
让我来定义三个论点
And let me define three arguments to this.
当你创建一个保险库时 在我的代码中
When you create a vault, in my code here,
我希望能用一些加隆来初始化它 一些数字
I want to be able to initialize it with some number of galleons, some number
镰刀和坚果
of sickles and, some number of Knuts.
我希望用户 程序员 能够传入一个或多个
I want the user, the programmer, to be able to pass in one or more
这些价值观的理想
of those values ideally.
但它们可以是可选的 所以我给它们默认值
But they can be optional, so I'll give them defaults.
让我们定义一个名为galleons的参数
So let's go ahead and define a parameter called galleons,
其缺省值为0；镰刀 其缺省值也为0；
whose default value will be 0; sickles, whose default value will also be 0;
和knts 其缺省值也将为0
and knuts, whose default value will be 0 as well.
因此程序员可以传入一个或两个或三个 甚至一个也不传入
So the programmer can pass in one or two or three or even none of those,
而且它们都会有一些隐含的违约
and they'll all have some implied defaults.
我要如何记住那些传入的值呢？
How do I want to remember those values that are passed in?
好吧 那就让我来吧
Well, let me do this.
大帆船=帆船
self.galleons = galleons.
和自我 镰刀=镰刀
And self.sickles = sickles.
和self.knerts=knits
And self.knuts = knuts.
因此 我可以添加一些错误检查 特别是如果您不通过的话
And so I could add some error checking, especially if you don't pass in.
我可以将这些转换为属性 以进行更多的验证
A number I could turn these into properties to do even more validation.
但让我们保持简单 一如既往地只关注新想法
But let's keep it simple and, as always, focus only on the new ideas.
所以我只会相信这些值是传入的
So I'm just going to trust that these values were passed in,
我会立即把它们赋给这些实例变量
and I'm going to immediately assign them to these instance variables.
现在 我想要做什么？
What, now, do I want to do?
好吧 让我们想出一种打印输出的方法
Well, let's come up with a way of printing out
最终 某人的金库里有什么
what is in someone's vault, ultimately.
但首先让我们这样做
But first let's do this.
让我们通过分配创建一个新的保险库 从而为波特一家创建一个保险库
Let's create a vault for the Potters by creating, via assignment, a new vault.
假设陶工有100只大帆船 50把镰刀和24克朗
And let's say that the potters have 100 galleons, 50 sickles, and 24 knuts.
它就在那个保险库里 让我们打印出来 比方说 波特
And that's in that vault. And let's print out, for instance, potter.
好的 让我们运行这段代码 看看它现在是如何工作的
All right, let's run this code and see how it works now.
让我继续运行Vault.py的Python.Enter
Let me go ahead and run Python of vault.py, Enter.
看起来很管用
Seems to work.
没有语法错误或其他任何错误
No syntax errors or anything else.
但这并不是很有启发性
But this is not very enlightening.
回想我们以前做过的事情 我该如何解决这个问题呢？
How do I fix this, thinking back to what we've done before?
观众：您必须使用__str
AUDIENCE: You have to use the __str.
大卫·J·马兰：没错
DAVID J. MALAN: Exactly.
我需要使用类附带的一种特殊方法
I need to use one of those special methods that comes with classes
并自己定义我希望将保险库打印为字符串的方式
and define for myself how I want a vault to be printed as a string.
因此 让我继续下去 这样做
So let me go ahead and do that.
让我定义将self作为其唯一参数的str方法
Let me define the str method taking in self as its sole argument here.
让我们只返回一个非常简单的字符串
And let's just return a very simple string
这正好揭示了保险库里有什么
that just reveals what's in the vault.
所以我将返回一个格式化的f字符串
So I'm going to return a formatted f string,
里面是帆船 然后是帆船这个词
inside of which is self.galleons and then the word galleon,
所以我知道那些是什么了
so I know which those are.
然后让我们自己做 镰刀 让我们输出单词 镰刀
Then let's do self.sickles, and let's output the word, sickles.
最后 让我们输出self.knuts 然后在这里输出knuts
And then lastly let's output self.knuts, and then knuts here.
所以我知道 在这根绳子上 每一枚硬币有多少
So I know, in this string, just how many of each of those coins
我在这个特殊家庭的金库里 好的 让我继续
I have in this particular family's vault. All right, let me go ahead
并运行Vault.py的Python 除了str方法外 不更改其他任何内容
and run Python of vault.py, changing nothing else except the str method.
现在 我们确实看到哈利有100艘大帆船 50把镰刀和25枚坚果
And now, , we, see indeed that Harry has 100 galleons, 50 sickles, and 25 knuts.
好吧 好吧 我们再做一件事
All right, well, let's do one thing more here.
下面 让我们继续定义一个Weasley变量
Below that, let's go ahead and define a Weasley variable.
罗恩的金库里似乎从来没有哈利那么多钱
And Ron never seemed to have quite as much money in the vault as did Harry.
因此 假设韦斯莱跳马将有25、50和100个
So let's say that the Weasley vault will have 25, 50, and 100.
所以我就把这些面额的顺序颠倒一下
So I'll just reverse the order of those denominations,
而不是哈利的100 50 25
rather than Harry's 100, 50, 25.
现在让我继续把韦斯莱印成这样
And now let me go ahead and print Weasley like this.
让我们继续清除我的终端窗口 运行Vault.py的Python
And let's go ahead and clear my terminal window, run Python of vault.py.
这次 字符串方法将被调用两次 一次
This time, that str method will be invoked twice, once
这些保险库对象中的每一个
for each of those vault objects.
我们会看到 确实 哈利的第一个
And we'll see, indeed, that the first one for Harry
分别得到了100 50和25 而罗恩只有25 50
has got 100, 50, and 25, respectively, versus Ron's 25, 50,
和100
and 100, respectively.
但现在让我们做一些有趣的事情
But now let's do something interesting.
假设您想要合并两个存储库的内容
Suppose that you wanted to combine the contents of two vaults,
不管是哈里和罗恩还是其他两个人
be it Harry's and Ron's or any other two people.
您将如何在代码中进行这项工作？
How would you go about doing this in code?
如果我想为某人组合保险库 我可以这么做
Well, if I wanted to combine the vaults for someone, I could do this.
嗯 我可以做同样的大帆船--
Well, I could do galleons equals--
让我们来做陶器 大帆船+小帆船
let's do potter.galleons + weasley.galleons.
这给了我一个名为Galleons的变量 它具有
That gives me a variable called galleons that has
哈利和罗恩的大帆船的总和
the sum of Harry and Ron's galleons.
接下来让我们做镰刀=陶器 镰刀+韦斯莱镰刀
Let's next do sickles = potter.sickles + weasley.sickles.
最后 让我们来做knts=potter.knts+weasley.kutts
And then lastly, let's do knuts = potter.knuts + weasley.knuts.
我有三个变量
I've got three variables.
我现在能用这些值做什么呢？
What can I now do with these values?
那我们就建第三个新金库总数将
Well, let's create a third-- a new vault. Total will
这个变量的名字等于一个新的保险库 大写V 注意
be the name of this variable equals a new vault, Capital V, notice.
现在 让我们传入这三个新变量--
And now, let's pass in those three new variables--
大帆船 镰刀 和坚果
galleons, sickles, and knuts.
就这样 让我们打印出整个保险库
And that's it, and let's print out this total vault.
所以我们现在应该看到三个拱顶--一个是哈利的 一个是罗恩的
So we should now see three vaults-- one for Harry, for Ron,
以及两者的结合
and the combination-- the addition of the two.
让我继续搜索vault.py的Python 然后我们就得到了它
Let me go ahead and rerun Python of vault.py, and there we have it.
100 50 25和25 50和100 现在通过加法合并
What was 100, 50, 25 and 25, 50, and 100, combined through addition now,
是125 100 125
is 125, 100, 125.
所以很简单 使用几周前的技术
So pretty straightforward, using techniques from weeks
之前 我们只是声明了一些新的变量并做了一些加法
ago, where we're just declaring a few new variables and doing some addition.
但如果我能做这样的事不是很酷吗？
But wouldn't it be cool if I could do something like this?
如果我能以某种方式
Wouldn't it be cool if I could just somehow,
而不是手动创建我自己的保险库 在这里做所有这些烦人的数学运算--
not manually create my own vault and do all of this annoying math up here--
如果我能做波特和韦斯莱 摆脱这里所有的逻辑呢？
what if I could just do potter + weasley and get rid of all of this logic here?
如果我让操作员超载不是很好吗
Wouldn't it be nice if I overload the operator--
我们知道加号 就像str一样
we know as plus, just like str does, just
就像list一样--允许我把两个保险库加在一起
like list does-- to allow me to add two vaults together
在左边和右边
on the left and the right.
在Python中 通过运算符重载
Well, it turns out in Python and through operator overloading,
有一种方法可以做到这一点
there is a way to do just this.
如果你查阅文档
If you consult the documentation, there's
这个方法和其他许多随类而来的特殊方法
this and so many other special methods that come with classes.
第三个是这个
The third one we'll see here is this one here--
__add__.
你会发现它被描述得很一般
And you'll see that it very generically is described
适用于任何对象 无论是Vault还是String
in the documentation is working for any object, be it a vault or str
或者是一份名单或者别的什么
or a list or something else.
按照惯例 第一个参数是self
By convention, it's going to take a first argument called self,
然后它会用到另一个参数 按照惯例 叫做other
and then it's going to take some other argument, by convention, called other.
self实际上指的是
self, in effect, is going to be referring to whatever
对象位于加号的左侧
object is on the left of a plus sign.
另一个是指
other is going to be referring to whatever
在加号的右边
is on the right-hand side of a plus sign,
从而给了我们一种用代码描述操作数的方法
thereby giving us a way of describing, in code, the operand
操作数在运算符的左边 操作数在运算符的右边 加上 介于两者之间
on the left and the operand on the right of the operator, plus, in between.
也就是说 如果我回到VS Code
That is to say, if I go back to VS Code here,
我想做的是为这个项目提供支持
what I'm trying to do is implement support for this.
好吧 让我试试 暂时不写其他代码--
Well, let me try, without writing any other code just yet--
vault.py的Python 输入--
Python of vault.py, Enter--
TypeError：+：'Vault'和'vault'不支持的操作数类型 '
TypeError: unsupported operand type(s) for +: 'Vault' and 'vault.'
也就是说 Python此时不知道
That is to say Python, at this moment, does not know what
就是把两个拱顶加在一起
it means to add two vaults together.
你和我可能有一种直觉
You and I might have an instinct.
可能想把加隆镰刀和坚果结合起来
Probably want to combine the galleons and the sickles and the knuts
分别
respectively.
Python不知道这一点
Python doesn't know that.
它只知道你有一个名为Vault的新类
It just knows that you have a new class called Vault.
让我们来教Python如何做到这一点
But let's teach Python to do this.
我来清空终端窗口
Let me clear my terminal window.
让我回到这个类本身 在那里 目前
Let me scroll back up to the class itself, where, at the moment,
我只有两个特殊的方法-- init和str
I only have two special methods-- init and str.
但让我们加上第三个
But let's add this third.
让我在这里进入类并定义__add__ 然后指定它的第一个
Let me go into the class here and define __add__ and then specify its first
参数作为self 然后为这个特定的
parameter as self, as before, and then a second parameter for this particular
方法调用 按照约定 其他
method called, by convention, other.
现在 像往常一样 我可以给这些参数取任何名字
Now, as always, I could name those parameters anything
我也想 但我还是按惯例来吧
I want, but I'm going to stick with convention here.
现在 在这个方法中 我是不是
And now, inside of this method, am I going
把两个保险库里的东西加在一起
to have to now add together the contents of two vaults?
哪两个金库？
Well, what two vaults?
好吧 如果我们向下滚动到我们手头的目标 当然
Well, if we scroll down to our goal at hand, the goal, of course,
就是加上这个保险库和另一个保险库 波特
is to add this vault plus this other vault-- potter
还有韦斯莱
plus weasley, respectively.
在Python中 当你重载一个运算符
Well, it turns out, in Python, that, when you do overload an operator like
另外 自动发生的事情
plus, what's going to happen automatically,
一旦Python看到这个 它会调用__add__方法
as soon as Python sees that, is it's going to call that __add__ method,
它会传递到论证中
and it's going to pass into it to arguments--
不管左边的操作数是什么--在这个例子中是potter--
whatever the operand is on the left-- potter, in this case--
以及右边的操作数--这里是韦斯莱
and whatever the operand is on the right-- weasley, in this case.
而这些价值将分别作为自我和他人传递进来
And those values are going to get passed in as self and other, respectively.
这意味着我们可以在这里访问他们的内容
What that means is that we can access their contents up here
在我们的Add实现中 如下所示
in our implementation of add as follows.
让我们继续定义一个名为Galleon的局部变量 并将
Let me go ahead and define a local variable called galleons and set that
例如 等于自身大帆船的和--
equal to, for instance, the sum of self.galleons--
不管本案中波特的保险库里有什么
whatever's in Potter's vault in this case,
再加上本案中韦斯利金库里的任何东西
plus whatever is in Wesley's vault in this case, which
会是另一艘大帆船
would be other.galleons.
让我对镰刀做同样的事情
Let me do the same for sickles.
自我 镰刀+其他 镰刀
self.sickles + other.sickles.
最后 让我为克努茨做这件事
And let me lastly do that for knuts.
所以自己人+其他人
So self.knuts + other.knuts.
但归根结底 我需要
But at the end of the day, I'm going to need
返回一个全新的更大的保险库 其中包含所有这些内容
to return a brand new bigger vault that contains all of those contents
在一起
together.
如果我们最终想要将更大的保险库赋给一个像Total这样的变量
And if we ultimately want to assign that bigger vault to a variable like total
在这里 在左边 我们最好从这个Add方法返回一个值
here, on the left, we'd better return a value from this add method.
所以我要继续前进 给自己一个全新的跳马 就像回到
So I'm going to go ahead and give myself a brand new vault, as by returning
Capital Vault 当然 它将调用我的存储库函数
capital Vault, which of course, is going to call my vault function into which
我现在可以传递其中一些初始化参数
I can now pass some of those initialization arguments.
那么 有多少大帆船、镰刀和坚果
Well, how many galleon, sickles, and knuts do
我想让这个全新的保险库容纳？
I want this brand new vault to contain?
我希望它能装这么多大帆船这么多把镰刀
Well, I want it to contain this many galleons this many sickles,
还有这么多坚果
and this many knuts.
所以最终 我们在这个实现中所做的
So ultimately, what we're doing in this implementation
加法是把那些大帆船、镰刀和坚果加在一起 通过
of add is adding together those galleons, sickles, and knuts, passing
这样我们就能得到一个全新的更大的保险库
them to the vault function so that we get a brand new bigger vault,
并将其全部归还
and return that altogether.
所以现在我定义了这个新的特殊方法
So now I've defined this new special method
名为Add的应用程序现在应该只对两个保险库执行plus操作
called add that should now just make plus work for two vaults.
让我们看看
Let's see.
让我运行到我的终端窗口 即Vault.py的Python 然后按Enter键
Let me run down to my terminal window, Python of vault.py and hit Enter.
好了 现在我们实现了一个重载运算符
And voila, and now we've implemented an overloaded operator, plus,
去做你我作为人类所希望的事情
to do what you and I as humans would hope
将两个存储库添加到一起时会出现这种情况
would be the case when you add two vaults together.
但我现在已经更具体地编写了代码
But I've now written the code more specifically
教Python把两个保险库加在一起的具体含义
to teach Python what it means concretely to add two vaults together.
它的代码非常相似
And it's with very similar code in effect,
Python在后台对两个字符串做这样的操作
underneath the hood, that Python is doing this for two strings,
将它们连接在一起 将两个列表连接成一个新的列表
to concatenate them together, to joining two lists into a new list with list,
还有很多其他的课程
and so many other classes as well.
关于运算符重载或者这个例子还有什么问题吗？
Any questions now on operator overloading or this example here.
观众：你会如何创作
AUDIENCE: How would you go about creating
为两个单独的班级添加学生和Vault的功能？
a function for adding a student and a vault for two separate classes?
有可能吗？
Would that be possible?
大卫·J·马兰：让我看看这里发生了什么
DAVID J. MALAN: Let me see what happens here.
我也不知道
I don't know offhand.
开始吧
Let's do this.
让我们创建一个str 看看会发生什么
Let's create a str and see what happens.
如果我加上波特再加一个
If I add Potter plus a str--
String对象
str object.
是啊 所以它会工作
Yeah, so it would work.
我只是在想办法 埃里克
I'm just figuring this out as I go here, Eric.
所以说清楚 我只是
So just to be clear, what I did was I just
把韦斯莱改成了str 只是想看看
changed weasley to str just to see what would
当我加上一个拱顶和一个str的时候 理论上是可行的
happen when I add a vault plus a str, and it will work, theoretically.
为什么要这样？
Why?
因为只要左边的值类型实现了add方法
Because so long as the type of value on the left has an add method implemented,
其他可以是任何你想要的类型
other can be any type that you want.
你只需要决定并编码它是什么
You just have to decide and code what it's
从概念上讲 这意味着增加一个保险库和一个字符串
going to mean conceptually to add a vault plus a string, which,
在这种情况下 可能没有任何意义 但这是可能的
in this case, probably doesn't make any sense at all, but it's possible.
它将是左边的操作数
It's going to be the operand on the left.
我在推断
And I'm inferring that.
我刚才不知道答案
I did not know the answer a moment ago.
我这样推断是因为我得到的是第11行的属性错误
I'm inferring that because what I got was an attribute error here on line 11
因为巨蟒不喜欢这样其他的 大帆船没有工作
because Python did not like this. other.galleons didn't work,
但我可以想办法解决
but I could make it work by figuring something out.
问得好
Really good question.
我自己都不知道
Didn't know that one myself.
关于运算符重载的其他问题？
Other questions on operator overloading?
问：你能在Python中定义新的操作符吗？
AUDIENCE: Can you define new operators in Python?
大卫·J·马兰：我不这么认为
DAVID J. MALAN: I don't think so.
有一个很长但很精确的操作符列表可以重载
There is a very long but precise list of operators that you can overload.
我不相信你可以任意分配字符
I do not believe you can assign arbitrary characters
Python中的操作符
to be operators in Python.
让我在聊天中听从卡特的意见--
Let me defer to Carter in the chat to--
好的 我看到我的两个同事在说 不 不可能
OK, I'm seeing two of my colleagues are saying, no, not possible.
因此 我将按照我的第一直觉 不
So I'm going to go with my first instinct, no.
不然的话 那就太酷了
Otherwise, that'd be kind of cool.
你可以让表情符号做任何你想做的事情
You could make emoji do whatever you want to.
最后一个关于操作符重载的问题如何？
How about one final question on operator overloading?
观众：这是你唯一能做的手术吗？
AUDIENCE: Is that the only operation you can do as far as--
你也能做减法吗？
can you do a subtraction as well?
大卫·J·马兰：你可以的
DAVID J. MALAN: You can.
你可以做这么多别人让我做的事
You can do so many others let me.
如果 卡特 你不介意在这里调出这个网址--
If, Carter, you don't mind pulling up this URL here--
所以这里的链接--特殊方法名称和今天的幻灯片
so this link here-- special method names and today's slides,
您将看到可以重载的所有操作符的长长列表
you'll see a long list of all of the operators that you can overload.
你可以做小于、等于、加等于、减等于
You can do less than, equals than, plus equals, minus equals.
你看到我在屏幕上输入的几乎所有符号
Pretty much any symbol you've seen me type on the screen
可以在类的上下文中重载
can be overloaded in the context of classes.
所以 即使今天 我们完全专注于
So even though, today, we focused entirely
在面向对象编程方面 这是我们一直在使用的一种技术
on object-oriented programming, this is a technique that we've been using,
真的 从上课的第一周开始 因为那些INT
really, since the first week of the class because those ints,
那些STR 那些花车 那些列表 那些词典
those strs, those floats, those lists, those dictionaries,
而在这段时间里 引擎盖下已经有了更多的东西--课程
and so much more were already underneath the hood this whole time-- classes
以及它的宗旨
and objects thereof.
但你现在 作为一名程序员 有能力
But you now, as a programmer, have the ability
要使用自己的实例或类变量创建自己的类
to create your own classes with your own instance or class variables,
使用您自己的实例或类方法 使用您自己的属性
with your own instance or class methods, with your own properties,
甚至可以使用您自己为操作员定制的行为
and even with your own custom behavior for operators.
所以最终 你完全可以继续
So ultimately, you can absolutely continue
使用这些简单的元组或列表或那些词典或其他结构
using those simple tuples or lists or those dictionaries or other structures
也是
as well.
但面向对象编程 以及随之而来的类和现在的这些对象
But object-oriented programming, and with it, classes and now these objects
只是您工具包中的另一个工具
is just another tool in your toolkit.
大胆地说 随着您的代码变得更加复杂
And daresay, as your code gets more sophisticated
你的问题变得更大 你会发现
and your problems get bigger, you'll find
能够对这些现实世界甚至幻想世界的实体进行建模
that being able to model these real world or even fantasy world entities
使用类以及相关数据和功能
with classes and related data and functionality
最终将允许您定义不仅正确而且永远正确的代码
will ultimately just allow you to define code that's not just correct but ever
也是精心设计的
well-designed as well.
这是CS50
This was CS50.